<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A simple but tough-to-beat baseline for the Fake News Challenge stance detection task</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Riedel</surname></persName>
							<email>benjamin.riedel.09@ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isabelle</forename><surname>Augenstein</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgios</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Spithourakis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Riedel</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A simple but tough-to-beat baseline for the Fake News Challenge stance detection task</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2022-11-11T11:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Identifying public misinformation is a complicated and challenging task. An important part of checking the veracity of a specific claim is to evaluate the stance different news sources take towards the assertion. Automatic stance evaluation, i.e. stance detection, would arguably facilitate the process of fact checking. In this paper, we present our stance detection system which claimed third place in Stage 1 of the Fake News Challenge. Despite our straightforward approach, our system performs at a competitive level with the complex ensembles of the top two winning teams. We therefore propose our system as the 'simple but tough-to-beat baseline' for the Fake News Challenge stance detection task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System description</head><p>The single, end-to-end stance detection system consists of lexical and similarity features passed through a multi-layer perceptron (MLP) with one hidden layer. Although relatively simple in nature, the system performs on par with more elaborate, ensemble-based systems of other teams <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9]</ref> (see Section 4).</p><p>The code for our system and instructions on how to reproduce our submission are available at UCLMR's public GitHub repository: github.com/uclmr/fakenewschallenge.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Representations and features</head><p>We use two simple bag-of-words (BOW) representations for the text inputs: term frequency (TF) and term frequency-inverse document frequency (TF-IDF) <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10]</ref>. The representations and feature extracted from the headline and body pairs consist of only the following: arXiv:1707.03264v2 [cs.CL]  </p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Automating stance evaluation has been suggested as a valuable first step towards assisting human fact checkers to detect inaccurate claims. The Fake News Challenge initiative thus recently organised the first stage of a competition (FNC-1) to foster the development of systems for automatically evaluating what a news source is saying about a particular issue <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>.</p><p>More specifically, FNC-1 involved developing a system that, given a news article headline and a news article body, estimates the stance of the body towards the headline. The stance label to be assigned could be one of the set: 'agree', 'disagree', 'discuss', or 'unrelated' (see example of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). More information on the FNC-1 task, rules, data, and evaluation metrics can be found on the official website: fakenewschallenge.org.</p><p>The goal of this short paper is to present a description of UCL Machine Reading's (UCLMR) system employed during FNC-1, a summary of the system's performance, a brief overview of the competition, and our work going forward.</p><p>? The TF vector of the headline;</p><p>? The TF vector of the body; ? The cosine similarity between the 2 -normalised TF-IDF vectors of the headline and body.</p><p>We tokenise the headline and body texts as well as derive the relevant vectors using scikit-learn <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>.</p><p>Different vocabularies are used for calculating the TF and TF-IDF vectors. For the TF vectors, we extract a vocabulary of the 5,000 most frequent words in the training set and exclude stop words (the scikit-learn stop words for the English language with negation terms removed). For the TF-IDF vectors, a vocabulary of the 5,000 most frequent words is defined on both the training and test sets and the same set of stop words is excluded.</p><p>The TF vectors and the TF-IDF cosine similarity are concatenated in a feature vector of total size 10,001 and fed into the classifier. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Classifier</head><p>The classifier is a MLP <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> with one hidden layer of 100 units and a softmax on the output of the final linear layer. We use the rectified linear unit (ReLU) activation function <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> as non-linearity for the hidden layer. The system predicts with the highest scoring label ('agree', 'disagree', 'discuss', or 'unrelated'). The classifier as described is fully implemented in TensorFlow [1].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Training</head><p>Our training objective was to minimise the cross entropy between the system's softmax probabilities and the true labels. For regularisation of the system, we added 2 regularisation of the MLP weights to the objective and applied dropout <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> on the output of both perceptron layers during training.</p><p>We trained in mini-batches over the entire training set with back-propagation using the Adam optimiser <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> and gradient clipping by a global norm clip ratio <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. All of the aforementioned were implemented in TensorFlow <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>Training was stopped early based on a qualitative criterion with respect to the plateau of the loss on the training set and the mean performance of the system on 50 random splits of the data into training and hold-out sets as defined in the official baseline setup <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Hyperparameters</head><p>The full set of hyperparameters of the system, their labels, their descriptions, the ranges of values considered during tuning, and corresponding optimised values are provided in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. The hyperparameters were tuned during development using random search on a grid of combinations of values considered and cross-validation on various splits of the data. 3 Results</p><p>Submissions to the competition were evaluated with respect to the FNC-1 score, as defined in the official evaluation metrics <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. Our submission achieved a FNC-1 score of 81.72%.</p><p>The performance of our system is summarised by below confusion matrix for the labels of and predictions on the final test set (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>). We conclude that although our system performs satisfactorily in general, this can mainly be attributed to the close to perfect classification of the instances into 'related' and 'unrelated' headline/body pairs (accuracy: 96.55%) and the more or less default 'discuss' classification of the 'related' instances. Our system's performance with respect to the 'agree' label is average at best, whereas the system's accuracy on the 'disagree' test examples is clearly quite poor. The disappointing performance is noteworthy since these two labels are arguably the most interesting in the FNC-1 task and the most relevant to the superordinate goal of automating the stance evaluation process. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Competition</head><p>A total of 50 teams actively participated in FNC-1. The final top 10 leader board (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>) shows our submission (UCLMR) placed in third position. The official baseline achieved a FNC-1 score of 75.20% on the test data set <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> and is included in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> for reference. Official baseline 75.20</p><p>The competition was won by team 'SOLAT in the SWEN' from Talos Intelligence, a threat intelligence subsidiary of Cisco Systems, and the second place was taken by team 'Athene' consisting of members from the Ubiquitous Knowledge Processing Lab and the Adaptive Preparation of Information from Heterogeneous Sources Research Training Group at Technische Universit?t Darmstadt (TU Darmstadt). The respective FNC-1 scores of these teams were 82.02% and 81.97%.</p><p>The team from Talos Intelligence employed a 50/50 weighted average ensemble of (i) two onedimensional convolutional neural networks on respectively word embeddings of the headline and body feeding into a MLP with three hidden layers and (ii) five overarching sets of features passed into gradient boosted decision trees <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>The team from TU Darmstadt used an ensemble of five separate MLPs, each with seven hidden layers and fed with seven overarching sets of features. Predictions were based on the hard vote of the five separate, randomly initialised MLPs <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>.</p><p>The submission of our team performed almost on par with the top two teams and with considerable distance to the remaining teams as well as the official baseline. In contrast to other submissions, we achieved competitive results with a simple, single, end-to-end system.</p><p>Discussions with other teams, including those from Talos Intelligence and TU Darmstadt, revealed that the test set performance of other systems on the labels of key interest ('agree' and 'disagree') was not much better, if at all.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Future work</head><p>Our goal going forward is to carry out in-depth analyses of our system. The added benefit of our straightforward setup, as opposed to more sophisticated neural network architectures, is that it provides an opportunity to try to understand how it works, what contributes to its performance, and what its limitations are.</p><p>A particular focus of these analyses will be to try and identify what the mediocre performance of the system with respect to the 'agree' and 'disagree' labels can potentially be traced back to, next to the limited size of the data set overall and the small number of instances of the labels of specific interest.</p><p>Notwithstanding this, we would like to propose our system as the 'simple but tough-to-beat baseline' <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> for the FNC-1 stance detection task given the system's competitive performance and basic implementation. We accordingly welcome researchers and practitioners alike to employ, improve, and/or extend our work thus far.</p><p>? Florian Mai at the Christian-Albrechts Universit?t zu Kiel</p><p>? Anna Seg from the FNC-1 team 'annaseg'</p><p>? James Thorne at the University of Sheffield </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Schematic diagram of UCLMR's system.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Details on hyperparameters of UCLMR's system.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Label</cell><cell>Description</cell><cell>Range</cell><cell>Optimised</cell></row><row><cell>lim_unigram</cell><cell>BOW vocabulary size</cell><cell>1,000 -10,000</cell><cell>5,000</cell></row><row><cell>hidden_size</cell><cell>MLP hidden layer size</cell><cell>50 -600</cell><cell>100</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">train_keep_prob 1 -dropout on layer outputs 0.5 -1.0</cell><cell>0.6</cell></row><row><cell>l2_alpha</cell><cell>2 regularisation strength</cell><cell cols="2">0.1 -0.0000001 0.0001</cell></row><row><cell>learn_rate</cell><cell>Adam learning rate</cell><cell>0.1 -0.001</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>clip_ratio</cell><cell>Global norm clip ratio</cell><cell>1 -10</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>batch_size</cell><cell>Mini-batch size</cell><cell>250 -1,000</cell><cell>500</cell></row><row><cell>epochs</cell><cell>Number of epochs</cell><cell>? 1, 000</cell><cell>90</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Confusion matrix of UCLMR's FNC-1 submission.</figDesc><table><row><cell>True</cell><cell cols="7">Pred. 'agree' 'disagree' 'discuss' 'unrelated' Overall % Accuracy</cell></row><row><cell>'agree'</cell><cell></cell><cell>838</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>939</cell><cell>114</cell><cell>1,903</cell><cell>44.04</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">'disagree'</cell><cell>179</cell><cell>46</cell><cell>356</cell><cell>116</cell><cell>697</cell><cell>6.60</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">'discuss'</cell><cell>523</cell><cell>46</cell><cell>3,633</cell><cell>262</cell><cell>4,464</cell><cell>81.38</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">'unrelated'</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>330</cell><cell>17,963</cell><cell>18,349</cell><cell>97.90</cell></row><row><cell>Overall</cell><cell></cell><cell>1,593</cell><cell>107</cell><cell>5,258</cell><cell>18,455</cell><cell>25,413</cell><cell>88.46</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Top 10 FNC-1 leader board. UCLMR submission in bold.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Team</cell><cell>% FNC-1 score</cell></row><row><cell>SOLAT in the SWEN</cell><cell>82.02</cell></row><row><cell>Athene</cell><cell>81.97</cell></row><row><cell>UCL Machine Reading</cell><cell>81.72</cell></row><row><cell>Chips Ahoy!</cell><cell>80.21</cell></row><row><cell>CLUlings</cell><cell>79.73</cell></row><row><cell>unconscious bias</cell><cell>79.69</cell></row><row><cell>OSU</cell><cell>79.65</cell></row><row><cell>MITBusters</cell><cell>79.58</cell></row><row><cell>DFKI LT</cell><cell>79.56</cell></row><row><cell>GTRI -ICL</cell><cell>79.33</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>?</head><label></label><figDesc>Sean Bird from Talos Intelligence ? Andreas Hanselowski at the Technische Universit?t Darmstadt ? Jingbo Shang at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign This work was supported by a Marie Curie Career Integration Award, an Allen Distinguished Investigator Award, and Elsevier.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We would like to thank Richard Davis and Chris Proctor at Stanford University for the description of their FNC-1 development efforts <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. The system presented here is based on their setup.</p><p>It should also be noted that Akshay Agrawal, Delenn Chin and Kevin Chen from Stanford University were the first to propose their FNC-1 development efforts as the 'simple but tough-to-beat baseline' <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Our exchange with them was informative and highly appreciated.</p><p>Furthermore, we are grateful for insightful discussions with the following individuals during system development and the official competition.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">TensorFlow: Large-scale machine learning on heterogeneous systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Abadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Barham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Brevdo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Citro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Devin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ghemawat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Goodfellow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Irving</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Isard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jozefowicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kaiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kudlur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Levenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Man?</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Monga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Olah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schuster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shlens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Steiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Talwar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Vanhoucke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Vasudevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Vi?gas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Vinyals</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Warden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wattenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wicke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://tensorflow.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cosine siamese models for stance detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://web.stanford.edu/class/cs224n/reports/2759862.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple but tough-to-beat baseline for sentence embeddings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference for Learning Representations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Talos targets disinformation with Fake News Challenge victory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Baird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sibley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://blog.talosintelligence.com/2017/06/talos-fake-news-challenge.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Approximation by superpositions of a sigmoidal function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cybenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Mathematics of Control, Signals and Systems</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fake news, real consequences: Recruiting neural networks for the fight against fake news</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Proctor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://web.stanford.edu/class/cs224n/reports/2761239.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A baseline implementation for FNC-1</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Galbraith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Iqbal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Van Veen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Thorne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/FakeNewsChallenge/fnc-1-baseline" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital selection and analogue amplification coexist in a cortex-inspired silicon circuit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H R</forename><surname>Hahnloser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sarpeshkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mahowald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Douglas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Seung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Description of the system developed by team Athene in the FNC-1</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hanselowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pvs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Caspelherr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/hanselowski/athene_system/blob/master/system_description_athene.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A statistical interpretation of term specificity and its application in retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Documentation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adam: A method for stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kingma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference for Learning Representations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A statistical approach to mechanized encoding and searching of literary information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Luhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IBM Journal of Research and Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the difficulty of training recurrent neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Pascanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pedregosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Grisel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Dubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vanderplas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Passos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cournapeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P E</forename><surname>Duchesnay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fake News Challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pomerleau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.fakenewschallenge.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dropout: A simple way to prevent neural networks from overfitting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Krizhevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
