<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Multi-Paragraph Reasoning with Knowledge-enhanced Graph Neural Network</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deming</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">State Key Lab on Intelligent Technology and Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yankai</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Pattern Recognition Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>WeChat AI</addrLine>
									<region>Tencent Inc</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhenghao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">State Key Lab on Intelligent Technology and Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiyuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">State Key Lab on Intelligent Technology and Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maosong</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">State Key Lab on Intelligent Technology and Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Multi-Paragraph Reasoning with Knowledge-enhanced Graph Neural Network</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2022-11-12T19:01+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Multi-paragraph reasoning is indispensable for open-domain question answering (OpenQA), which receives less attention in the current OpenQA systems. In this work, we propose a knowledge-enhanced graph neural network (KGNN), which performs reasoning over multiple paragraphs with entities. To explicitly capture the entities' relatedness, KGNN utilizes relational facts in knowledge graph to build the entity graph. The experimental results show that KGNN outperforms in both distractor and full wiki settings than baselines methods on HotpotQA dataset. And our further analysis illustrates KGNN is effective and robust with more retrieved paragraphs.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Open-domain question answering (OpenQA) aims to answer questions based on large-scale knowledge source, such as an unlabelled corpus. Recent years, OpenQA has aroused the interest of many researchers, with the availability of large-scale datasets such as Quasar <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Dhingra et al., 2017)</ref>, SearchQA <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Dunn et al., 2017)</ref>, TriviaQA <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Joshi et al., 2017)</ref>, etc. They proposed lots of OpenQA models <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Clark and Gardner, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wang et al., 2018a,b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Lin et al., 2018)</ref> which achieved promising results in various public benchmarks.</p><p>However, most questions in previous OpenQA datasets only require reasoning within a single paragraph or a single-hop over paragraphs. The HotpotQA dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Yang et al., 2018)</ref> was constructed to facilitate the development of OpenQA system in handling multi-paragraph reasoning. Multi-paragraph reasoning is an important and practical problem towards a more intelligent OpenQA. Nevertheless, existing OpenQA systems have not paid enough attention to multi-paragraph reasoning. They generally fall into two categories when dealing with multiple paragraphs: (1) regarding each paragraph as an individual which cannot reason over paragraphs;</p><p>(2) concatenating all paragraphs into a single long text which leads to time and memory consuming. To achieve a multi-paragraph reasoning system, we propose a knowledge-enhanced graph neural network (KGNN). First, we build an entity graph by all named entities from paragraphs, and add coreference edges to the graph if the entity appears in different paragraphs. After that, to explicitly capture the entities' relatedness, we further utilize the relational facts in knowledge graph (KG) to build the relational entity graph for reasoning, i.e, add a relation edge to the graph if two entities have a relation in KG. We believe that the reasoning information can be captured through propagation  over a relational entity graph. As the example in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, for the given entity Wildest Dreams, we require two kinds of the one-hop reasoning to obtain the answer: One is Wildest Dreams appears in multi-paragraph and the other is reasoning based on the relational fact (Wildest Dreams,lyrics by, Max martin and Shellback).</p><p>Our main contribution is that we propose a novel reasoning module combined with knowledge. The experiments show that reasoning over entities can help our model surpass all baseline models significantly on HotpotQA dataset. Our analysis demonstrates that KGNN is robust and has a strong ability to handle massive texts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Model architecture</head><p>In this section, we introduce the framework of knowledge-enhanced graph neural network (KGNN) for multi-paragraph reasoning.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>, KGNN consists of three parts including encoding module, reasoning module, and prediction module. An additional component is used for supporting fact prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Encoder module</head><p>Without loss of generality, we use the encoding components described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Clark and Gardner (2018)</ref>, which include a character-level encoder, self-attention layer, and bi-attention layer to embed the question and paragraphs into their low-dimensional representations. The question Q and paragraphs {P 1 , P 2 , ? ? ? , P N } are first encoded as: Q = Self-Att(Char-Enc(Q)), (1) P i = Self-Att(Char-Enc(P i )), <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> then we compute the question-related paragraph representations through a bi-attention operation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">P i (0) = Bi-Att(Q, P i ),<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where Char-Enc(?) denotes the "characterlevel encoder", Self-Att(?) denotes the "selfattention layer" and Bi-Att(?) denotes the "biattention layer".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Reasoning module</head><p>Most existing OpenQA models <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Clark and Gardner, 2018)</ref> directly regards all paragraphs as individuals, which may have obstacles in multi-paragraph reasoning for answering questions. Different from existing OpenQA models, KGNN propagates information among paragraphs with entities through a knowledge-enhanced graph neural network.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Build entity graph</head><p>We regard all entities 1 from paragraphs as nodes in the graph for multi-paragraph reasoning, which is denoted by V . And we build the entity graph according to two types of edges among paragraphs. Co-reference of entity is the most common relation across paragraphs. For two nodes v i , v j ? V , an edge? ij = (v i , v j ) will be added to the graph if two nodes indicate the same entity; Furthermore, we adopt relational facts from knowledge graph to enhance our model's reasoning ability. For two nodes v i , v j ? V , a relational edge? r ij = (v i , v j ) will be added to the graph if two entities have a relation r, which could help the relational reasoning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Relational Reasoning</head><p>As we have built the graph G = (V , E), we leverage KGNN to perform reasoning. The reasoning process is as follows:</p><p>Graph Representation. For each node v i ? V , we obtain its initial representation from contextual word representations. Assuming the corresponding entity has k mentions in the paragraph, the initial node representation v i would be defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">v i = Max-Pool(m 1 , m 2 , ..m k ),<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where Max-Pool(?) denotes a max-pooling layer and m i denotes the representation of the mention m i . Here, if a mention m i ranges from s-th to t-th word in the paragraph P j , its representation is defined as the mean of word representations as m i = 1 t?s+1 t l=s FFN(P jl ), where FFN(?) indicates a fully-connect feed-forward layer.</p><p>Message Propagation. As we want to reason over paragraphs with entities, we propagate messages from each node to its neighbors to help perform reasoning. Since different kinds of edges play different roles in reasoning, we use the relation-specific network in the message propagation. Formally, we define the following propagation function for calculating the update of a node:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">v u i = r ? r |N r (v i )| v j ?Nr(v i ) ? r (v j ),<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where N r (v i ) is the neighbor set for v i with relation r. ? r and ? r (?) are relation-specific attention weight and feed-forward network respectively, which is defined as follows.</p><p>To measure the relevance between question and relation, we utilize a entire question representation Q to compute relation-specific attention weight for relation r as ? r = softmax(FFN(Q) . And with a translating relation embedding E r , we design our relation-specific network as ? r (v j ) = FFN(v j + E r ).</p><p>Paragraph Update. After message propagation over entities among paragraphs, we update the question-aware paragraph representations. We first define question-aware paragraph representations U ij is defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">U ij = v u Idx(ij) an entity appears at P ij , 0 otherwise,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where Idx(?) indicates the node index of P ij in the constructed entity graph. Further, we utilize a reset gate to decide how much information to keep from the graph-aware paragraph representation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">r ij = ?(W pP ij + W u U ij ),<label>(7)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">U ij = r ij * U ij + (1 ? r ij ) * P ij ,<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where W p and W u are trainable matrices and ? denotes the sigmoid function. Finally, we apply self-attention mechanism to share global information from entities to the whole paragraph, and the output of reasoning part will be added to the input as a residual:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">P ij =P ij + Self-Att(? ij ).<label>(9)</label></formula><p>We denote the initial paragraph representations asP <ref type="bibr">(0)</ref> , and denote the entire one-step reasoning process, i.e., Eq. (4-9) as a single function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">P (t) = Reason(P) (t?1) ,<label>(10)</label></formula><p>where t ? 1. Hence, a T -step reasoning can be divided into T times one-step reasoning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Prediction module</head><p>After T -step reasoning on the relational entity graph, we predict the answer according to the final question-aware paragraph representationsP <ref type="bibr">(T )</ref> . Furthermore, for the sake of the answer probability comparison among multiple paragraphs, we utilize shared-normalization <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Clark and Gardner, 2018</ref>) in the answer prediction.</p><p>3 Experiment</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Dataset</head><p>We use HotpotQA to conduct our experiments.</p><p>HotpotQA is an OpenQA dataset with complex reasoning, which contains more than 11k question-answer pairs and all questions in development and testing set require complex multi-hop reasoning over paragraphs. We evaluate KGNN on distractor and full wiki settings of HotpotQA. In distractor setting, 2 golden paragraphs are given as inputs with 8 disturbance terms. In full wiki setting, only questions are offered and we need to extract the answer from the whole corpus. So we employ an information retrieval system to retrieve 30 paragraphs from the entire Wikipedia for the following experiment.</p><p>For the relational entity graph construction, we align entities to Wikidata items and we add 5 common relations in question answering to propagate message. The relations include {director, position held, record label, lyrics by, adapted from }.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Baseline Methods</head><p>To verify the effectiveness of our reasoning module, we compare KGNN with <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Yang et al. (2018)</ref>     </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Overall Result</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Effect of Layer Number</head><p>In this part, we additionally perform experiments to understand the effect of the layer number on KGNN. From <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 2</ref>, we could observe that 2-layer KGNN model achieves the best performance. From carefully analyzing the data, we find that most questions in HophotQA dataset only require 2-hop reasoning for obtaining the answer. And 2-layer KGNN model has the ability to capture enough reasoning flows in this scenario.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Effect of Paragraph Number</head><p>In real world (i.e., full wiki setting), an OpenQA system usually covers enough paragraphs to provide useful information for answering questions. Nevertheless, the noise of paragraphs misleads models and remains a challenge for OpenQA. For each question, we use 30 retrieved paragraphs to investigate the denoising ability of the system. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 3</ref>, KGNN model handles and acquires more information from extra paragraphs. KGNN's performance increases more significantly than <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Yang et al. (2018)</ref>. The results demonstrate that reasoning across paragraphs through entities and their relations is a robust and flexible way of encoding multiple paragraphs.   </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Overview of KGNN.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>question answering (OpenQA) aims to answer the given question by leveraging knowledge sources, which is first proposed by Green Jr et al. (1961). Recently, Chen et al. (2017) introduces machine reading comprehension technique to answer open-domain questions by reading multiple retrieved texts. Wang et al. (2018a) selects a most informative paragraph to answer the question. Moreover, Wang et al. (2018b), Lin et al. (2018) and Clark and Gardner (2018) focus on how to aggregate evidence in multiple paragraphs. However, all existing OpenQA models simply regard each paragraph as an individual or concatenate all paragraphs into a single long text. Sun et al. (2018), De Cao et al. (2019) and Cao et al. (2019) introduce entity graph neural network to reason over entities for Knowledge Base QA (KBQA). Different from KBQA, our work regards entities as bridges to reason over paragraphs and can give a span-style answer instead of supplying an entity-style answer.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Yang et al. (2018)</ref> distractor 45.60 59.02 20.32 64.49 10.83 40.16 KGNN distractor 50.81 65.75 38.74 76.79 22.40 52.82</figDesc><table><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>Setting</cell><cell>EM</cell><cell>Ans</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell cols="2">Sup Fact EM F1</cell><cell>EM</cell><cell cols="2">Joint</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Yang et al. (2018) full wiki</cell><cell cols="3">23.95 32.89</cell><cell>3.86</cell><cell>37.71</cell><cell cols="2">1.85</cell><cell>16.15</cell></row><row><cell>KGNN</cell><cell>full wiki</cell><cell cols="5">27.65 37.19 12.65 47.19</cell><cell cols="2">7.03</cell><cell>24.66</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="6">and a modified version, named Yang et al. (2018)-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="6">split, which regards all paragraphs individually</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="6">and applies a shared-normalization function over</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="6">paragraphs to obtain the answer.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results on HotpotQA test set for distractor and full wiki settings.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>EM</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Yang et al. (2018)-split 11.87 41.87</cell></row><row><cell>Yang et al. (2018)</cell><cell cols="2">18.14 50.72</cell></row><row><cell>KGNN (#Layer=1)</cell><cell cols="2">22.26 53.50</cell></row><row><cell>KGNN (#Layer=2)</cell><cell cols="2">22.41 54.05</cell></row><row><cell>KGNN (#Layer=3)</cell><cell cols="2">22.24 53.49</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Effect of Layer Number on joint metrics.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>shows experimental results on HotpotQA</cell></row><row><cell>dataset. The table illustrates that our model out-</cell></row><row><cell>performs Yang et al. (2018) in both distractor and</cell></row><row><cell>full wiki settings. It indicates the effectiveness of</cell></row><row><cell>KGNN model in multi-paragraph reasoning with</cell></row><row><cell>external knowledge.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Effect of paragraph number on joint F1.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">We link the named entities to Wikidata with spaCy (https://spacy.io/)</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">We use Adam optimizer to train the official code and gain 10% joint F1 promotion</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">ConclusionMulti-paragraph reasoning is crucial for answering open-domain questions in practice, while it is still not considered in most existing OpenQA systems. In this work, we propose a novel OpenQA model KGNN, which performs reasoning over paragraphs via a knowledge enhanced graph neural network. Experimental results show that KGNN outperforms strong baselines with a large margin on the HotpotQA dataset, and also has the ability to tackle more informative texts. We hope our work can shed some lights to the combination of knowledge graph and text for OpenQA.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bag: Bidirectional attention entity graph convolutional network for multi-hop reasoning question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meng</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dacheng</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reading wikipedia to answer opendomain questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danqi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Fisch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Illia Polosukhin, Alexandre Lacoste, and Jonathan Berant</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eunsol</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Hewlett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jakob</forename><surname>Uszkoreit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Coarse-to-fine question answering for long documents</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple and effective multi-paragraph reading comprehension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Question answering by reasoning across documents with graph convolutional networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>De Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wilker</forename><surname>Aziz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Titov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quasar: Datasets for question answering by search and reading</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bhuwan</forename><surname>Dhingra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathryn</forename><surname>Mazaitis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1707.03904</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Levent</forename><surname>Sagun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ugur</forename><surname>Guney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Volkan</forename><surname>Cirik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyunghyun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1704.05179</idno>
		<title level="m">SearchQA: A new q&amp;a dataset augmented with context from a search engine</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Baseball: an automatic question-answerer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alice</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Bert F Green</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carol</forename><surname>Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><surname>Chomsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Laughery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of IRE-AIEE</title>
		<meeting>IRE-AIEE</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TriviaQA: A large scale distantly supervised challenge dataset for reading comprehension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mandar</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eunsol</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Denoising distantly supervised open-domain question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yankai</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haozhe</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiyuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maosong</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haitian</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bhuwan</forename><surname>Dhingra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manzil</forename><surname>Zaheer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathryn</forename><surname>Mazaitis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruslan</forename><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open domain question answering using early fusion of knowledge bases and text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">R3: Reinforced ranker-reader for open-domain question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuohang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoxiao</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiguo</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Klinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shiyu</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerald</forename><surname>Tesauro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowen</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of AAAI</title>
		<meeting>AAAI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence aggregation for answer re-ranking in open-domain question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuohang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoxiao</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shiyu</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiguo</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Klinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerald</forename><surname>Tesauro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Murray</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICLR</title>
		<meeting>ICLR</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hotpotqa: A dataset for diverse, explainable multi-hop question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhilin</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peng</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saizheng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruslan</forename><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
