<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">REPRESENTATION LEARNING VIA INVARIANT CAUSAL MECHANISMS</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jovana</forename><surname>Mitrovic</surname></persName>
							<email>mitrovic@google.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DeepMind</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Mcwilliams</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DeepMind</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
							<email>jcwalker@google.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DeepMind</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lars</forename><surname>Buesing</surname></persName>
							<email>lbuesing@google.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DeepMind</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Blundell</surname></persName>
							<email>cblundell@google.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DeepMind</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">REPRESENTATION LEARNING VIA INVARIANT CAUSAL MECHANISMS</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2022-11-11T22:09+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Self-supervised learning has emerged as a strategy to reduce the reliance on costly supervised signal by pretraining representations only using unlabeled data. These methods combine heuristic proxy classification tasks with data augmentations and have achieved significant success, but our theoretical understanding of this success remains limited. In this paper we analyze self-supervised representation learning using a causal framework. We show how data augmentations can be more effectively utilized through explicit invariance constraints on the proxy classifiers employed during pretraining. Based on this, we propose a novel selfsupervised objective, Representation Learning via Invariant Causal Mechanisms (RELIC), that enforces invariant prediction of proxy targets across augmentations through an invariance regularizer which yields improved generalization guarantees. Further, using causality we generalize contrastive learning, a particular kind of self-supervised method, and provide an alternative theoretical explanation for the success of these methods. Empirically, RELIC significantly outperforms competing methods in terms of robustness and out-of-distribution generalization on ImageNet, while also significantly outperforming these methods on Atari achieving above human-level performance on 51 out of 57 games.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Training deep networks often relies heavily on large amounts of useful supervisory signal, such as labels for supervised learning or rewards for reinforcement learning. These training signals can be costly or otherwise impractical to acquire. On the other hand, unsupervised data is often abundantly available. Therefore, pretraining representations for unknown downstream tasks without the need for labels or extrinsic reward holds great promise for reducing the cost of applying machine learning models. To pretrain representations, self-supervised learning makes use of proxy tasks defined on unsupervised data. Recently, self-supervised methods using contrastive objectives have emerged as one of the most successful strategies for unsupervised representation learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Oord et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Hjelm et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chen et al., 2020a)</ref>. These methods learn a representation by classifying every datapoint against all others datapoints (negative examples). Under assumptions on how the negative examples are sampled, minimizing the resulting contrastive loss has been justified as maximizing a lower bound on the mutual information (MI) between representations <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Poole et al., 2019)</ref>. However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Tschannen et al., 2019)</ref> has shown that performance on downstream tasks may be more tightly correlated with the choice of encoder architecture than the achieved MI bound, highlighting issues with the MI theory of contrastive learning. Further, contrastive approaches compare different views of the data (usually under different data augmentations) to calculate similarity scores. This approach to computing scores has been empirically observed as a key success factor of contrastive methods, but has yet to be theoretically justified. This lack of a solid theoretical explanation for the effectiveness of contrastive methods hinders their further development.</p><p>To remedy the theoretical shortcomings, we analyze the problem of self-supervised representation learning through a causal lens. We formalize intuitions about the data generating process using a causal graph and leverage causal tools to derive properties of the optimal representation. We show that a representation should be an invariant predictor of proxy targets under interventions on features that are only correlated, but not causally related to the downstream targets of interest.</p><p>Since neither causally nor purely correlationally related features are observed and thus performing actual interventions on them is not feasible, for learning representation with this property we use data augmentations to simulate a subset of possible interventions. Based on our causal interpretation, we propose a regularizer which enforces that the prediction of the proxy targets is invariant across data augmentations. We propose a novel objective for self-supervised representation learning called REpresentation Learning with Invariant Causal mechanisms (RELIC). We show how this explicit invariance regularization leverages augmentations more effectively than previous self-supervised methods and that representations learned using RELIC are guaranteed to generalize well to downstream tasks under weaker assumptions than those required by previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Next we generalize contrastive learning and provide an alternative theoretical explanation to MI for the success of these methods. We generalize the proxy task of instance discrimination commonly used in contrastive learning using the causal concept of refinements <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Chalupka et al., 2014)</ref>. Intuitively, a refinement of a task can be understood as a more fine-grained variant of the original problem. For example, a refinement for classifying cats against dogs would be the task of classifying individual cat and dog breeds. The instance discrimination task results from the most fine-grained refinement, e.g. discriminating individual cats and dogs from one another. We show that using refinements as proxy tasks enables us to learn useful representations for downstream tasks. Specifically, using causal tools, we show that learning a representation on refinements such that it is an invariant predictor of proxy targets across augmentations is a sufficient condition for these representations to generalize to downstream tasks (cf. Theorem 1). In summary, we provide theoretical support both for the general form of the contrastive objective as well as for the use of data augmentations. Thus, we provide an alternative explanation to mutual information for the success of recent contrastive approaches namely that of causal refinements of downstream tasks.</p><p>We test RELIC on a variety of prediction and reinforcement learning problems. First, we evaluate the quality of representations pretrained on ImageNet with a special focus on robustness and out-ofdistribution generalization. RELIC performs competitively with current state-of-the-art methods on ImageNet, while significantly outperforming competing methods on robustness and out-of-distribution generalization of the learned representations when tested on corrupted ImageNet (ImageNet-C <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hendrycks &amp; Dietterich, 2019)</ref>) and a version of ImageNet that consist of different renditions of the same classes (ImageNet-R <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Hendrycks et al., 2020)</ref>). In terms of robustness, RELIC also significantly outperforms the supervised baseline with an absolute reduction of 4.9% in error. Unlike much prior work that specifically focuses on computer vision tasks, we test RELIC for representation learning in the context of reinforcement learning on the Atari suite <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bellemare et al., 2013)</ref>. There we find that RELIC significantly outperforms competing methods and achieves above human-level performance on 51 out of 57 games.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Contributions.</head><p>? We formalize problem of self-supervised representation learning using causality and propose to more effectively leverage data augmentations through invariant prediction.</p><p>? We propose a new self-supervised objective, REpresentation Learning with Invariance Causal mechanisms (RELIC), that enforces invariant prediction through an explicit regularizer and show improved generalization guarantees.</p><p>? We generalize contrastive learning using refinements and show that learning on refinements is a sufficient condition for learning useful representations; this provides an alternative explanation to MI for the success of contrastive methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">REPRESENTATION LEARNING VIA INVARIANT CAUSAL MECHANISMS</head><p>Problem setting. Let X denote the unlabelled observed data and Y = {Y t } T t=1 be a set of unknown tasks with Y t denoting the targets for task t. The tasks {Y t } T t=1 can represent both a multi-environment as well as a multi-task setup. Our goal is to pretrain with unsupervised data a representation f (X) that will be useful for solving the downstream tasks Y.</p><p>Causal interpretation. To effectively leverage common assumptions and intuitions about data generation of the unknown downstream tasks for the learning algorithm, we propose to formalize them using a causal graph. We start from the following assumptions: a) the data is generated from content and style variables, with b) only content (and not style) being relevant for the unknown downstream tasks and c) content and style are independent, i.e. style changes are content-preserving. For example, when classifying dogs against giraffes from images, different parts of the animals constitute content, while style could be, for example, background, lighting conditions and camera lens characteristics. By assumption, content is a good representation of the data for downstream tasks and we therefore cast the goal of representation learning as estimating content. In the following, we compactly formalize these assumptions with a causal graph 1 , see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">S C Y 1 Y T X f (X) Y R Data generation Representation Learning . . .</formula><p>Let C and S be the latent variables describing content and style. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref>, the directed arrows from C and S to the observed data X (e.g. images) indicate that X is generated based on content and style. The directed arrow from C to the target Y t (e.g. class labels) encodes the assumption that content directly influences the target tasks, while the absence of any directed arrow from S to Y t indicates that style does not. Thus, content C has all the necessary information to predict Y t . The absence of any directed path between C and S in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref> encodes the intuition that these variables are independent, i.e. C ? ? S.</p><p>Using the independence of mechanisms <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Peters et al., 2017)</ref>, we can conclude that under this causal model performing interventions on S does not change the conditional distribution P (Y t |C), i.e. manipulating the value of S does not influence this conditional distribution. Thus, P (Y t |C) is invariant under changes in style S. We call C an invariant representation for Y t under S, i.e.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">p do(S=si) (Y t | C) = p do(S=sj ) (Y t | C) ? s i , s j ? S,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where p do(S=s) denotes the distribution arising from assigning S the value s with S the domain of S <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Pearl, 2009)</ref>. Specifically, using C as a representation allows for us to predict targets stably across perturbations, i.e. content C is both a useful and robust representation for tasks Y.</p><p>Since the targets Y t are unknown, we will construct a proxy task Y R in order to learn representations from unlabeled data X only. In order to learn useful representations for Y t , we will construct proxy tasks that represents more fine-grained problems that Y t ; for a more formal treatment of proxy tasks please refer to Section 3. Further, to learn invariant representations, such as C, we enforce Equation 1 which requires us to observe data under different style interventions, i.e. we need data that describes the same content under varying style. Since we do not have access to S, to simulate style variability we use content-preserving data augmentations (e.g. rotation, grayscaling, translation, cropping for images). Specifically, we utilize data augmentations as interventions on the style variable S, i.e. applying data augmentation a i corresponds to intervening on S and setting it to s ai . 2 Although we are not able to generate all possible styles using a fixed set of data augmentations, we will use augmentations that generate large sets of diverse styles as this allows us to learn better representations. Note that the heuristic of estimating similarity based on different views from contrastive learning can be interpreted as an implicit invariance constraint.</p><p>RELIC objective. Equation 1 provides a general scheme to estimate content (c.f. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref>). We operationalize this by proposing to learn representations such that prediction of proxy targets from the representation is invariant under data augmentations. The representation f (X) must fulfill the following invariant prediction criteria</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">(Invariant prediction) p do(ai) (Y R |f (X)) = p do(aj ) (Y R |f (X)) ?a i , a j ? A.</formula><p>(2) A = {a 1 , . . . , a m } is the set of data augmentations which simulate interventions on the style variables and p do(a) denotes p do(S=sa) .</p><p>To achieve invariant prediction, we propose to explicitly enforce invariance under augmentations through a regularizer. This gives rise to an objective for self-supervised learning we call Representation Learning via Invariant Causal Mechanisms (RELIC). We write this objective as</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">E X E a lk ,aqt ?A?A b?{a lk ,aqt} L b (Y R , f (X)) s.t. KL p do(a lk ) (Y R | f (X)), p do(aqt) (Y R | f (X)) ? ?</formula><p>where L is the proxy task loss and KL is the Kullback-Leibler (KL) divergence. Note that any distance measure on distributions can be used in place of the KL divergence. We explain the remaining terms in detail below. Concretely, as proxy task we associate to every datapoint x i the label y R i = i. This corresponds to the instance discrimination task, commonly used in contrastive learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Hadsell et al., 2006)</ref>. We take pairs of points (x i , x j ) to compute similarity scores and use pairs of augmentations a lk = (a l , a k ) ? A ? A to perform a style intervention. Given a batch of samples</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">{x i } N i=1 ? D, we use p do(a lk ) (Y R = j | f (x i )) ? exp ?(f (x a l i ), h(x a k<label>j</label></formula><p>))/? . with x a data augmented with a and ? a softmax temperature parameter. We encode f using a neural network and choose h to be related to f , e.g. h = f or as a network with an exponential moving average of the weights of f (e.g. target networks similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref>). To compare representations we use the function ?(f (x i ), h(x j )) = g(f (x i )), g(h(x j )) where g is a fullyconnected neural network often called the critic.</p><p>Combining these pieces, we learn representations by minimizing the following objective over the full set of data x i ? D and augmentations a lk</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">? A ? A ? N i=1 a lk log exp (?(f (x a l i ), h(x a k i ))/? ) M m=1 exp (?(f (x a l i ), h(x a k m ))/? ) + ? a lk ,aqt KL(p do(a lk ) , p do(aqt) )<label>(3)</label></formula><p>with M the number of points we use to construct the contrast set and ? the weighting of the invariance penalty. We used the shorthand p do(a) for p do(a) (Y R = j | f (x i )). With appropriate choices for ?, g, f and h above, Equation 3 recovers many recent state-of-the-art methods (c.f. <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> in Section A). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b</ref> presents a schematic of the RELIC objective.</p><p>The explicit invariance penalty encourages the within-class distances (for a downstream task of interest) of the representations learned by RELIC to be tightly concentrated. We show this empirically in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> and theoretically in Appendix B. In the following section we provide theoretical justification for using an instance discrimination-based contrastive loss using a causal perspective. We also show (cf. Theorem 1 below) that minimizing the contrastive loss alone (i.e. ? = 0) does not guarantee generalization. Instead, invariance across augmentations must be explicitly enforced.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">GENERALIZING CONTRASTIVE LEARNING</head><p>Learning with refinements. In contrastive learning, the task of instance discrimination, i.e. classifying the dataset {(x i , y R i = i)|x i ? D}, is used as the proxy task. To better understand contrastive learning and motivate this proxy task, we generalize instance discrimination using the causal concept of refinements <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Chalupka et al., 2014)</ref>. Intuitively, a refinement of one problem is another more fine-grained problem. If task Y t is to classify cats against dogs, then a refinement of Y t is the task of classifying cats and dogs into their individual breeds. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref> for a further visual example. For any set of tasks, there exist many different refinements. However, the most fine-grained refinement corresponds exactly to classifying the dataset {(x i , y R i = i)|x i ? D}. Thus, the instance discrimination task used in contrastive learning is a specific type of refinement. For a definition and formal treatment of refinements please refer to Appendix D.</p><p>Let Y R be targets of a proxy task that is a refinement for all tasks in Y. Leveraging causal tools, we connect learning on refinements to learning on downstream tasks. Specifically, we provide a theoretical justification for exchanging unknown downstream tasks with these specially constructed proxy tasks. We show that if f (X) is an invariant representation for Y R under changes in style S, then f (X) is also an invariant representation for tasks in Y under changes in style S. Thus by enforcing invariance under style interventions on a refinement, we learn representations that generalize to downstream tasks. 3 This is summarized in the following theorem.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Theorem 1. Let Y = {Y t } T t=1 be a family of downstream tasks. Let Y R be a refinement for all tasks in Y. If f (X) is an invariant representation for Y R under style interventions S, then f (X) is an invariant representation for all tasks in Y under style interventions S, i.e. p do(si) (Y R | f (X)) = p do(sj ) (Y R | f (X)) ? p do(si) (Y t | f (X)) = p do(sj ) (Y t | f (X)) (4) for all s i , s j ? S with p do(si) = p do(S=si) . Thus, f (X) is a representation that generalizes to Y.</formula><p>Theorem 1 states that if Y R is a refinement of Y then learning a representation on Y R is a sufficient condition for this representation to be useful on Y. For a formal exposition of these points and accompanying proofs, please refer to Appendix D. Recall that the instance discrimination proxy task is the most fine-grained refinement, and so the left hand side of 4 is satisfied for any downstream task satisfying the stated assumptions of the theorem.</p><p>We generalize contrastive learning through refinements and connect representations learned on refinements and downstream tasks in Theorem 1. Thus, using causality we provide an alternative explanation to mutual information for the success of contrastive learning. Note that our methodology of refinements is not limited to instance discrimination tasks and is thus more general than currently used contrastive losses. Real world data often includes rich sources of metadata which can be used to guide the construction of refinements by grouping the data according to any available meta-data. Note that the coarser we can create a refinement, the more data efficient we can expect to be when learning representations for downstream tasks. Further, we can also expect to require less supervised data to finetune the representation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">RELATED WORK</head><p>Contrastive objectives and mutual information maximization. Many recent approaches to selfsupervised learning are rooted in the well-established idea of maximizing mutual information (MI), e.g. Contrastive Predictive Coding (CPC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Oord et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">H?naff et al., 2019)</ref>, Deep InfoMax (DIM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Hjelm et al., 2018)</ref> and Augmented Multiscale DIM (AMDIM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bachman et al., 2019)</ref>. These methods are based on noise contrastive estimation (NCE) <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Gutmann &amp; Hyv?rinen, 2010)</ref> which, under specific conditions, can be viewed as a bound on MI <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Poole et al., 2019)</ref>. The resulting objective functions are commonly referred to as InfoNCE.</p><p>The precise role played by mutual information maximization in self-supervised learning is subject to some debate. <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Tschannen et al., 2019)</ref> argue that the performance on downstream tasks is not correlated with the achieved bound on MI, but may be more tightly correlated with encoder architecture and capacity. Importantly, InfoNCE objectives require custom architectures to ensure the network does not converge to non-informative solutions thus precluding the use of standard architectures. Recently, several works <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(He et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chen et al., 2020a)</ref> successfully combined contrastive estimation with a standard ResNet-50 architecture. In particular, SimCLR <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2020a)</ref> relies on a set of strong augmentations 4 , while <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(He et al., 2019)</ref> uses a memory bank. Inspired by target networks in reinforcement learning, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref> proposed BYOL: an algorithm for self-supervised learning which remarkably does not use a contrastive objective. Although theoretical explanation for the good performance of BYOL is presently missing, interestingly the objective, an 2 distance between two different embeddings of the input data resembles the 2 form of our regularizer proposed in Equation 5 in Appendix B. Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019)</ref> proposed a learning theoretic framework to analyze the performance of contrastive objectives. However, without strong assumptions on intra-class concentration they note that contrastive objectives are fundamentally limited in the representations they are able to learn. RELIC explicitly enforces intra-class concentration via the invariance regularizer, ensuring that it generalizes under weaker assumptions. Unlike <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019)</ref> which do not discuss augmentations, we incorporate augmentations into our theoretical explanation of contrastive methods.</p><p>The reasons for the improvement in performance from AMDIM through to SimCLR and BYOL are not easily explained by either the MI maximization or the learning theoretic viewpoint. Further, it is not clear why relatively minor architectural differences between the methods result in significant differences in performance nor is it obvious how current state-of-the-art can be improved. In contrast to prior art, the performance of RELIC is explained by connections to causal theory. As such it gives a clear path for improving results by devising problem appropriate refinements, interventions and invariance penalties. Furthermore, the use of invariance penalties in RELIC as dictated by causal theory yields significantly more robust representations that generalize better than those learned with SimCLR or BYOL.</p><p>Causality and invariance. Recently, the notion of invariant prediction has emerged as an important operational concept in causal inference <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Peters et al., 2016)</ref>. This idea has been used to learn classifiers which are robust against domain shifts <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Gong et al., 2016)</ref>. Notably, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Heinze-Deml &amp; Meinshausen, 2017)</ref> propose to use group structure to delineate between different environments where the aim is to minimize the classification loss while also ensuring that the conditional variance of the prediction function within each group remains small. Unlike <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Heinze-Deml &amp; Meinshausen, 2017)</ref> who use supervised data and rely on having a grouping in the training data, our approach does not rely on ground-truth targets and can flexibly create groupings of the training data if none are present. Further, we enforce invariant prediction within the group by constraining the distance between distributions resulting from contrasting data across groups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">EXPERIMENTS</head><p>We first visualize the influence of the explicit invariance constraint in RELIC on the linear separability of the learned representations. We then evaluate RELIC on a number of prediction and reinforcement learning tasks for usefulness and robustness. For the prediction tasks, we test RELIC after pretraining the representation in a self-supervised way on the training set of the ImageNet ILSVRC-2012 dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Russakovsky et al., 2015)</ref>. We evaluate RELIC in the linear evaluation setup on ImageNet and test its robustness and out-of-distribution generalization on datasets related to ImageNet. Unlike much prior work in contrastive learning which focuses specifically on computer vision tasks, we test RELIC also in the context of learning representations for reinforcement learning. Specifically, we test RELIC on the suite of Atari games (Bellemare et al., 2013) which consists of 57 diverse games of varying difficulty.</p><p>Linear evaluation. In order to understand how representations learned by RELIC differ from other methods, we compare it against those learned by AMDIM and SimCLR in terms of Fischer's linear discriminant ratio <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Friedman et al., 2009)</ref></p><formula xml:id="formula_7">: F LDA = ? k ? ? k 2 / i,j?C k f (x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 where ? k = 1 |C k | i?C k f (x i )</formula><p>is the mean of the representations of class k and C k is the index set of that class. A larger F LDA implies that classes are more easily separated with a linear classifier. This can be achieved by either increasing distances between classes (numerator) or shrinking within-class variance (denominator). <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows the distribution of F LDA for RELIC, SimCLR and AMDIM after training as measured on the (downsampled) ImageNet validation set. The distance between medians of RELIC and SimCLR is 162. AMDIM is tightly concentrated close to 20. The invariance penalty ensures thateven though labels are a-priori unknown-for RELIC within-class variability of f is concentrated leading to better linear separability between classes in the downstream task of interest. This is reflected in the rightward shift of the distribution of F LDA in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> for RELIC compared with SimCLR and AMDIM which do not impose such a constraint. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Top-1 Top-5 ResNet-50 architecture PIRL <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Misra &amp; Maaten, 2020)</ref> 63.6 -CPC v2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(H?naff et al., 2019)</ref> 63.8 85.3 CMC <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Tian et al., 2019)</ref> 66.2 87.0 SimCLR <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2020a)</ref> * 69.3 89.0 SwAV <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Caron et al., 2020)</ref> * 70.1 -RELIC (ours) * 70.3 89.5 InfoMin Aug. <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Tian et al., 2020)</ref> ? 73.0 91.1 SwAV <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Caron et al., 2020)</ref> ? 75.3 -ResNet-50 with target network MoCo v2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Chen et al., 2020b)</ref> 71.1 -BYOL <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref> *  <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Caron et al., 2020)</ref> and InfoMin <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Tian et al., 2020)</ref>, but note that these methods use stronger augmentations which alone have been shown to boost performance by over 5%.</p><p>A fair comparison between different objectives can only be achieved under the same architecture and the same set of augmentations.</p><p>Robustness and generalization. We evaluate robustness and out-of-distribution generalization of RELIC's representation on datasets Imagenet-C <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hendrycks &amp; Dietterich, 2019)</ref> and ImageNet-R <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Hendrycks et al., 2020)</ref>, respectively. To evaluate RELIC's representation, we train a linear classifier on top of the frozen representation following the procedure described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2020a)</ref> and appendix E.5.2. For Imagenet-C we report the mean Corruption Error (mCE) and Corruption Errors for Noise corruptions in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>. RELIC has significantly lower mCE than both the supervised ResNet-50 baseline and the unsupervised methods SimCLR and BYOL. Also, it has the lowest Corruption Error on 14 out of 15 corruptions when compared to SimCLR and BYOL. Thus, we see that RELIC learns the most robust representation. RELIC also outperforms SimCLR and BYOL on ImageNet-R showing its superior out-of-distribution generalization ability; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>. For further details and results please consult E.5.  Reinforcement Learning. Much prior work in contrastive learning has focused specifically on computer vision tasks. In order to compare these approaches in a different domain, we investigate representation learning in the context of reinforcement learning. We compare RELIC as an auxiliary loss against other state of the art self-supervised losses on an agent trained on 57 Atari games. Using human normalized scores as a metric, we use the original architecture and hyperparameters of the R2D2 agent <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kapturowski et al., 2019)</ref> and supplement it with a second encoder trained with a given representation learning loss. When auxiliary losses are present, the Q-Network takes the output of the second encoder as an input. The Q-Network and the encoder are trained with separate optimizers. For the augmentation baseline, the Q-Network takes two identical encoders trained end-to-end. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table  4</ref> shows a comparison between RELIC, SimCLR, BYOL, CURL <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Srinivas et al., 2020)</ref>, and feeding augmented observations directly to the agent <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kostrikov et al., 2020)</ref>. We find that RELIC has a significant advantage over competing self-supervised methods, performing best in 25 out of 57 games. The next best performing method, CURL performs best in 11 games. Full details are presented in Section E.6. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">CONCLUSION</head><p>In this work we have analyzed self-supervised learning using a causal framework. Using a causal graph, we have formalized the problem of self-supervised representation learning and derived properties of the optimal representation. We have shown that representations need to be invariant predictors of proxy targets under interventions on features that are only correlated, but not causally related to the downstream tasks. We have leveraged data augmentations to simulate these interventions and have proposed to explicitly enforce this invariance constraint. Based on this, we have proposed a new self-supervised objective, Representation Learning via Invariant Causal Mechanisms (RELIC), that enforces invariant prediction of proxy targets across augmentations using an invariance regularizer. Further, we have generalized contrastive methods using the concept of refinements and have shown that learning a representation on refinements using the principle of invariant prediction is a sufficient condition for these representations to generalize to downstream tasks. With this, we have provided an alternative explanation to mutual information for the success of contrastive methods. Empirically we have compared RELIC against recent self-supervised methods on a variety of prediction and reinforcement learning tasks. Specifically, RELIC significantly outperforms competing methods in terms of robustness and out-of-distribution generalization of the representations it learns on ImageNet. RELIC also significantly outperforms related self-supervised methods on the Atari suite achieving superhuman performance on 51 out of 57 games. We aim to investigate the construction of more coarse-grained refinements and the empirical evaluation of different kinds of refinements in future work.</p><p>A RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN RELIC AND OTHER METHODS <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: The objective in eq. (3) recovers state of the art methods depending on design choices ("-" denotes the identity function and "norml." means g is constrained to have unit norm).</p><p>Method ? g Regl. CPC <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(H?naff et al., 2019)</ref> g, W g PixelCNN -AMDIM <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bachman et al., 2019)</ref> ?, ? --SimCLR <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2020a)</ref> g, g MLP, norml.</p><p>-BYOL <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref> g 1 , g 2 1 layer MLP, norml. g 1 (g 2 ) ? g 2 2 RELIC (ours) g, g MLP, norml. Eq.</p><p>(3)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B DISTANCE CONCENTRATION AND GENERALIZATION</head><p>Quantifying the generalization performance of representations learned on unlabelled data is a difficult task without imposing assumptions on the underlying structure of the data and the downstream tasks of interest. The results in <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019</ref>) assume a latent class structure underlying the data. The similarity of images under each (potentially overlapping) latent class c is measured by a probability distribution D c . In the contrastive setting a positive pair of points {x, x + } is said to be sampled from a distribution E c D c (x)D c (x + ) and a negative example x ? is sampled from the marginal distribution. The task of interest is multi-class classification using the learned representation. In our setting the augmented data points {x a l i , x a k i } and {x a l i , x a k m } M m=1 take the roles of the pairs of positive and negative points, respectively.</p><p>In this section, under the same structural assumptions on the data as <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019)</ref> we will show that a similar result holds but under weaker assumptions on the function, f . To intuit the following results, we can view our explicit invariance constraint through the lens of distance concentration. Its effect can be seen intuitively in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>. The shaded region represents the set of augmentations, A around an image. Depicted are two images x i and x j from the ImageNet class Stingray. The points x a l i and x a k j are augmentations which correspond to a region of overlap between the augmentation sets of x i and x j . If the augmentations f (x a l i ) and f (x a k j ) are similar enough, encouraging f (x i ) to be close to f (x a l i ) and similarly for f (x j ) and f (x a k j ) indirectly encourages f (x i ) to be close to f (x j ). This has the effect of concentrating distances between similar images. We will make this intuition more formal in the following discussion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Consider a modified, Euclidean distance regularized version of our objectiv?</head><formula xml:id="formula_8">f ? arg min f ?F N i=1 a lk ({f (x a l i ) (f (x a k i ) ? f (x a k m ))} M m=1 ) s.t. f (x i ) ? f (x ak i ) 2 ? ?. (5) where f ? F = {f : X ? R d s.t. ||f || 2 ? T } with T ? 0. Here (v) = log(1 + m exp(v m ))</formula><p>is the logistic loss. For a single negative, this is equivalent to the standard RELIC objective with an identity critic.</p><p>Assumptions. We require that the following assumptions hold: (A1)f is L-Lipschitz and minimizes eq. (5) such that the constraint is active and (A2) x is a bounded variable.</p><p>Lemma 1 (Concentration). If assumption (A1) holds for ? ? B 6L? , and (A2) holds for x,f (x) is a sub-Gaussian random variable with parameter ? 2 f ? 1 ? ? 2 x .</p><p>See Appendix C for proof. This result states that the Euclidean version of our invariance regularizer has the effect of contracting the within-class variance of the data. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows that this holds in practise for the original version of our objective in eq. (3). This guarantees that the following generalization result from <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019)</ref> holds. For brevity we state an informal version of the Theorem with details deferred to the original publication. Theorem 2 (Generalization. Adapted from Lemma B.2. from <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019)</ref>). Let L ? sup (f ) be the standard (K + 1)-wise hinge loss of the linear classification function W ? f whose c th column is ? For all practical purposes, the final generalization result is identical to <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019)</ref> stating thatf -which is learned by minimizing a contrastive objective on unlabelled data-performs well on labelled data. However, this crucially depends on the intraclass concentration of the representation, that f (x) is sub-Gaussian with parameter ? 2 f . Whereas in <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Saunshi et al., 2019)</ref> this was assumed to hold, our Lemma 1 shows that the necessary concentration is ensured by our invariance penalty. Experimentally we see this property holds in practise (figure 2).</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">x = 1 |Cc| i?Cc f (x i )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C ADDITIONAL RESULTS</head><p>Proof of Lemma 1. Assume the data x is ? 2</p><p>x -sub-Gaussian. In practise this holds since x is bounded. It immediately follows that L-Lipschitz function f (x) sub-Gaussian with parameter at most L. Now we will characterize the reduction in variance from x to f . Assume there is a ball of radius B around each point such that for any augmentation x s i of x i x i ? x s i 2 2 ? B. By assumption (A1) we have that f (x i ) ? f (x s i ) 2 2 ? ?. This implies that for points x i and x j such that x i ? x j 2 2 ? 2B, there exists a region of overlap so that f (</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 ? f (x i ) ? f (x s i ) 2 2 + f (x s i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 ? 2?.</formula><p>In practise this says that there are augmentations of x i which are sufficiently similar to augmentations of x j so that their representations should be similar, thereby driving f (x i ) and f (x j ) to be closer.</p><p>The variance of points in f space is</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">? 2 f = 1 2N 2 i j f (x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 The overlap B &lt; x i ? x j 2 2 ? 2B induces a graph where we say j ? N (i) ? j s.t. x i ? x j 2 2 ? 2B.</formula><p>For N samples we can decompose the variance as</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">? 2 f = 1 2N 2 i j f (x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 = 1 2N 2 i j?N (i) f (x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 + j / ?N (i) f (x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2</formula><p>By smoothness of f we always have that have f (</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 ? L x i ? x j 2 2 . By the constraint we have that f (x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 ? 2?L B x i ? x j 2 2 ?j ? N (i) and for ? = 2?L B &lt; 1.</formula><p>Constant proportion overlap. Now, assuming that for each point i there is a constant proportion of the points, 0 ? ? ? 1 in the set N (i) ?i we can obtain the following inequality</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">? 2 f = 1 2N 2 i j f (x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 ? ??? 2 x + (1 ? ?)L? 2 x = (?? + (1 ? ?)L)? 2 x<label>(7)</label></formula><p>For ? 2 f ? ? 2 x we require (?? + (1 ? ?)L) ? 1. Since both terms are positive we separately require (1 ? ?)L ? 1:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">(1 ? ?)L &lt; 1 (1 ? ?) &lt; 1 L ? &gt; (1 ? 1 L )</formula><p>This condition makes sense since the larger ?, the fewer unconnected components in the graph. If the above holds, we also require ? 2?L B &lt; 1 ? (1 ? ?)L to ensure the sum is bounded above by 1. This</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">implies ? &lt; (1?(1??)L)B 2L? .</formula><p>However, ? is a property of the augmentation set and not directly a user-controllable parameter so if ? is too small or the function is not smooth enough, it might not be possible to set ? in such a way to induce contraction in ? 2 f . In the next section we derive a tighter concentration based on the structure of random graphs which are induced by the connectivity between data points and their augmentations.</p><p>Random graphs. Consider the graph G(V, E) induced by the constraints (i, j) ? E ? x i ? x j 2 2 ? 2B. Call N (i) the set of neighbours of point i. For N points, if there is a constant probability ? that j ? N (i) then G N,? is an Erd?s-Renyi graph.</p><p>From Theorem 3, if ? ? c log N N for c &gt; 1 then with high probability, there are no unconnected components in G. That is, every vertex in V is reachable from any other vertex in a finite number of steps. We can then decompose the contribution to the variance in terms of components in the graph that are adjacent and those which are reachable within a certain number of steps.</p><p>Let the degree-the shortest path-between any two points be at most D we obtain the following refinement of eq. (7)</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">? 2 f = 1 2N 2 i j f (x i ) ? f (x j ) 2 2 ? ??? 2 x + (1 ? ?)D?? 2 x</formula><p>From Theorem 4 we have with high probability that 3 ? D ? 4. So for ? 2</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">f ? 1 ? ? 2 x with ? ? 1 we require ? ? B 2L?(?+3(1??)) ? B 6L? .</formula><p>Theorem 3 (Connectedness <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Erd?s &amp; R?nyi, 1960)</ref>). If p = c log n n where c &gt; 1 with high probability then the graph G(n, p) has no unconnected components.</p><p>Definition 1 (Diameter). For a connected graph,</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">G(V, E) the diameter diam(G) = max dist(v i , v j ) where dist(v i , v j )</formula><p>is the minimum number of edges in the path between v i and v j .</p><p>Theorem 4 (Diameter of random graphs <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Frieze &amp; Karo?ski, 2016)</ref>  if D is a set of images of cats and dogs and Y t denotes labels cat and dog, then D is partitioned into two equivalence classes corresponding to cat and dog images by Y t .</p><p>Intuitively, a refinement is a subdivision of an existing partition. For a visualization of a refinement of a set of tasks see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>. To mathematically define refinements, we first need to introduce what it means for an equivalence relation to be finer than another equivalence relation.</p><p>Definition 2. (Fineness). Let ? and ? be two equivalence relations on the set D. If every equivalence class of ? is a subset of an equivalence class of ?, we say that ? is finer than ?.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Now we define what refinements.</head><p>Definition 3. (Refinement). Let A, B be sets of equivalence classes induced by equivalence relations ? and ? over the set D. If ? is finer than ?, then we call A a refinement of B.</p><p>Furthermore, we can relate the corresponding sets of equivalence classes.</p><p>Lemma 2. Let ? and ? be two equivalence relationships on the set D and denote the corresponding induced partitions by A and B. If ? is finer than ?, then every equivalence class of ? is a union of equivalence classes of ?.</p><p>Coming back to the example of cats and dogs, let ? be the relation that associates cats with cats and dogs with dogs. Now the relation ? which associated both cats and dogs with their specific breed (e.g. poodles with other poodles) is finer than ?. Note that ? partitions D into breeds and so we can easily generate the sets of cats and dogs (i.e. equivalence classes of ?) by taking a union over all the corresponding breeds.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D.2 PROOF OF THEOREM 1</head><p>Definition 4. (Invariant Representation). Let X and Y be the covariates and target, respectively. We call f (X) an invariant representation for Y under style S if</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">p do(S=si) (Y | f (X)) = p do(S=sj ) (Y | f (X)) ? s i , s j ? S,<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where do(S = s) denotes assigning S the value s and S is the domain of S.</p><p>Theorem 1. Theorem 1. Let Y = {Y t } T t=1 be a family of downstream tasks. Let Y R be a refinement for all tasks in Y. If f (X) is an invariant representation for Y R under changes in style S, then f (X) is an invariant representation for all tasks in Y under changes in style S, i.e.</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">p do(si) (Y R | f (X)) = p do(sj ) (Y R | f (X)) ? p do(si) (Y t | f (X)) = p do(sj ) (Y t | f (X)) (9)</formula><p>for all t ? {1, . . . , T } and for all s i , s j ? S with p do(si) = p do <ref type="bibr">(S=si)</ref> . Thus, f (X) is a representation that generalizes to Y.</p><p>Proof. Let t ? {1, . . . , T }. We have</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">p do(si) (Y t |f (X)) = p do(si) (Y t |Y R )p do(si) (Y R |f (X))d Y R = p(Y t |Y R )p do(si) (Y R |f (X))d Y R = p(Y t |Y R )p do(sj ) (Y R |f (X))d Y R = p do(sj ) (Y t |f (X)).</formula><p>For the second and last equality, we used that the mechanism of Y t |Y R is independent of S, i.e.</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">p do(si) (Y t |Y R ) = p do(sj ) (Y t |Y R ).</formula><p>The third equality follows from the assumption that f (X) is an invariant representation for Y R under changes in S. Thus, we get that f (X) is an invariant representation for Y t under changes in S. Specifically, for a representation to be an invariant representation for Y t it is a sufficient condition for it to be an invariant representation for Y R .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E EXPERIMENTAL DETAILS E.1 IMAGE AUGMENTATIONS</head><p>For pretraining the representations in RELIC, we apply the augmentation scheme proposed in SimCLR <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2020a)</ref> and used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref>. This consists of the following augmentations applied in the order they are listed ? random crop -we randomly crop the image using an area randomly selected between 8%</p><p>and 100% of the image with an logarithmically sampled aspect ration between 3/4 and 4/3. After this, we resize the patch to 224 ? 224; ? random horizontal flip; ? color jittering -we apply in random order perturbations to brightness, contrast, saturation and hue of the image by shifting them by a random uniform offset; ? grayscale -we randomly apply grayscaling; ? Gaussian blurring -we blur the image using a 23 ? 23 square Gaussian kernel with standard deviation uniformly sampled in [0.1, 0.2]; ? solarization -we transform all the pixels with x ? x * 1 {x&lt;0.5} + (1 ? x) * 1 {x?0.5} .</p><p>We use the same parameters for the augmentations and probabilities of applying individual augmentations as SimCLR <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2020a)</ref>. After applying augmentations, we normalize the images with the mean and standard deviation computed on ImageNet across the color channels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.2 ARCHITECTURE</head><p>We test RELIC on two different architectures -ResNet-50 <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(He et al., 2016)</ref> and ResNet-50 with target network as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref>. For ResNet-50, we use version 1 with post-activation. We take the representation to be the output of the final average pooling layer, which is of dimension 2048. As in SimCLR <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Chen et al., 2020a)</ref>, we use a critic network to project the representation to a lower dimensional space with a multi-layer perceptron (MLP). When using ResNet-50 as encoder, we treat the parameters of the MLP (e.g. depth and width) as hyperparameters and sweep over them. This MLP has batch normalization <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Ioffe &amp; Szegedy, 2015)</ref> after every layer, rectified linear activations (ReLU) <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Nair &amp; Hinton, 2010)</ref>. We used a 4 layer MLP with widths <ref type="bibr">[4096,</ref><ref type="bibr">2048,</ref><ref type="bibr">1024,</ref><ref type="bibr">512]</ref> and output size 128 with ResNet-50. When using a ResNet-50 with target networks as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref>, we exactly follow their architecture settings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.3 OPTIMIZATION</head><p>We use a batch size of 4096 and the LARS optimizer <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(You et al., 2017)</ref> with a cosine decay learning rate schedule <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Loshchilov &amp; Hutter, 2017)</ref> for 1000 epochs with 10 epochs for warm-up. We exclude the biases and batch normalization parameters from LARS adaptation. We use as the base learning rate 0.3 for ResNet-50 and 0.2 for ResNet-50 with target network. We scale this learning rate by batch size/256 and use a global weight decay parameter of 1.5 * 10 ?6 and exclude the biases and batch normalization parameters. For the target network, we follow the approach of BYOL <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref> and start the exponential moving average parameter ? at ? base = 0.996 and increase it to one during training via ? = 1 ? (1 ? ? base )(cos(?k/K) + 1)/2 with k the current training step and K the maximum number of training steps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.4 EVALUATION ON IMAGENET</head><p>We follow the standard linear evaluation protocol on ImageNet as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Kolesnikov et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chen et al., 2020a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Grill et al., 2020)</ref>. We train a linear classifier on top of the fixed representation, i.e. we do not update the network parameters or the batch statistics. For training, we randomly crop and resize images to 224 ? 224, and randomly horizontally flip the images after that. For testing, the images are resized to 256 pixels along the shorter dimension with bicubic resampling after which we take a center crop of size 224 ? 224. Both for training and testing, the images are normalized by substracting the mean and standard deviations across the color channels computed on ImageNet after the augmentations. We use Stochastic Gradient Descent with a Nestorov momentum of 0.9 and train for 80 epochs with a batch size of 1024. We do not use any regularization techniques, e.g. weight decay.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.5 ROBUSTNESS AND GENERALIZATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.5.1 DATASET DETAILS</head><p>ImageNet-C. The ImageNet-C dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hendrycks &amp; Dietterich, 2019)</ref> consists of 15 different types of corruptions from the noise, blur, weather, and digital categories applied to the validation images of ImageNet. This dataset is used for measuring semantic robustness. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> visualizes the corruption types. Each type of corruption has 5 levels of severity, i.e. there are 75 distinct corruptions in the dataset. In <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>, we display the Impulse noise corruption for 5 different severity levels. As can be seen, with increasing severity level the image becomes increasingly corrupted and difficult to parse. In addition to these 75 corruption types, there are an additional 4 corruption types (speckle noise, gaussian blur, spatter and saturate) that are provided as a validation set. We use these additional corruption types for selecting the best hyperparameters. For further details on this dataset, please refer to <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hendrycks &amp; Dietterich, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>ImageNet-R. The ImageNet-R dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Hendrycks et al., 2020)</ref> consists of 30, 000 images depicting various artistic renditions (e.g., paintings, sculpture, origami, cartoon) of 200 ImageNet object classes. This dataset is used to measure out-of-distribution generalization to various abstract visual renditions as it emphasizes shape over texture. The data was collected primarily from Flickr and also includes line drawings from <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Wang et al., 2019)</ref>. The images represent naturally occurring objects and have different textures and local image statistic to those of ImageNet. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 7</ref> visualizes different images from the dataset. For further details on this dataset, please refer to <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Hendrycks et al., 2020)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.5.2 EVALUATION</head><p>To evaluate robustness and generalization of the learned representation, we follow the standard linear evaluation protocol on ImageNet as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Chen et al., 2020b;</ref><ref type="bibr">a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Kolesnikov et al., 2019)</ref>. We train a linear classifier on top of the frozen representation, i.e. we do not update either the network parameters nor the batch statistics. During training, we augment the data by randomly cropping, resizing to 224 ? 224 and randomly flipping the image. At test time, images are resized to 256 pixels along the shorter side via bicubic resampling and we take a 224 ? 224 center crop. Both during training and testing, after applying augmentations we normalize the color channels by subtracting the average color and dividing by the standard deviation that is computed on ImageNet. We optimize the cross-entropy loss using Stochastic Gradient Descent with Nestorov momentum of 0.9. We sweep over number for epochs {30, 50, 60, 90}, learning rates {0.4, 0.3, 0.2, 0.1, 0.05, 0.01} and batch sizes {1024, 2048, 4096}. We select hyperparameters on the validation set provided in ImageNet-C and report the performance on ImageNet-R and on the test set of ImageNet-C under the best validation hyperparameters. We do not use any regularization techniques such as weight decay, gradient clipping, tanh clipping or logits regularization.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.5.3 ROBUSTNESS METRICS AND FURTHER RESULTS</head><p>Let f be a classifier that has not been trained on ImageNet-C. For each corruption type c and level of severity 1 ? s ? 5, denote the top-1 error of this classifier as E f s,c . Different corruption types pose different levels of difficulty. To make error rates across corruption types more comparable, the     For our experiments on Atari, we use the agent from R2D2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kapturowski et al., 2019)</ref> with standard hyperparameters noted below. We train each agent on approximately 15 billion frames and add a second encoder with the same architecture used in the Q-Network of the original agent. This second encoder is trained with a separate optimizer with only a representation learning objective. The agent then takes the output of this encoder as a given input. We use standard augmentations used in prior work <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kostrikov et al., 2020)</ref> where we pad the frames on all sides with 4 pixels copied from the borders and then randomly cropping 84 windows. We randomly shift pixel intensity according to the distribution s = 1.0 + 0.1 * N where N is the standard Normal distribution with values clipped between -2 and 2. s is then multiplied by the original image to return the augmented image.</p><p>RELIC and SimCLR For our implementation of RELIC and SimCLR, we do not use a critic embedding at all and utilize the last layer of the encoder for the objective. As in CURL <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Srinivas et al., 2020)</ref> we utilize a target encoder for the second augmentation where we update the weights with a momentum of .99. We also clipped the gradients of our optimizer using a global norm ratio of 40. We report the hyperparameters in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 8</ref>. CURL For CURL, we use a second encoder as noted before. With the exception of the encoder architecture and the optimizer parameters, all hyperparameters are the same as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Srinivas et al., 2020)</ref> including the momentum value for the target network weight updates. We utilize the same architecture in the paper with a linear layer as a critic embedding for the target encoder. BYOL In BYOL, we utilize two-layer perceptron networks as our predictor and projection layers. For both networks, the number of hidden units in the two layers was 1024 and 512. We use a target network update momentum of .99. The optimizer parameters are the same as in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 8</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Direct Augmentation</head><p>We also compared against direct augmentation of the observations in the replay buffer as in DrQ <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kostrikov et al., 2020)</ref>. We keep the architecture the same in this instance and use two duplicate encoders as input to the agent. In this case, the optimizer can jointly update both encoders and train them end-to-end.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>(a) Causal graph formalizing assumptions about content and style of the data and the relationship between targets and proxy tasks. (b) RELIC objective. KL refers to the Kullback-Leibler divergence, while x-entropy denotes cross entropy.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Distribution of the linear discriminant ratio (F LDA , see text) of f for RELIC, SimCLR and AMDIM (y-axis clipped to aid visualization).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Visual representation of invariance penalty. Shaded region denotes set of augmentations around an image.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the mean of representations corresponding to class c. Further, let L ? ?(f ),sup (f ) use the the hinge loss with margin ?(f ) = 1 + c M ? f ( ? k + log M ) with c constant and M = max x f (x). Iff is the minimizer of eq. (5) and if Assumptions (A1) and (A2) hold then with high probabilityL ? sup (f ) ? ?(f )L ? ?(f ),sup (f ) + Gen N +(6)Here, Gen N is a standard generalization bound which depends on the Rademacher complexity of the function class F and the sample size, N .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>.Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Let d ? 2 be a fixed positive integer. For c &gt; 0 and p d n d?1 = log(n 2 /c) Then diam(G n,p ) ? d with probability exp(?c/2) and diam(G n,p ) ? d + 1 with probability 1 ? exp(?c/2). D GENERALIZING CONTRASTIVE LEARNING D.1 REFINEMENTS On the unsupervised observed data D, any task as defined by targets Y t induces an equivalence relation, i.e. Y t partitions D into equivalence classes. It divides D based on values of the target, D = {{x a |y a = y i } M i=1 } where {y 1 , . . . , y M } for some M is the set of target values.Here the equivalence relation associates datapoints based on the value of the target they predict. For example, Visualization of a refinement of a set of tasks. The tasks are to classify aquatic vs nonaquatic life and animal vs non-animal with the individual class boundaries denoted by the dashed and dotted black lines. A refinement for these tasks is a to classify aquatic animal vs aquatic non-animal vs non-aquatic animal vs non-aquatic non-animal and the class boundaries are given in teal. The ellipse indicates the set of points induced by augmenting the image of the ship.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 :Figure 6 :</head><label>56</label><figDesc>The ImageNet-C dataset consists of 15 types of corruptions from noise, blur, weather, and digital categories. Each type of corruption has five levels of severity, resulting in 75 distinct corruptions. See different severity levels inFigure 6The 5 different levels of severity of Impulse noise corruption available in the ImageNet-C dataset. With increasing severity the dog image is markedly corrupted.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Example images from the dataset ImageNet-R which contains 30, 000 images of 200 ImageNet classes. This dataset emphasizes shape over texture and has different textures and local image statistic to those of ImageNet.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>error</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Accuracy (in %) under linear evaluation on Ima-geNet for different self-supervised representation learning methods. Methods with * use SimCLR augmentations. Methods with ? use custom, stronger augmentations.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Top-1 error rates for different self-supervised representation learning methods on ImageNet-R. All models are trained only on clean ImageNet images and RELIC</figDesc><table><row><cell>)</cell></row></table><note>T refers to RELIC using a ResNet-50 with target network as in BYOL (Grill et al., 2020). Method Supervised SimCLR RELIC (ours) BYOL RELIC T (ours</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Mean Corruption Error (mCE), mean relative Corruption Error (mrCE) and Corruption Errors for the "Noise" class of corruptions (Gaussian, Shot, Impulse) on ImageNet-C. The mCE value is the average across 75 different corruptions. Methods are trained only on clean ImageNet images.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Method</cell><cell cols="5">mCE mrCE Gaussian Shot Impulse</cell></row><row><cell>Supervised</cell><cell cols="2">76.7 105.0</cell><cell>80.0</cell><cell>82.0</cell><cell>83.0</cell></row><row><cell>ResNet-50 architecture:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>SimCLR</cell><cell cols="2">87.5 111.9</cell><cell>79.4</cell><cell>81.9</cell><cell>89.6</cell></row><row><cell>ReLIC (ours)</cell><cell>76.4</cell><cell>87.7</cell><cell>67.8</cell><cell>70.7</cell><cell>77.0</cell></row><row><cell>ResNet-50 with target network:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>BYOL</cell><cell>72.3</cell><cell>90.0</cell><cell>65.9</cell><cell>68.4</cell><cell>73.7</cell></row><row><cell>ReLIC (ours)</cell><cell>70.8</cell><cell>88.4</cell><cell>63.6</cell><cell>65.7</cell><cell>69.2</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Human Normalized Scores over 57 Atari Games.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Atari Performance</cell><cell cols="3">RELIC SimCLR CURL</cell><cell cols="2">BYOL Augmentation</cell></row><row><cell>Capped mean</cell><cell>91.46</cell><cell>88.76</cell><cell>90.72</cell><cell>89.43</cell><cell>80.60</cell></row><row><cell>Number of superhuman games</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>34</cell></row><row><cell>Mean</cell><cell cols="4">3003.73 2086.16 2413.12 1769.43</cell><cell>503.15</cell></row><row><cell>Median</cell><cell>832.50</cell><cell>592.83</cell><cell>819.56</cell><cell>483.39</cell><cell>132.17</cell></row><row><cell>40% Percentile</cell><cell>356.27</cell><cell>266.07</cell><cell>409.46</cell><cell>224.80</cell><cell>94.35</cell></row><row><cell>30% Percentile</cell><cell>202.49</cell><cell>174.19</cell><cell>190.96</cell><cell>150.21</cell><cell>80.04</cell></row><row><cell>20% Percentile</cell><cell>133.93</cell><cell>120.84</cell><cell>126.10</cell><cell>118.36</cell><cell>57.95</cell></row><row><cell>10% Percentile</cell><cell>83.79</cell><cell>37.19</cell><cell>59.09</cell><cell>44.14</cell><cell>32.74</cell></row><row><cell>5% Percentile</cell><cell>20.87</cell><cell>12.74</cell><cell>20.56</cell><cell>7.75</cell><cell>2.85</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>rates are divided by AlexNet's errors. This standardized measure is the Corruption Error and is computed as , to normalize the Corruption Error values -Gaussian Noise 88.6%, Shot Noise 89.4%, Impulse Noise 92.3%, Defocus Blur 82.0%, Glass Blur 82.6%, Motion Blur 78.6%, Zoom Blur 79.8%, Snow 86.7%, Frost 82.7%, Fog 81.9%, Brightness 56.5%, Contrast 85.3%, Elastic Transformation 64.6%, Pixelate 71.8%, JPEG 60.7%, Speckle Noise 84.5%, Gaussian Blur 78.7%, Spatter 71.8%, Saturate 65.8%.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Mean Corruption Error (mCE) and Corruption Error values for Blur, Weather, and Digital corruption types on ImageNet-C. All models are trained only using clean ImageNet images.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Blur</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Weather</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Digital</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Method</cell><cell cols="13">mCE Defocus Glass Motion Zoom Snow Frost Fog Bright Contrast Elastic Pixel JPEG</cell></row><row><cell>Supervised</cell><cell>76.7</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>78</cell><cell>80</cell><cell>78</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>66</cell><cell>57</cell><cell>71</cell><cell>85</cell><cell>77</cell><cell>77</cell></row><row><cell>Using ResNet-50:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>SimCLR</cell><cell>87.5</cell><cell>94.8</cell><cell>103.3</cell><cell>101.8</cell><cell>101.9</cell><cell>83.7</cell><cell cols="2">80.6 65.6</cell><cell>71.5</cell><cell>54</cell><cell cols="2">106.8 105.2</cell><cell>93</cell></row><row><cell>ReLIC (ours)</cell><cell>76.4</cell><cell>81.4</cell><cell>96.9</cell><cell>92.7</cell><cell>93.2</cell><cell>73.7</cell><cell cols="2">71.2 54.5</cell><cell>60.2</cell><cell>46.9</cell><cell>97.4</cell><cell>85.5</cell><cell>77.2</cell></row><row><cell>ResNet-50 with target network:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>BYOL</cell><cell>72.3</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>93.6</cell><cell>86.3</cell><cell>87.9</cell><cell>74.3</cell><cell cols="2">69.1 48.5</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>48.6</cell><cell>90.4</cell><cell>74.3</cell><cell>73</cell></row><row><cell>ReLIC (ours)</cell><cell>70.8</cell><cell>73.2</cell><cell>94</cell><cell>81.9</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>73.2</cell><cell>68</cell><cell>47.5</cell><cell>54.2</cell><cell>48.4</cell><cell>89.5</cell><cell>75.6</cell><cell>71.8</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Mean relative Corruption Error (mrCE) and relative Corruption Error values for different corruptions and methods on ImageNet-C. The mrCE value is the mean relative Corruption Error of the corruptions in Noise, Blur, Weather, and Digital columns. All models are trained only using clean ImageNet images. RELIC-t denotes using RELIC with a ResNet-50+target network architecture as in BYOL<ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Grill et al., 2020)</ref>.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Noise</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Blur</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Weather</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Digital</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Method</cell><cell cols="16">mrCE Gauss. Shot Impulse Defocus Glass Motion Zoom Snow Frost Fog Bright Contrast Elastic Pixel JPEG</cell></row><row><cell>Supervised</cell><cell>105</cell><cell>104</cell><cell>107</cell><cell>107</cell><cell>97</cell><cell>126</cell><cell>107</cell><cell>110</cell><cell>101</cell><cell>97</cell><cell>79</cell><cell>62</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>146</cell><cell>111</cell><cell>132</cell></row><row><cell>Using ResNet-50:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>SimCLR</cell><cell>111.9</cell><cell>88</cell><cell>92.7</cell><cell>106.6</cell><cell>122.2</cell><cell>139.6</cell><cell>140.5</cell><cell>139.4</cell><cell>96.9</cell><cell cols="2">91.6 59.9</cell><cell>74.8</cell><cell>36.7</cell><cell cols="3">181.5 158.3 149.8</cell></row><row><cell>ReLIC (ours)</cell><cell>87.7</cell><cell>67.3</cell><cell>73.1</cell><cell>84.8</cell><cell>96.1</cell><cell>128.7</cell><cell>123</cell><cell>123.1</cell><cell>79.3</cell><cell cols="2">74.4 38.9</cell><cell>33.4</cell><cell>24.6</cell><cell>157.5</cell><cell>112</cell><cell>99.8</cell></row><row><cell>ResNet-50 with target network:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>BYOL</cell><cell>90</cell><cell>72.5</cell><cell>77.2</cell><cell>86.7</cell><cell>93</cell><cell>132</cell><cell>120</cell><cell>122.5</cell><cell>89.7</cell><cell cols="2">80.2 36.6</cell><cell>41.5</cell><cell>37.8</cell><cell>155</cell><cell cols="2">97.6 108.4</cell></row><row><cell>ReLIC (ours)</cell><cell>88.4</cell><cell>69.1</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>79.2</cell><cell>90.4</cell><cell>134.2</cell><cell>111.6</cell><cell>121.9</cell><cell>88.5</cell><cell cols="2">79.2 35.6</cell><cell>41.7</cell><cell>38.5</cell><cell cols="3">154.5 102.7 106.8</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">E.6 EVALUATION ON ATARI</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>RELIC and SimCLR Details</figDesc><table><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>Value</cell></row><row><cell>Normalize Inputs</cell><cell>True</cell></row><row><cell>Temperature</cell><cell>1.0 Constant</cell></row><row><cell>Scaling of Embeddings</cell><cell>False</cell></row><row><cell>Optimizer</cell><cell>Adam</cell></row><row><cell>Learning Rate</cell><cell>5e-4</cell></row><row><cell>Epsilon</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>Beta 1</cell><cell>0.9</cell></row><row><cell>Beta 2</cell><cell>0.999</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table 9</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">: CURL Details</cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>Value</cell></row><row><cell>Optimizer</cell><cell>Adam</cell></row><row><cell>Learning Rate</cell><cell>1e-3</cell></row><row><cell>Epsilon</cell><cell>0.01</cell></row><row><cell>Beta 1</cell><cell>0.9</cell></row><row><cell>Beta 2</cell><cell>0.999</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">See<ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Peters et al., 2017)</ref> for a review of causal graphs and causality. 2 Since neither content nor style are a priori known, choosing a set of augmentations implicitly defines which aspects of the data are considered style and which are content.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Note that since refinements are more fine-grained that the original task, if a representation captures a refinement then it also captures the downstream tasks as strictly more information is needed to solve the refinement.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">The set of augmentations includes Gaussian blurring, various colour distortions, flips and random cropping.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Acknowledgements. We thank David Balduzzi, Melanie Rey, Christina Heinze-Deml, Ilja Kuzborskij, Ali Eslami, Jeffrey de Fauw and Josip Djolonga for invaluable discussions.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning representations by maximizing mutual information across views</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Bachman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Devon</forename><surname>Hjelm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Buchwalter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15509" to="15519" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The arcade learning environment: An evaluation platform for general agents (extended abstract)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Marc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yavar</forename><surname>Bellemare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Naddaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Veness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bowling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Artif. Intell. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="279" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Unsupervised learning of visual features by contrasting cluster assignments. ArXiv, abs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Caron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mairal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Priya</forename><surname>Goyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bojanowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Armand</forename><surname>Joulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Krzysztof</forename><surname>Chalupka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pietro</forename><surname>Perona</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frederick</forename><surname>Eberhardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1412.2309</idno>
		<title level="m">Visual causal feature learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A simple framework for contrastive learning of visual representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Kornblith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Norouzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2002.05709</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Improved baselines with momentum contrastive learning. ArXiv, abs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xinlei</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haoqi</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ross</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Girshick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaiming</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the evolution of random graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Erd?s</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alfr?d</forename><surname>R?nyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Publ. Math. Inst. Hung. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Springer series in statistics New York</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerome</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Hastie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Tibshirani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The elements of statistical learning</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to random graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Frieze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Micha?</forename><surname>Karo?ski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain adaptation with conditional transferable components</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingming</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kun</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tongliang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dacheng</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clark</forename><surname>Glymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Sch?lkopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International conference on machine learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2839" to="2848" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bootstrap your own latent: A new approach to self-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Bastien</forename><surname>Grill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Strub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florent</forename><surname>Altch?</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Corentin</forename><surname>Tallec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pierre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Richemond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carl</forename><surname>Buchatskaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Doersch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhaohan</forename><forename type="middle">Daniel</forename><surname>Avila Pires</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><forename type="middle">Gheshlaghi</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Azar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2006.07733</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noise-contrastive estimation: A new estimation principle for unnormalized statistical models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Gutmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aapo</forename><surname>Hyv?rinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Thirteenth International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics</title>
		<meeting>the Thirteenth International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="304" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensionality reduction by learning an invariant mapping</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raia</forename><surname>Hadsell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Chopra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yann</forename><surname>Lecun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR&apos;06)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1735" to="1742" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep residual learning for image recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaiming</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiangyu</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shaoqing</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="770" to="778" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Momentum contrast for unsupervised visual representation learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaiming</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haoqi</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuxin</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saining</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ross</forename><surname>Girshick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1911.05722</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Heinze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Deml</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolai</forename><surname>Meinshausen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1710.11469</idno>
		<title level="m">Conditional variance penalties and domain shift robustness</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>H?naff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carl</forename><surname>Razavi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Doersch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Sm Eslami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Den Oord</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1905.09272</idno>
		<title level="m">Data-efficient image recognition with contrastive predictive coding</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Benchmarking neural network robustness to common corruptions and perturbations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Hendrycks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Dietterich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Learning Representations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The many faces of robustness: A critical analysis of out-of-distribution generalization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Hendrycks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Basart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norman</forename><surname>Mu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saurav</forename><surname>Kadavath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evan</forename><surname>Dorundo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rahul</forename><surname>Desai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tyler</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samyak</forename><surname>Parajuli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2006.16241</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning deep representations by mutual information estimation and maximization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>R Devon Hjelm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><surname>Fedorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karan</forename><surname>Lavoie-Marchildon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phil</forename><surname>Grewal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Bachman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Trischler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1808.06670</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Batch normalization: Accelerating deep network training by reducing internal covariate shift</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ioffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Szegedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1502.03167</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ArXiv</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Recurrent experience replay in distributed reinforcement learning. Iclr</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Kapturowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georg</forename><surname>Ostrovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Dabney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Quan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Remi</forename><surname>Munos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting self-supervised visual representation learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kolesnikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaohua</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucas</forename><surname>Beyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1920" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Image augmentation is all you need: Regularizing deep reinforcement learning from pixels</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Kostrikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Denis</forename><surname>Yarats</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Fergus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2004.13649</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sgdr: Stochastic gradient descent with warm restarts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Loshchilov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hutter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICLR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-supervised learning of pretext-invariant representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ishan</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurens</forename><surname>Van Der Maaten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6707" to="6717" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rectified linear units improve restricted boltzmann machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Van Den Oord</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yazhe</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oriol</forename><surname>Vinyals</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1807.03748</idno>
		<title level="m">Representation learning with contrastive predictive coding</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judea</forename><surname>Pearl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Causality</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Cambridge university press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causal inference by using invariant prediction: identification and confidence intervals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonas</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>B?hlmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolai</forename><surname>Meinshausen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series B (Statistical Methodology)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="947" to="1012" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Elements of causal inference: foundations and learning algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonas</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominik</forename><surname>Janzing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Sch?lkopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>MIT press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On variational bounds of mutual information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Poole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sherjil</forename><surname>Ozair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Van Den</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Oord</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Alemi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5171" to="5180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Imagenet large scale visual recognition challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olga</forename><surname>Russakovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Satheesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiheng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Karpathy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khosla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bernstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Berg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Fei-Fei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theoretical analysis of contrastive unsupervised representation learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikunj</forename><surname>Saunshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Orestis</forename><surname>Plevrakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjeev</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mikhail</forename><surname>Khodak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hrishikesh</forename><surname>Khandeparkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5628" to="5637" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aravind</forename><surname>Srinivas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Laskin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pieter</forename><surname>Abbeel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2004.04136</idno>
		<title level="m">Curl: Contrastive unsupervised representations for reinforcement learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yonglong</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilip</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phillip</forename><surname>Isola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1906.05849</idno>
		<title level="m">Contrastive multiview coding</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What makes for good views for contrastive learning. ArXiv, abs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yonglong Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilip</forename><surname>Poole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phillip</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Isola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On mutual information maximization for representation learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Tschannen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josip</forename><surname>Djolonga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylvain</forename><surname>Paul K Rubenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mario</forename><surname>Gelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lucic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1907.13625</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning robust global representations by penalizing local predictive power. ArXiv, abs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haohan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Songwei Ge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zachary</forename><forename type="middle">Chase</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lipton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1905" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Table 10: Individual Mean Episode Return on Atari</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>You</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Igor</forename><surname>Gitman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boris</forename><surname>Ginsburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1708.03888</idno>
		<idno>4336.90 -17098.10 -24761.06 -23076.73 -15497.66 -26028.08 -22162.91 solaris 12326.70</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
	<note>Large batch training of convolutional networks</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
