<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">(0,2) MIRROR SYMMETRY ON HOMOGENEOUS HOPF SURFACES</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2021-01">Jan 2021</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andoni</forename><surname>Luis?lvarez-C?nsul</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arriba</forename><surname>De</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>De</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>AND</roleName><forename type="first">Mario</forename><surname>Hera</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Garcia-Fernandez</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">(0,2) MIRROR SYMMETRY ON HOMOGENEOUS HOPF SURFACES</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
							<date type="published" when="2021-01">Jan 2021</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2022-11-11T21:32+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this work we find the first examples of (0,2) mirror symmetry on compact non-K?hler complex manifolds. For this we follow Borisov's approach to mirror symmetry using vertex algebras and the chiral de Rham complex. Our examples of (0,2) mirrors are given by pairs of Hopf surfaces endowed with a Bismut-flat pluriclosed metric. Requiring that the geometry is homogeneous, we reduce the problem to the study of Killing spinors on a quadratic Lie algebra and the construction of associated N = 2 superconformal structures on the superaffine vertex algebra, combined with topological T-duality.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Shortly after the discovery of mirror symmetry in string theory, physicists realized that this duality extends to a class of superconformal field theories dubbed (0,2)-models <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[62]</ref>. Unlike the more familiar story for algebraic Calabi-Yau manifolds, the geometric content of these models is given by a pair (X, E), where X is a Calabi-Yau threefold and E is a stable holomorphic vector bundle over X satisfying c 1 (E) = 0, ch 2 (E) = ch 2 (X).</p><p>Such pairs are supposed to be exchanged under (0,2)-mirror symmetry, in a way that some of the features of the standard picture are recovered when E = T X <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[48,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">51]</ref>. For a general E, however, (0, 2) mirror symmetry should be very different <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">49]</ref> to the exchange of the A-model with the B-model in the homological or SYZ versions of mirror symmetry <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">58]</ref>.</p><p>At this point a natural question is forced upon us: what is (0, 2) mirror symmetry? An important motivation for this question came with the observation that (0, 2) models have associated chiral rings <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> which generalize the quantum cohomology ring of a symplectic manifold. There has been some direct attempts to understand this picture in the mathematics literature with the aid of toric geometry <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>, but the story is far from being complete at the present moment. These mathematical advances provide underpinnings for the half-twisted model associated to a (0, 2)-theory [61] -a closely-related but simpler theory which plays a similar role to that of the A and B models in mirror symmetry. According to Witten <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[61]</ref>, (0, 2) mirror symmetry exchanges the half-twisted model of (X, E) with the half-twisted model of its mirror and therefore it has the potential to provide an indirect method to understand the chiral rings <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[50]</ref>. This alternative should run parallel Partially supported by the Spanish Ministry of Science and Innovation, through the 'Severo Ochoa Programme for Centres of Excellence in R&amp;D' (SEV-2015-0554 and CEX2019-000904-S), and grant MTM2016-81048-P. The first author is partially supported by MICINN under grant PID2019-109339GB-C31. The second author is partially supported by MICINN under grant BES-2017-080578. The second and third authors are partially supported by MICINN under grants PID2019-109339GA-C32 and <ref type="bibr">EUR2020-112265.</ref> to the classical prediction on the number of fixed-degree rational curves on the quintic Calabi-Yau threefold, by Candelas, De la Ossa, Green, and Parkes <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>.</p><p>The construction of the chiral ring in <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> is based on a general approach to mirror symmetry using vertex algebras by Borisov <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, which is well-suited for understanding certain aspects of (0, 2) mirror symmetry. The idea is that, even though the notion of superconformal field theory which underlies mirror symmetry is not yet properly axiomatized, part of the structure of such a theory is a vertex algebra with an N = 2 superconformal structure, which does have a rigorous mathematical meaning <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref> (see Section 3.1). The most basic features of this algebraic object are a vector superspace V and four quantum fields</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">L, J, G + , G ? ? End V [[z ?1 ]],</formula><p>whose Fourier modes satisfy suitable commutation relations (see <ref type="bibr">Example 3.2)</ref>. In this algebraic set-up, (0, 2) mirror symmetry is expected to be an isomorphism of the vertex algebras corresponding to the (0, 2) models of (X, E) and its mirror (X,?), which flips the N = 2 superconformal structures via the mirror involution</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">L ??L, J ?? ??, G ? ??? ? . (1.1)</formula><p>The general procedure whereby we associate an N = 2 superconformal structure to a pair (X, E) is not known at present, but it is expected to involve the construction of certain global sections on the (twisted) chiral de Rham complex <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30]</ref>, a sheaf of vertex algebras on a smooth manifold introduced by Malikov, Schechtman and Vaintrob. In relation to (0, 2) models, it was proved by Witten that the cohomology of the holomorphic chiral de Rham complex is related in perturbation theory to the chiral algebra of the half-twisted theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[63]</ref> (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>).</p><p>There has been some progress in Borisov's Programme in recent years, mainly due to the work of Heluani, Kac, and their collaborators <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35]</ref>, but this proposal is far from being complete: even for the case of algebraic Calabi-Yau manifolds, the construction of N = 2 structures on the chiral de Rham complex often involves the SU(n)-holonomy metric provided by Yau's theorem, which we do not know explicitly. For the case of pairs (X, E) the replacement of the metric is expected to be a solution of the Hull-Strominger system <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">57]</ref>, a fully non-linear system of partial differential equations about which we know very little at present. A novel feature of the solutions of the Hull-Strominger system is that they involve non-K?hler metrics which often admit continuous isometry groups, due to the presence of torsion. Over the years, this has led to the construction of large classes of examples on non-K?hler Calabi-Yau manifolds with an explicit description of the metric (see e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">52]</ref>). Thus, non-K?hler geometry provides a promising scenario for understanding the vertex algebra approach to (0, 2) mirror symmetry. Using the methods from <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>, first candidates of (0, 2) mirrors on compact non-K?hler manifolds have been recently constructed by the third author in <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref> via T-duality.</p><p>Even though the bundle E allows for symmetries, it also carries all sorts of additional difficulties compared to the standard Calabi-Yau case <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">53]</ref>. According to physicists, one way to have non-vanishing torsion in the absence of E is to add singularities to the solutions caused by the back-reaction of the geometry when a brane is in place. A famous example is the heterotic string soliton constructed by Callan, Harvey, and Strominger <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> on the non-compact manifold</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">X = C 2 \{0},</formula><p>corresponding to a NS5-brane located at the origin. Near an asymptotic S 3 with flux ? ? N surrounding the fivebrane (the throat of a semi-wormhole) we find a familiar non-K?hler metric: a Bismut-flat pluriclosed hermitian metric. Taking the quotient by a radial Z-action we obtain a compact Hopf surface X with a preferred geometry.</p><p>Inspired by this, in the present work we find the first examples of (0, 2) mirror symmetry on compact non-K?hler complex manifolds using vertex algebras. Our examples of (0, 2) mirrors in Theorem 4.18 are given by pairs of Hopf surfaces endowed with a Bismut-flat pluriclosed metric. The quantity ? is realized as the cohomology class of the torsion of the hermitian metric on the underlying smooth manifold, which remains fixed</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">[H ? ] = ? ? H 3 (S 3 ? S 1 , R) ? = R. (1.2)</formula><p>We will show that (0,2)-mirror symmetry exchanges the complex structure on X with the Aeppli class of the pluriclosed metric of the mirrorX, and viceversa (see <ref type="bibr">Proposition 4.13)</ref>. This phenomenon is strongly reminiscent of the rotation of the Hodge diamond on mirror symmetry for algebraic Calabi-Yau manifolds. More importantly, in Theorem 4.21 we consider an S 1 -equivariant version of the half-twisted model ? ch X (Q ? ) T 1 following <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46]</ref>, and prove that (0, 2) mirror symmetry yields an isomorphism in our examples</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">? ch X (Q ? ) T 1 ? = ? c? X (Q ? ) T 1 . (1.3)</formula><p>The identity is remarkable, as it gives an isomorphism of holomorphic sheaves of SUSY vertex algebras over different complex manifolds. It shall be compared with a fundamental result of Borisov and Libgober <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>, which matches the elliptic genera of a Calabi-Yau hypersurface on a Fano toric manifold with the one of its mirror.</p><p>The study of (0, 2) models on Hopf surfaces goes back to Witten <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[63]</ref>. Our result confirms physical expectations about mirror symmetry for these models <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[59]</ref>. For the latest developments on (0, 2) mirror symmetry in relation to Landau-Ginzburg models, we refer to <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31]</ref> and references therein. Alternative proposals to extend mirror symmetry to non-K?hler complex manifolds are due to Lau, Tseng, and Yau <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[44]</ref>, Aldi and Heluani <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, Popovici <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[54]</ref>, and Auroux and Ward <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">60]</ref>.</p><p>Outline of the paper. Our construction is a round trip, from geometry to algebra and back, and has independent interest in the field of vertex algebras. We start by regarding a Bismut-flat pluriclosed hermitian metric as a solution of the Killing spinor equations D S + ? ? = 0, / D + ? = 0, <ref type="bibr">(1.4)</ref> on an exact Courant algebroid over S 3 ? S 1 with?evera class (1.2) (see <ref type="bibr">Proposition 4.6)</ref>. These are universal equations for a generalized metric, a divergence operator, and a spinor on a Courant algebroid, introduced in <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24]</ref>. Their solutions encompass special holonomy metrics with solutions of the Hull-Strominger system, and are motivated by similar equations in supergravity <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>. Identifying S 3 ? S 1 with the compact Lie group K = SU(2) ? U(1) <ref type="bibr">(1.5)</ref> and requiring that the solutions are left-invariant, we identify the Killing spinor equations with analogue equations on a Courant algebroid over a point, that is, a quadratic Lie algebra g (see <ref type="bibr">Proposition 4.5)</ref>.</p><p>Basic features of the Killing spinor equations (1.4) on a quadratic Lie algebra g are studied in Section 2. In Section 3, we prove two main results concerning the construction of N = 2 superconformal structures from Killing spinors in the universal superaffine vertex algebra associated to a quadratic Lie algebra (see <ref type="bibr">Example 3.5)</ref>. For this, we assume that the rank of the generalized metric on g is even (dim V + = 2n), and characterize the Killing spinor equations in terms of natural conditions for a decomposition</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">g = V + ? V ? = l ? l ? V ?</formula><p>and a divergence ? ? l ? l (see <ref type="bibr">Proposition 2.19)</ref>. Here, l, l are isotropic and (l ? l) ? = V ? . The resulting F -term and D-term equations</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">[l, l] ? l, [l, l] ? l, [? j , ? j ] = ? l ? ? l (1.6)</formula><p>make sense over an arbitrary closed field, and are reminiscent of similar conditions which appear in supersymmetric field theories in theoretical physics <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. Here, ? j , ? j form an isotropic basis of l ? l. In this generality, in Theorem 3.13 we prove that a solution of (1.6) satisfying a technical condition (2.41) induces an embbeding of the N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra with central charge c = 3 dim l into the superaffine vertex algebra associated to g with level 0 = k ? C. This result generalizes a construction by Getzler for Manin triples <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref> (see <ref type="bibr">Remark 3.14)</ref>. In our second main result (Theorem 3.16), we construct an analogue embedding with central charge</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">c = 3 dim l + 12 k (?|?) (1.7)</formula><p>for solutions of (1.6) such that ? is holomorphic (Definition 2.25). We expect similar results for the cases dim V + ? {4k, 7, 8}, in relation to other interesting vertex algebras in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35]</ref> (see Remark 2.15 and Section 4.5).</p><p>Back to the geometry, in Section 4.2 we construct a family of left-invariant solutions of the Killing spinor equations on the group manifold K (see <ref type="bibr">Lemma 4.8)</ref>. Applying Theorem 3.16, in Proposition 4.17 we show that any element in the family induces an embedding of the N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra with central charge c = 6 + 6/? on the global sections of the (twisted) chiral de Rham complex. The construction of (0, 2) mirrors in Theorem 4.18 requires the application of topological T-duality <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>, combined with Linshaw-Mathai's chiral version of the Cavalcanti-Gualtieri isomorphism <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46]</ref>, which realizes the mirror involution (1.1). The identification of the equivariant half-twisted models for (0, 2) mirrors is established in Theorem 4.21, following closely <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>. Finally, in Section 4.5 we discuss an application of Theorem 3.13 to the construction of an explicit twoparameter family of N = 4 superconformal vertex algebras with central charge c = 6. Our construction seems to be related to a N = 4 superconformal algebra originally discovered by Sevrin, Troost and Van Proeyen <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[56]</ref> (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>), but we have not been able to find a precise match.</p><p>aim of this section is to introduce a notion of metric with parallel spinor on the quadratic Lie algebra (g, (?|?)), which we will use for our applications to vertex algebras in Section 3.</p><p>To define this notion, we will view the quadratic Lie algebra as a Courant algebroids over a point, and then follow closely <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>.</p><p>We start by considering the relevant notions of metric and connection in our setup.</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">Definition 2.1. A generalized metric on g is an orthogonal decomposition g = V + ? V ? ,</formula><p>so that the restriction of (?|?) to V ? is non-degenerate. We say that a generalized metric is Riemannian if (?|?) |V + is positive-definite and (?|?) |V ? is negative-definite.</p><p>In the sequel we will only consider Riemannian metrics, but a similar analysis can be carried out in other signatures. Observe that a generalized metric is uniquely determined by a choice of positive definite subspace V + ? g. Given such a generalized metric, the associated orthogonal projections will be denoted</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">? + : g ?? V + , ? ? : g ?? V ? .</formula><p>When there is no possibility of confusion, we will use the shorter notation a ? = ? ? a, for a ? g.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">Definition 2.2. A generalized connection on g is a linear map D : g ? g * ? g,</formula><p>satisfying the following compatibility condition for any a, b, c ? g:</p><p>(D a b|c) + (b|D a c) = 0.</p><p>In Definition 2.2, the notation D a b stands for the element in g obtained from a and Db via the natural duality pairing g ? g * ? R.</p><p>The space of generalized connections on g can be canonically identified with g * ? ? 2 g, via the pairing (?|?) on g. As in the case of differential geometry, given a generalized metric V + ? g, we can define a natural space of V + -compatible generalized connections.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">Definition 2.3. Let V + ? g be a generalized metric. A generalized connection D is V + -compatible if D(V ? ) ? g * ? V ? . The space of V + -compatible connections will be denoted by D(V + ).</formula><p>Similarly as with generalized connections, there is a canonical identification</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">D(V + ) = g * ? (? 2 V + ? ? 2 V ? ), so any D ? D(V + ) splits into four operators D + ? ? V * ? ? ? 2 V + , D ? + ? V * + ? ? 2 V ? , D + + ? V * + ? ? 2 V + , D ? ? ? V * ? ? ? 2 V ? . (2.1)</formula><p>In order to construct operators canonically associated to a generalized metric, we recall next the definition of torsion for generalized connections <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32]</ref>.</p><p>Definition 2.4. Given a generalized connection D, its torsion T D ? ? 3 g * is defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">T D (a, b, c) = (D a b ? D b a ? [a, b]|c) + (D c a|b), (2.2)</formula><p>for any a, b, c ? g.</p><p>The fact that T D is totally skew-symmetric follows from the axioms of a quadratic Lie algebra and the compatibility between D and (?|?) (Definition 2.2).</p><p>Given a generalized metric V + ? g, we will denote by</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">D 0 (V + ) = {D ? D(V + ) | T D = 0}</formula><p>the space of torsion-free compatible connections. This is an affine space modelled on</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">? + ? ? ? where ? ? = ? ? ? ? ? (V * ? ) ?3 : ?(a, b, c) = ??(a, c, b), ?(a,b,c) ?(a, b, c) = 0, for a, b, c ? V ? ? ? ? . (2.</formula><p>3)</p><p>The next result shows that the mixed-type operators D ? ? in (2.1) are uniquely determined by the generalized metric V + for any element D ? D 0 (V + ).</p><p>Lemma 2.5. Let V + ? g be a generalized metric. Then, for any D ? D 0 (V + ), we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">D a ? b + = [a ? , b + ] + , D a + b ? = [a + , b ? ] ? . (2.4)</formula><p>Proof. This result follows because given a, b, c ? g and D ? D(V + ), we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">T D (a ? , b + , c + ) = D a ? b + ? [a ? , b + ] c + .</formula><p>Remark 2.6. The previous lemma can be regarded as a weak analogue of the Koszul formula in Riemannian geometry. In the context of generalized geometry, as introduced by Hitchin <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref>, the canonical mixed-type operators (2.4) relate to classical connections with skew-symmetric torsion (see Section 4.1).</p><p>As we will see shortly, D 0 (V + ) is positive-dimensional provided that dim V ? = 1, that is, in general, a generalized metric does not determine a torsion-free compatible connection uniquely <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. This situation can be compared with the construction of the Levi-Civita connection in Riemannian geometry. To proceed, we introduce 'divergences' as a device to further constrain the degrees of freedom in D 0 (V + ).</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">Definition 2.7. A divergence on g is an element ? ? g * .</formula><p>Observe that any connection D ? D(g) determines a divergence by the formula</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">? D (a) = ? tr Da. (2.5)</formula><p>In the sequel, we will identify divergences with elements ? ? g via the isomorphism g ? = g * provided by (?|?). Given ? ? g, we define elements</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">? ? + ? V * + ? ? 2 V + , ? ? ? ? V * ? ? ? 2 V ? , by the formula ? ? ? a ? b ? := (a ? |b ? )? ? ? (? ? |b ? )a ? .<label>(2.</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6)</head><p>Then we obtain a canonical splitting</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">? ? = ? 0 ? ? V ? (2.7)</formula><p>via the direct sum decomposition</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">? ? = ? ? 0 + ? ? ? ? ? ? , (2.8) where ? ? 0 ? ? 0 ? = ? ? ? ? : dim V ? i=1 ?(e ? i , e ? i , ?) = 0 . (2.9)</formula><p>and</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">? ? := 1 dim V ? ? 1 n i=1 ? e ? i e i ? .</formula><p>Here, {e ? i } is an orthogonal base of V ? with metric dual basis {e i ? }, that is, e ? i , e j ? = ? ij . Given a generalized metric V + and a divergence ? ? g, we denote by</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">D 0 (V + , ?) = {D ? D 0 (V + ) | tr D = ?(?|?)}</formula><p>the space of torsion-free V + -compatible generalized connections with fixed divergence. This is an affine space modelled on ? 0 + ? ? 0 ? . Lemma 2.8. Given a generalized metric V + and a divergence ? ? g, the space D 0 (V + , ?) is non-empty provided that dim V ? = 1. Furthermore, the following formula defines an element D ? D 0 (V + , ?):</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">D a b = [a ? , b + ] + + [a + , b ? ] ? + 1 3 [a + , b + ] + + 1 3 [a ? , b ? ] ? + ? ? + a + b + dim V + ? 1 + ? ? ? a ? b ? dim V ? ? 1 . (2.10) Proof. ConsiderD ? D(V + ) defined b? D a b = [a ? , b + ] + + [a + , b ? ] ? . (2.11)</formula><p>This is a compatible connection with T D ? ? 3 V + ? ? 3 V ? , and therefore</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">D 0 =D ? 1 3 TD ? D 0 (V + ).</formula><p>Finally, it is not difficult to see that D 0 has zero divergence. The statement follows now from the identity</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">D a b = D 0 a b + ? ? + a + b + dim V + ? 1 + ? ? ? a ? b ? dim V ? ? 1 .</formula><p>Remark 2.9. The V * + -valued endomorphism ? ? + in (2.8) is reminiscent of the '1-form valued Weyl endomorphisms' in conformal geometry, which appear in the variation of the Levi-Civita connection upon a conformal change of the metric. Thus, geometrically, divergences keep track of the 'conformal geometry' on the quadratic Lie algebra g.</p><p>To finish this section, we present a natural compatibility condition for pairs (V + , ?) which plays an important role in our applications in Section 3. This condition leads to desirable structural properties of the 'generalized Ricci tensor' on a quadratic Lie algebra <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">55]</ref>, but we will not need this more general piece of the theory for the present work. Definition 2.10. Let V + be a generalized metric on g. We say that ? ? g is an infinitesimal</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">isometry of V + if [?, V ? ] ? V ? . (2.12)</formula><p>In this case, we will say that (V + , ?) is a compatible pair.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2.2.</head><p>The Killing spinor equations. In order to introduce the Killing spinor equations on the quadratic Lie algebra g, we define next a pair of Dirac-type operators canonically associated to a pair (V + , ?) as in Lemma 2.8.</p><p>Let V + be a Riemannian generalized metric on g. In the sequel, we fix an orthogonal basis</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">{e ? i } n i=1 of V ? with dual basis {e i ? } n i=1 , i.e. such that e i ? e ? j = ? ij .</formula><p>It is not difficult to see that the following construction is independent of the choice of basis.</p><p>Let Cl(V + ) and Cl(V ? ) denote the complex Clifford algebras of V + and V ? , respectively, defined by the relation v ? v = (v|v) <ref type="bibr">(2.13)</ref> for v ? V ? . We fix irreducible representations S ? of Cl(V ? ) (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45]</ref>, and note the different convention for the relation (2.13) in the Clifford algebra).</p><p>For any choice of metric connection D ? D(V + ), we have associated spin connections</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">D S + + ? V * + ? End(S + ), D S ? ? ? V * ? ? End(S ? ). (2.14)</formula><p>Definition 2.11. Let (V + , ?) be a pair given by a generalized metric and a divergence. Given D ? D 0 (V + , ?), define a pair of Dirac-type operators</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">/ D + ? End(S + ), / D ? ? End(S ? ),</formula><p>given explicitly by the following formula, for ? ? S ? :</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">/ D ? ? = n i=1 e i ? ? D S ? e ? i ?.</formula><p>Lemma 2.12. The Dirac operators / D + and / D ? are independent of the choice of connection D ? D 0 (V + , ?).</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">Proof. Let D ? D(V + , ?). Consider a torsion-free V + -compatible connection D ? = D + ? ? D 0 (V + ), with ? = ? + + ? ? ? ? + ? ? ? .</formula><p>Using the decomposition in (2.8), there exists e ? ? V ? such that ? ? = ? 0 ? + ? e ? . Then the divergence of D ? , defined by (2.5), is</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">? D ? = (?|?) ? (dim V + ? 1)(e + |?) ? (dim V ? ? 1)(e ? |?),</formula><p>and therefore ? D ? = (?|?) implies e + = e ? = 0. Define ? ? ? 3 g * by ?(e 1 , e 2 , e 3 ) = (? e 1 e 2 |e 3 ), and note that the total skew-symmetrization c.p.(?) vanishes, since D ? and D are torsionfree. Decomposing ? = ? + + ? ? in pure types, the result follows from</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">/ D ?? = / D ? ? 1 2 c.p.(? ? ) = / D ? .</formula><p>We are ready to introduce the equations of our main interest. Observe that, from Lemma 2.8 and Lemma 2.12, the operator / D + (respectively / D ? ) depends only on ? + = ? + ? (respectively ? ? = ? ? ?). Notice also that the canonical operators D ? ? associated to a generalized metric V + ? g (see Lemma 2.5) induce spin connections</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">D S + ? ? V * ? ? End(S + ), D S ? + ? V * + ? End(S ? ). (2.15) Definition 2.13. A triple (V + , ? ? , ?),</formula><p>given by a generalized metric V + , ? ? ? V ? , and a non-vanishing spinor ? ? S ? , is a solution of the Killing spinor equations, if if and only if</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">D S ? ? ? = 0, / D ? ? = 0,<label>(2.</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_38">D ? ? ? V * ? ? Lie G ? ,<label>(2.</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>18)</head><p>where G ? ? Spin(V ? ) is the stabilizer of ?. More explicitly, (2.17) is equivalent to</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">i,j [? ? , e ? i ] e j ? e j ? e ? i ? ? = 0.</formula><p>Proof. The first part of the statement follows simply from the identity <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45]</ref> Lie</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">G ? = {B ? ? 2 V ? | B ? ? = 0}.</formula><p>As for the second part, an endomorphism A ? End(V ? ) satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">A = dim V ? i,j=1 Ae ? i e j ? e i ? ? ? e ? j .</formula><p>Since e i ? ? ? e ? j ? e j ? ? ? e ? i ? so(V ? ) embeds as 1 2 e j ? e ? i in the Clifford algebra Cl(V ? ), an endomorphism A ? so(V ? ) corresponds to</p><formula xml:id="formula_42">A = 1 4 dim V ? i,j=1 Ae ? i e j ? e j ? e ? i ? Cl(V ? ). (2.19)</formula><p>Then, given a spinor ? ? S ? , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">D S ? ? ? = 1 4 i,j [? ? , e ? i ] e j ? e j ? e ? i ? ?.</formula><p>Remark 2.15. The case dim V ? = 2n ? and G ? = SU(n ? ) is studied in detail in Section 2.3. When dim V ? = 7, it is interesting to consider the equations (2.16) for a non-vanishing real spinor, as in this case G ? = G 2 in Lemma 2.14 (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr">Prop. 10.2]</ref>). Similarly, when dim V ? = 8 and we take S ? = R 8 , one has G ? = Spin(7) (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr">Prop. 10.4]</ref>).</p><p>Next we obtain a similar characterization of the dilatino equation in <ref type="bibr">(2.16)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">Lemma 2.16. A triple (V + , ? ? , ?) as in Definition 2.</formula><p>13 is a solution of the dilatino equation</p><formula xml:id="formula_45">/ D ? ? = 0,<label>(2.</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>20)</head><p>if and only if 1 6</p><formula xml:id="formula_46">i,j,k [e ? k , e ? i ] e j ? e k ? e j ? e ? i ? ? = ? ? ? ?.</formula><p>Proof. Consider the connection D ? D(V + , ?) in (2.10). Arguing as in the proof of Lemma 2.14, for any a ? ? V ? we obtain</p><formula xml:id="formula_47">D S ? a ? ? = 1 12 i,j [a ? , e ? i ] e j ? e j ? e ? i ? ? + 1 4(dim V ? ? 1) i,j a ? e ? i ? ? e j ? ? ? + e ? i a ? e j ? e j ? e ? i ? ? = 1 12 i,j [a ? , e ? i ] e j ? e j ? e ? i ? ? + 1 4(dim V ? ? 1) (? ? a ? ? a ? ? ? ) ? ?.</formula><p>Hence, setting</p><formula xml:id="formula_48">C := 1 12 i,j,k [e ? k , e ? i ] e j ? e k ? e j ? e ? i ? ?,</formula><p>we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_49">/ D ? ? = C + 1 4(dim V ? ? 1) k e k ? (? ? e ? k ? e ? k ? ? ) ? ? = C + 1 4(dim V ? ? 1) k 2 ? ? e k ? e ? k ? 2? ? ? ? = C ? 1 2 ? ? ?.</formula><p>2.3. Killing spinors in even dimensions. In this section we analyse further the Killing spinor equations (2.16) under the assumption that dim V ? is even. In the sequel, we fix a generalized metric g = V + ?V ? on g and orientations on V ? . Assuming that dim V ? = 2n ? , for n ? ? N, S ? split as irreducible Spin(2n ? )-representations</p><formula xml:id="formula_50">S ? = S + ? ? S ? ? ,<label>(2.21)</label></formula><p>corresponding to the ?1-eigenspaces for the action of the complex volume</p><formula xml:id="formula_51">? ? C = i n ? e ? 1 . . . e ? 2n ?</formula><p>for a choice of oriented basis {e ? j } ? V ? such that e ? i e ? j = ?? ij . A pure spinor ? ? S ? must have definite chirality, that is, either ? ? S + ? or ? ? S ? ? (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr">Lemma 9</ref>.6, p. 337]).</p><p>For ? ? S + ? pure, the isotropy group of ? in Spin(2n ? ) is given by (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr">Lemma 9</ref>.15, p. 343]) G ? = SU(n ? ). In particular, ? determines an almost complex structure J on V ? compatible with (?|?) |V ? and the given orientation, such that the decomposition</p><formula xml:id="formula_52">V C ? := V ? ? R C = V 1,0 ? ? V 0,1 ? in ?i-eigenspaces is determined by V 1,0 + = {a + ? V + ? C | a + ? ? = 0}, V 0,1 ? = {a ? ? V ? ? C | a ? ? ? = 0}</formula><p>, where C is the field of complex numbers. Our aim in this section is to characterize <ref type="bibr">(2.16)</ref> in terms of this SU(n ? )-structure.</p><p>We fix a pure spinor ? ? S + + (the case ? ? S + ? is analogue). Using the almost complex structure J on V + determined by ?, we have a model</p><formula xml:id="formula_53">S + = ? * V 0,1 + with Clifford action a + ? ? = ? 2i ( a 1,0 + | ? ) ? + ? 2a 0,1 + ? ?.</formula><p>Here, (?|?) denotes the C-linear extension of the pairing to V C + , which is a symmetric tensor of type <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1)</ref>. With this identification, the decomposition (2.21) corresponds to </p><formula xml:id="formula_54">? * V 0,1 + = ? even V 0,1 + ? ? odd V 0,1 + ,<label>(2.</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_55">{? + j } n + j=1 ? V 1,0 + , {? + j } n + j=1 ? V 1,0 + = V 0,1 + , defined by ? + j = 1 ? 2 (e + j ? iJe + j ), ? + j = ? + j = 1 ? 2 (e + j + iJe + j )</formula><p>. Notice that the C-linear extension of (?|?) |V + satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_56">? + j ? + k = 0, ? + j ? + k = ? jk , ? + j ? + k = 0. (2.23)</formula><p>With the previous notation, we have the following. </p><formula xml:id="formula_57">1) [V 0,1 ? , V 0,1 ? ] ? V C ? , 2) n ? j=1 [? ? j , ? ? j ] ? V C ? . (2.24) Proof. Assume first ? ? S + + . Given a ? ? V ? , define ? ? ? 2 V + by the formula ? (b + , c + ) = ([a ? , b + ]|c + ), for b + , c + ? V + .</formula><p>Here we identify V + ? = V * + with the isomorphism given by the induced metric on V + . Then, by Lemma 2.14, there exists ? ? C * such that the gravitino equation is equivalent to</p><formula xml:id="formula_58">? ? ? = ? ? ? = 0 for all a ? ? V ? . Decompose ? as ? = ? 2,0 + ? 1,1 + ? 0,2 ,</formula><p>where ? 0,2 = ? 2,0 . Using the identities</p><formula xml:id="formula_59">? j ? 1 = 0, ? j ? 1 = ? 2? j , ? j ? k ? 1 = 2? jk , we obtain ? ? ? = 2?? 0,2 + 2? j ? 1,1 (? j , ? j ).</formula><p>Thus, ? ? ? = 0 holds if and only if</p><formula xml:id="formula_60">0 = ? (b 0,1 + , c 0,1 + ) = [a ? , b 0,1 + ] c 0,1 + = a ? [b 0,1 + , c 0,1 + ] , 0 = j (a ? |[? j , ? j ]), for all b + , c + ? V C + .</formula><p>The statement follows from the fact that a ? can be chosen arbitrarily. Similarly, ? ? S + ? pure is a solution of the gravitino equation if and only if</p><formula xml:id="formula_61">1) [V 1,0 ? , V 1,0 ? ] ? V C ? , 2) n ? j=1 [? ? j , ? ? j ] ? V C ? ,</formula><p>which is equivalent to (2.24) by conjugation on the two equations.</p><p>We state next our characterization of the dilatino equation <ref type="bibr">(2.20)</ref> in the present setup.</p><p>Lemma 2.18. A triple (V + , ? ? , ?), with dim V ? = 2n ? , ? ? S + ? pure, and ? ? ? V ? , is a solution of the dilatino equation <ref type="bibr">(2.20)</ref> if and only if the following two conditions hold </p><formula xml:id="formula_62">1) [V 0,1 ? , V 0,1 ? ] + ? V 0,1 ? , 2) i 2 n ? j=1 [? ? j , ? ? j ] + = ?J? ? . (2.25) Proof. Assume first ? ? S + + . Define H ? ? 3 V + by the formula H(a + , b + , c + ) = ([a + , b + ]|c + ) for a + , b + , c + ? V + .</formula><formula xml:id="formula_63">? + j ? + k ? + l ? 1 = 2 ? 2? kl ? + j , ? + j ? + k ? + l ? 1 = 2 ? 2(? jk ? + l ? ? jl ? + k ), we obtain (H ? 6? + ) ? ? = ?2 ? 2 H 0,3 + 3 H 1,2 (? + j , ? + j ) ? 3? 0,1 + .</formula><p>Thus, (H ? 6? + ) ? ? = 0 holds if and only if 0 = H(a 0,1</p><formula xml:id="formula_64">+ , b 0,1 + , c 0,1 + ) = [a 0,1 + , b 0,1 + ] c 0,1 + , 0 = j a 1,0 + [? + j , ? + j ] ? 2 a 1,0 + ? 0,1 + , for all a + , b + , c + ? V C + . Using the orthogonal decomposition g ? R C = V C + ? V C ?</formula><p>, and the fact that (?|?) |V + is of type (1, 1), we see that the dilatino equation is equivalent to</p><formula xml:id="formula_65">[V 0,1 + , V 0,1 + ] + ? V 0,1 + , 1 2 n + j=1 [? + j , ? + j ] 0,1 + = ? 0,1 + .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Using now</head><formula xml:id="formula_66">i[? + j , ? + j ] = ?i[? + j , ? + j ] = i[? + j , ? + j ], it follows that ?J? + = i? 0,1 + + i? 0,1 + = i 2 n + j=1 [? + j , ? + j ] 0,1 + + [? + j , ? + j ] 1,0 + = i 2 n + j=1 [? + j , ? + j ] + .</formula><p>Similarly, a pure spinor ? ? S + ? is a solution of the dilatino equation if and only if</p><formula xml:id="formula_67">[V 1,0 ? , V 1,0 ? ] ? ? V 1,0 ? , 2) 1 2 n ? j=1 [? ? j , ? ? j ] 1,0 ? = ?? 1,0 ? ,</formula><p>which is equivalent to (2.25) by conjugation on the two equations.</p><p>With the previous results at hand, we give a characterization of the Killing spinor equations in the present setup.</p><formula xml:id="formula_68">Proposition 2.19. Let (V + , ? ? , ?) be a triple, with dim V ? = 2n ? , ? ? S + ? pure, and ? ? ? V ? . Then, (V + , ? ? , ?)</formula><p>is a solution of the Killing spinor equations (2.16) if and only if the following two conditions hold:</p><formula xml:id="formula_69">1) [V 0,1 ? , V 0,1 ? ] ? V 0,1 ? , 2) i 2 n ? j=1 [? ? j , ? ? j ] = ?J? ? . (2.26)</formula><p>Proof. The proof is straightforward from Lemma 2.17 and Lemma 2.18.</p><p>Remark 2.20. Let (V + , ? ? , ?) be a solution of the Killing spinor equations as in Proposition 2.19, and denote by ? ? ? S ? ? a pure spinor in the line corresponding to ?J. Then, it follows from (2.26) that (V + , ? ? , ? ? ) is also a solution of the Killing spinor equations.</p><p>2.4. The F-term and D-term conditions. Proposition 2.19 suggests a weaker version of the equations <ref type="bibr">(2.16)</ref>, which forgets about the real structure on the complex quadratic Lie algebra g ? R C, and takes as fundamental object the isotropic subspace</p><formula xml:id="formula_70">V 1,0 + ? g ? R C</formula><p>. This alternative point of view is more flexible, as it allows to work over an arbitrary field of characteristic zero. This is the approach that we take for the applications to vertex algebras in Section 3.</p><p>Let g c be a complex quadratic Lie algebra with pairing (?|?). We consider the following space of non-degenerate isotropic subspaces:</p><formula xml:id="formula_71">L = {l ? l ? g c | l, l are isotropic and (?|?) |l?l is non-degenerate}.</formula><p>By definition, given an element l ? l ? L, we have a canonical identification</p><formula xml:id="formula_72">l * ? = l.</formula><p>We will use the following notation for the orthogonal projections:</p><formula xml:id="formula_73">? + : g c ? l ? l, ? l : g c ? l, ? l : g c ? l,</formula><p>which exist by assumption. Given a ? g c , when there is no possible confussion we will use the simplified notation</p><formula xml:id="formula_74">a + = ? + a, a l = ? l a, a l = ? l a. (2.27)</formula><p>To formulate the following definition, given l ? l ? L, we fix dual isotropic bases ? j , ? j of l ? l as in <ref type="bibr">(2.23)</ref>. In other words, {? j } dim l j=1 is a basis of l, {? j } dim l j=1 is a basis of l, and (? j |? k ) = 0, (? j |? k ) = ? jk , (? j |? k ) = 0.</p><p>(2.28) Definition 2.21. We will say that an element l ? l ? L satisfies</p><formula xml:id="formula_75">(1) the F-term gravitino equation if [l, l] ? l ? l, [l, l] ? l ? l. (2.29) (2) the F-term dilatino equation if [l, l] + ? l, [l, l] + ? l. (2.30) (3) the F-term equation if [l, l] ? l, [l, l] ? l. (2.31) (4) the D-term gravitino equation if, for any basis ? j , ? j of l ? l as in (2.28), dim l + j=1 [? j , ? j ] ? l ? l. (2.32) (5) the D-term dilatino equation with divergence ? ? l ? l if, for any basis ? j , ? j of l ? l as in (2.28), 1 2 dim l + j=1 [? j , ? j ] + = ? l ? ? l . (2.33) (6) the D-term equation with divergence ? ? l ? l if, for any basis ? j , ? j of l ? l as in (2.28), 1 2 dim l + j=1 [? j , ? j ] = ? l ? ? l . (2.34)</formula><p>It is easy to see that (2.32), (2.33) and (2.34) are independent of the choice of basis. The names of the equations (2.31) and (2.34) are borrowed from similar conditions appearing in supersymmetric field theories in theoretical physics. In this setup, the structure of the effective potential typically distinguishes two types of conditions for a minimal energy configuration <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>, and (2.31) and (2.34) are strongly reminiscent of those.</p><p>Remark 2.22. Note that the F -term gravitino equation (2.29) is equivalent to [w ? , e j ] l = 0, w ? , e j l = 0, for all j ? {1, . . . , n} and ? ? {1, . . . , m}, for any given basis</p><formula xml:id="formula_76">{w ? } of V ? := (l ? l) ? .</formula><p>In the case that g c is the complexification of a real quadratic Lie algebra g, any solution of the gravitino equation (2.17) determines a solution of the F-term and D-term gravitino equations (2.29) and (2.32), given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_77">l ? l = V 1,0 + ? V 0,1 + ? g ? R C. (2.35)</formula><p>This is a straightforward consequence of Proposition 2.19. The following provides a converse for this result. Proof. Given a solution l?l ? L of (2.29) and (2.32) that satisfies (2.36), define V C + := l?l. Then condition 1) in (2.36) implies that V C + is the complexification of a subspace V + ? g, while condition 2) implies that (?|?) |V + &gt; 0. Using (2.36) again, we see that l induces an almost complex structure J : </p><formula xml:id="formula_78">V + ? V + compatible with (?|?) |V + . Therefore,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_79">l ? l = V 1,0 + ? V 0,1 + ? g ? R C, ? = ? + (2.37)</formula><p>This follows by direct application of Proposition 2.19. We give next the converse result.</p><p>Proposition 2.24. Any solution (V + , ? + , ?) of the Killing spinor equations (2.16) on g c = g ? R C, with dim V + = 2n + and ? ? S + + pure, determines a solution of the F-term and D-term equations, (2.31) and (2.34), given by (2.37), such that</p><formula xml:id="formula_80">1) ? (l) = l,</formula><p>2) (a|? (a)) &gt; 0 for any 0 = a ? l,</p><formula xml:id="formula_81">3) ? (?) = ?. (2.38)</formula><p>Conversely, any solution of the F-term and D-term equations satisfying (2.38) determines a solution (V + , ?, ?) of the Killing spinor equations, with dim V + = 2n + and ? ? S + + pure, uniquely up to rescaling of the spinor.</p><p>Proof. Given a solution l?l ? L of (2.31) and (2.34) that satisfies (2.38), define V C + := l?l. Arguing as in the proof of Lemma 2.23, (V + , ?, ??) is a solution of the Killing spinor equations (2.16), for any ? ? C * , satisfying the hypothesis in the statement. Notice that condition 3) in (2.38) implies that ? is real, that is, ? ? V + . The converse follows directly from Proposition 2.19 and Lemma 2.23.</p><p>Let (l ? l, ?) be a pair as in Definition 2.21. To finish this section we introduce a notion of compatibility for such a pair, which provides a 'holomorphic counterpart' to the notion of isometry in Definition 2.10 (cf. Lemma 4.9).</p><p>Definition 2.25. Let g c be a complex quadratic Lie algebra and l ? l ? L a solution of the F-term equation <ref type="bibr">(2.31)</ref>. We say that ? ? g c is</p><formula xml:id="formula_82">(1) an infinitesimal isometry if [?, l ? l] ? l ? l. (2.39) (2) holomorphic if [?, l] ? l, [?, l] ? l. (2.40)</formula><p>Note that, trivially, condition (2.40) implies <ref type="bibr">(2.39)</ref>. Observe also that, in the situation considered in Proposition 2.24, equation (2.39) implies that ? is an isometry in the sense of Definition 2.21. More abstractly, in the next result we study a salient feature of holomorphicity for the derived Lie subalgebras</p><formula xml:id="formula_83">[l, l] ? g c , [l, l] ? g c .</formula><p>The necessary condition (2.41) below will play a key role in our first main Theorem 3.13. The proof is a direct consequence of the invariance of the pairing (?|?) and the isotropic condition on l, l, and it is omitted.</p><formula xml:id="formula_84">Lemma 2.26. Let l ? l ? g c be a solution of the F-term equation (2.31) and ? ? g c holomorphic. Then ? is orthogonal to the derived Lie subalgebras [l, l], [l, l] ? g c , that is, ? ? [l, l] ? ? [l, l] ? . (2.41)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Superconformal vertex algebras from Killing spinors</head><p>3.1. Background on supersymmetric vertex algebras. Here we review basic notions and examples of the theory of supersymmetric vertex algebras that will be needed in the rest of this article. We will use extensively the superfield formalism introduced by Heluani-Kac <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>, where details can be found. As we will work only with N K = 1 SUSY vertex algebras and N K = 1 SUSY Lie conformal algebras within this formalism <ref type="bibr">[36, ?4]</ref>, we will refer to these special cases simply as 'SUSY vertex algebras' and 'SUSY Lie conformal algebras'. The case N K = 1 was studied earlier by Barron <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. As in the rest of Section 3, we work over an algebraically closed field C of characteristic 0. The adjective "super" applied to algebras, modules and vector spaces will mean Z/2Z-graded.</p><p>In the standard approach, a vertex algebra consists of a vector superspace V , endowed with an even vector |0 ? V (vacuum), an even endomorphism T : V ? V (infinitesimal translation) and a parity preserving linear map Y :</p><formula xml:id="formula_85">V ? (End V )[[z ? ]]</formula><p>(the state-field correspondence) mapping each vector v ? V into a field. By a field, we mean a formal sum</p><formula xml:id="formula_86">a(z) := Y (a, z) = n?Z a (n) z ?n?1 in an even variable z, with 'Fourier modes' a (n) ? End V , such that Y (a, z)b is a formal</formula><p>Laurent series for all b ? V , so that the operator product expansions are finite sums</p><formula xml:id="formula_87">a(z)b(w) ? n?0 (a (n) b)(w) (z ? w) n+1 .</formula><p>This data should satisfy several conditions called vacuum axioms, translation invariance and locality (see, e.g., [41, ?4.1] for details).</p><p>One is often interested in a vertex algebra that is conformal <ref type="bibr">[41, ?4.10]</ref>. In particular, the T -action is enhanced to an action of the Virasoro algebra for some central charge c ? C.</p><p>When the Virasoro action admits a further enhancement to a superconformal symmetry, it is computationally more efficient to use the superfield formalism. In the case of the (Neveu-Schwarz) N = 1 superconformal algebra, this action includes an odd linear map S : V ? V such that S 2 = T . Adding a formal odd variable ? commuting with z, we can assign a superfield Y (a, Z) = Y (a, z) + ?Y (Sa, z), to each a ? V , with Z = (z, ?), and then the enhanced translation-invariance property is</p><formula xml:id="formula_88">[S, Y (a, Z)] = (? ? ? ?? z )Y (a, Z). (3.1)</formula><p>This motivates the definition of a SUSY vertex algebra <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>, which we recall next.</p><p>Since S 2 = T , V is a supermodule over the translation algebra H, defined as the associative superalgebra with an odd generator S, an even generator T , and the relation S 2 = T . This superalgebra can be identified with the parameter algebra, i.e., the associative superalgebra L with an odd generator ??, an even generator ??, and the relation ? 2 = ??. The two pairs of generators are denoted ? = (T, S) and ? = (?, ?). Expanding now the superfields</p><formula xml:id="formula_89">Y (a, Z) = n?Z J =0,1 Z ?1?n|1?J a (n|J) ,</formula><p>the ?-bracket and the normally ordered product are respectively defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_90">[a ? b] = n?N J =0,1 ? n|J n! a (n|J) b, : ab := a (?1|1) b,<label>(3.2)</label></formula><p>where Z n|J = z n ? J and ? n|J = ? n ? J . </p><formula xml:id="formula_91">R ? R ?? L ? R, (a, b) ?? [a ? b],<label>(3.3)</label></formula><p>called the ?-bracket, that satisfies the following identities for all a, b, c ? R, respectively called sesquilinearity, skew-symmetry or commutativity, and the Jacobi identity:</p><formula xml:id="formula_92">[Sa ? b] = ? [a ? b] , [a ? Sb] = ?(?1) |a| (S + ?) [a ? b] , (3.4) [a ? b] = (?1) |a||b| [b ???? a] , (3.5) [a ? [b ? c]] = (?1) |a|+1 [a ? b] ?+? c + (?1) (|a|+1)(|b|+1) [b ? [a ? c]] . (3.6)</formula><p>The identities (3.4) and (3.5) take place in L ? R, and the identity (3.6) takes place in L ? L ? ? R, where L ? is a copy of L with the formal variables ? = (?, ?) replaced by ? = (?, ?). The degree of a homogeneous element a is denoted |a| (when we use this notation, we are implicitly assuming a is homogeneous). The precise meaning of the expressions in (3.4), (3.5) and (3.6) is explained in Appendix A.</p><p>Adding the data given by the second operation in (3.2), one obtains the following definition <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36,</ref><ref type="bibr">Def. 4.19]</ref>. A SUSY vertex algebra is a SUSY Lie conformal algebra V , whose underlying vector superspace is a differential superalgebra, with the (odd) differential S : V ? V induced by the H-module structure on V , that is unital (with identity element |0 ? V ), quasicommutative and quasiassociative, and such that the ?-bracket and the multiplication of this superalgebra, called normally ordered product</p><formula xml:id="formula_93">V ? V ?? V, (a, b) ??: ab :, (3.7)</formula><p>are related by the non-commutative Wick formula. Quasicommutativity, quasiassociativity and the non-commutative Wick formula are respectively given by the following identities:</p><formula xml:id="formula_94">: ab : ?(?1) |a||b| : ba := 0 ?? d? [a ? b] ,<label>(3.8)</label></formula><p>: (: ab :) c : ? : a (: bc :) :=:</p><formula xml:id="formula_95">? 0 d? a [b ? c] : +(?1) |a||b| : ? 0 d? b [a ? c] :, (3.9) [a ? : bc :] =: [a ? b] c : +(?1) (|a|+1)|b| : b [a ? c] : + ? 0 d? [[a ? b] ? c] . (3.10)</formula><p>The meaning of the integrals in these identities is explained in Appendix A.</p><p>Any SUSY Lie conformal algebra R determines a SUSY vertex algebra V (R) together with an embedding of SUSY Lie conformal algebras R ?? V (R), that is universal for morphisms </p><formula xml:id="formula_96">R ? V ? into other SUSY vertex algebras V ? . One says that V (R) is</formula><formula xml:id="formula_97">L(z) = n?Z L n z ?2?n , G(z) = n? 1 2 +Z G n z ? 3 2 ?n ,</formula><p>one recovers from (3.11) the usual Virasoro and Neveu-Schwarz commutation relations with central charge c (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36,</ref><ref type="bibr">Example 5.5]</ref> for details), respectively given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_98">[L m , L n ] = (m ? n)L m+n + ? m,?n m 3 ? m 12 c, (3.12a) [G m , L n ] = m ? n 2 G m+n , [G m , G n ] = 2L m+n + c 3 m 2 ? 1 4 ? m,?n . (3.12b) Example 3.2.</formula><p>The N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra of central charge c is generated by the SUSY Lie conformal algebra R whose underlying H-module is freely generated by two superfields, namely an odd vector H (a 'Neveu-Schwarz vector'), an even vector J (a 'current') and a scalar c, with ?-brackets given by <ref type="bibr">(3.11)</ref> and</p><formula xml:id="formula_99">[J ? J] = ? H + ?? 3 c , [H ? J] = (2T + 2? + ?S) J. (3.13)</formula><p>Expanding in components the corresponding superfields</p><formula xml:id="formula_100">Y (J, Z) = ?i J(z) + ? G ? (z) ? G + (z) , Y (H, Z) = G + (z) + G ? (z) + 2?L(z),</formula><p>and the field components in Fourier modes</p><formula xml:id="formula_101">J(z) = n?Z J n z ?1?n , G ? (z) = n? 1 2 +Z G ? n z ? 3 2 ?n ,</formula><p>one obtains from the above ?-brackets the Virasoro commutation relations (3.12a) and the following ones (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41,</ref><ref type="bibr">Theorem 5</ref>.10] and [7, Example 3.13]):</p><formula xml:id="formula_102">[J m , J n ] = m 3 ? m,?n c, J m , G ? n = ?G ? m+n , G ? m , L n = m ? n 2 G ? m+n , [L m , J n ] = ?nJ m+n , G + m , G ? n = L m+n + m ? n 2 J m+n + c 6 m 2 ? 1 4 ? m,?n .</formula><p>Remark 3.3. The Neveu-Schwarz vector H can be recovered from the current J. More precisely, given an even vector J satisfying the identities (3.13) for some odd vector H and an invariant central element c, the triple (J, H, c) automatically satisfies (3.11), so it determines an N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra. This follows by the Jacobi identity for SUSY Lie conformal algebras.</p><p>Example 3.4. The ('small') N = 4 superconformal vertex algebra of central charge c is generated by the SUSY Lie conformal algebra R whose underlying H-module is freely generated by an odd vector H, three even vectors J 1 , J 2 , J 3 , and a scalar c, with ?brackets given by (3.11), (3.13) for J = J i with i = 1, 2, 3 (i.e., H and J i determine an N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra of central charge c), and</p><formula xml:id="formula_103">J i , J j = ?? ijk (S + 2?)J k , i = j, (3.14)</formula><p>where ? ijk is the totally antisymmetric tensor. Superfield expansions similar to the ones in Examples 3.1 and 3.2 provide commutation relations for the corresponding Fourier-mode infinite-dimensional Lie superalgebra (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr">Example 3.14]</ref>).</p><p>Example 3.5. Let (g, (?|?)) be a quadratic Lie algebra and k ? C a scalar (one can start with a Lie superalgebra, but we will not consider this generality in this paper). Let ?g be the corresponding purely odd vector superspace. Abusing notation,</p><formula xml:id="formula_104">[?, ?] : ?g ? ?g ? ?g, (?|?) : ?g ? ?g ? C,</formula><p>will denote the bilinear maps corresponding to the Lie bracket and the quadratic form on g, identifying elements a of g with their corresponding odd copies ?a in ?g. The universal superaffine vertex algebra with level k associated to g is the SUSY vertex algebra V k (g super ) generated by the supercurrent algebra or superaffinization SCurg. This is the SUSY Lie conformal algebra with underlying H-module freely generated by ?g and a scalar k, with the ?-bracket</p><formula xml:id="formula_105">[a ? b] = [a, b] + ?(a|b)k (3.15) for all a, b ? ?g.</formula><p>The above construction is often considered when the Lie algebra g is simple or abelian, taking the level k + h ? , where 2h ? is the eigenvalue for the Casimir operator on g (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36,</ref><ref type="bibr">Example 5.9]</ref> and <ref type="bibr">[41, pp. 33, 115]</ref>). Since we do not want to restrict to semisimple or abelian Lie algebras in this paper, we will not use this convention.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3.2.</head><p>Generators of supersymmetry. Let (g, (?|?)) be a finite-dimensional quadratic Lie algebra over an algebraically closed field C of characteristic 0. Following Section 2.4, throughout this section we fix a direct sum decomposition</p><formula xml:id="formula_106">g = l ? l ? V ? ,</formula><p>with l, l isotropic, (?|?) |l?l non-degenerate, and V ? = (l ? l) ? . We will use the notation (2.27) for the associated orthogonal projections. We fix a basis {? j , ? j } n j=1 of l ? l satisfying (2.28) and an orthogonal basis {v ? } m ?=1 of V ? . Let V k (g super ) be the universal superaffine vertex algebra associated to (g, (?|?)) with level 0 = k ? C (see Example 3.5). We fix ? ? l ? l and consider the associated odd vectors e := ?? = e l + e l , u := ?(? l ? ? l ) = e l ? e l . (3.16)</p><p>We define odd vectors associated to the basis elements e j = ?? j , e j = ?? j , w ? = ?v ? , and use them to define even vectors on V k (g super ) by</p><formula xml:id="formula_107">J 0 := i k : e j e j :, (3.17a) J := J 0 ? 2 k Siu. (3.17b)</formula><p>Here and in the sequel we use the Einstein summation convention for repeated indices. It is easy to see that the previous expresions are independent of the choice of basis. We aim to prove that J 0 and J generate N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra structures (see Observe that w is independent of the choice of basis, and hence it provides an invariant of the subspace l ? l ? g.</p><p>Proposition 3.6. Define c 0 := 3 dim l and the vector</p><formula xml:id="formula_108">H ? := H 0 + 1 k T w ? V k (g super ), (3.19)</formula><p>where H 0 := 1 k : e j Se j : + : e j (Se j ) :  Then, one has</p><formula xml:id="formula_109">+ 1 k 2 : e j : e</formula><formula xml:id="formula_110">[J 0? J 0 ] = ? H ? + ?? 3 c 0 . (3.21)</formula><p>Proof. By the Wick non-conmutative formula J 0? : e j e j : =: J 0? e j e j :</p><formula xml:id="formula_111">+(?1) (|J 0 |+1) | e j | : e j [J 0? e j ] : + ? 0 d? J 0? e j ? e j . (3.22)</formula><p>We calculate [J 0? e j ] and [J 0? e j ] using the conmutativity of the ?-bracket</p><formula xml:id="formula_112">J 0? e k = i k (?1) |J 0 ||e k | e k ???? : e j e j : .</formula><p>Applying Wick's non-conmutative formula, it is easy to see that e k ? : e j e j : =: e k ? e j e j : + (?1) (|e k |+1)|e j | : e j e k ? e j : + By Wick non-conmutative formula and conmutativity, it is easy to see that ? ? : e j , e k e k : + : e k e j , e k : ? e j = ?2k e j , e j l .</p><p>Hence, computing the previous two integrals, we obtain the identity</p><formula xml:id="formula_113">[J 0? J 0 ] = ?H ? ?? dim l = ? H ? + ?? 3 c 0 ,</formula><p>whereH := 1 k 2 : : e j , e k e k : e j : + : : e k e j , e k : e j :</p><p>+ : e j : e j , e k e k : : ? : e j : e k [e j , e k ] : : + 1 k : Se j e j : + : e j (Se j ) : .</p><p>To finish the proof, it suffices to check thatH = H ? as in <ref type="bibr">(3.19)</ref>, for which we apply basic properties in Lemma A.1. Applying (A.3) and (A.4) we obtain, respectively, ? : e j : e j , e k e k : :=: e j : e k e j , e k : :,</p><p>: Se j e j :=: e j Se j : +T e j , e j .</p><p>By (A.5), we also have : : e k e j , e k : e j : =: e j : e k e j , e k : : ?kT e j e k e j , e k ? e j e j , e k e k =: e j : e k e j , e k : : ?k T e j , e j + T e j , e j l .  Then, one has</p><formula xml:id="formula_114">[J ? J] = ? H + ?? 3 c . (3.27)</formula><p>Proof. By sesquilinearity we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_115">[J ? J] = [J 0? J 0 ] ? i 2 k [J 0? Su] ? i 2 k [Su ? J 0 ] ? 4 k 2 [Su ? Su] = [J 0? J 0 ] + i 2 k (? + S) [J 0? u] ? i 2 k ? [u ? J 0 ] ? 4 k 2 ? (S + ?) [u ? u] .</formula><p>We calculate the ?-brackets in the different summands by steps. The term [J 0? J 0 ] was calculated in <ref type="bibr">(3.21)</ref>. Combining Adding the different terms above, we conclude that Similarly, if we denote u = e l ? e l , we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_116">[J ? J] = [J 0? J 0 ] + i 2 k (? + S) [J 0? u] ? i 2 k ? [u ? J 0 ] ? 4 k 2 ? (S + ?) [u ? u] = ? H ? + ?? 3 c + i 2 2 k 2 S : u,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_117">J := J 0 ? 2 k Siu = ?J 0 + 2 k Siu = ?J.</formula><p>Note that J 0 (respectively J) satisfies the relation (3.21) (resp. (3.27)) for the same vector H ? (resp. H). We start by proving the identity (3.28a). Firstly, we find a more convenient expression for the vector H 0 defined in <ref type="bibr">(3.20)</ref>.  Using now (A.9), we conclude the identity (3.29) imposing the involutivity of l and l.</p><p>We will also need the following technical identity. + : e j : e k e i , [e j , e k ] l l : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k l + : : .</p><p>Proof. Applying the Jacobi identity for the Lie bracket of g and the involutivity of l, l, we obtain : e j : e k e i , [e j , e k ] l l : : =: e j : e k [e i , e j ] l , e k l : : + : e j : e k [e j , [e i , e k ] l ] l : :, : e j : e k e i , e j , e k l + : : =: e j : e k e i , e j , e k + : :</p><p>=: e j : e k e i , e j , e k + : : + : e j : e k e j , e i , e k + : :</p><p>=: e j : e k e i , e j + , e k : e j : e k [e i , e j ] l , e k l : : = ? : e i , e j l : e k [e j , e k ] l : :, : e j : e k [e j , [e i , e k ] l ] l : : = ? : e j : e i , e k l [e j , e k ] l : :, : e j : e k e i , e j l , e k l : : = ? : e i , e j l : e k [e j , e k ] l : :, : e j : e k e i , e j l , e k + : : =: e j : e k e i , e j l , e k l : : = ? : [e i , e j ] l : e k e j , e k l : :, : e j : e k e j , e i , e k l l : : = ? : e j : e i , e k l [e j , e k ] l : , : e j : e k e j , e i , e k l + : : =: e j : e k e j , e i , e k l l : : = ? : e j : [e i , e k ] l e j , e k l : .</p><p>Substituting these expressions on the right hand side of (3.11), it suffices to prove that : e j : e k e i , e j l , e k l : : + : e j : e k e j , e i , e k l l : := 0 and : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k + : :=: e j : e k e j , e i , e k ? + : : .</p><p>By (A.8), the last identity is trivial using antisymmetry and invariance of the quadratic Lie algebra. Moreover, using the sames properties, one can easily conclude that : e j : e k e i , e j l , e k l : : + : e j : e k e j , e l , e k l l : := 2 : e j : e k , e i l e j , e k l : : .</p><p>Thus, it suffices to see that a :=: e j : e k , e i l [e j , e k ] l : := 0. But using the Jacobi identity in the left hand side of the previous equality, we conclude 2a = ?a by (A.3), as required.</p><p>The next step is to calculate [H 0? a] for arbitrary a ? l ? l.</p><p>Lemma 3.12. Assume that l ? l satisfies the F -term equation <ref type="bibr">(2.31)</ref>. Then for any a = a l + a l ? l ? l, we have [H 0? a l ] = ? 2 k 2 : e j : e k a l , e j ? , e k l : :</p><p>+ : e j : e k a l , e j ? , e k ? : : + : a l , e j ? : e k e j , e k ? : :</p><p>+ : e j : e k a l , e j , e k ? l : : + : e j : e k e k , a l ? , e j ? : : </p><formula xml:id="formula_118">+ 1 k ? : e</formula><formula xml:id="formula_119">+ 1 k ? : e j [a l , e j ] ? : ?2 : e j S [a l , e j ] ? : +2T e j , [a l , e j ] ? l + ? e j , [a l , e j ] ? l + [a l , e j ] ? , e j ? + (? + 2T + ?S) a l ; (3.30b) [H ? ? a l ] = [H 0? a l ] + ? k [a l , w] ? ??(a l |w). (3.30c) [H ? ? a l ] = [H 0? a l ] + ? k [a l , w] ? ??(a l |w). (3.30d)</formula><p>Proof. Since we can exchange the roles played by l and l, it suffices to check (3.30a) and (3.30c) for a l = e i , an element in the basis of l. By conmutativity of the ?-bracket we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_120">[H 0? e i ] = (?1) |H 0 ||e i | [e i???? H 0 ] .</formula><p>Hence we need to calculate</p><formula xml:id="formula_121">[e i? H 0 ] = 1 k ? 1 i + 1 k 2 ? 2 i ,</formula><p>for which we use the expression for H 0 in Lemma 3.10. We compute first ? 1 i := e i? : e j Se j : + : e j (Se j ) : = ? 1,1 i + ? 1,2 i .</p><p>Applying the Wick non-conmutative formula once on each summand, we have: ? 1,1 i := e i? : e j Se j : =: [e i , e j ] Se j : + : e j S e i , e j : ?? : e j e i , e j : +?ke i + ? [e i , e j ] , e j , ? 1,2 i := e i? : e j (Se j ) =: e i , e j (Se j ) : + : e j (S [e i , e j ]) : ?? : e j [e i , e j ] : +?Ske i + ? e i , e j , e j , and by the involutivity of l,</p><formula xml:id="formula_122">? 1 i = ? 1,1 i + ? 1,2 i</formula><p>=: e j S e i , e j ? : + : e i , e j ? (Se j ) : + (? + ?S) ke i ? ? ? : e j e i , e j : + : e j [e i , e j ] l : ? ? [e j , e i ] l , e j + e j , e i , e j .</p><p>Here we have used the identity (which follows from antisymmetry and invariance on g)</p><p>: [e i , e j ] l Se j : + : e j S e i , e j + : + : e i , e j + (Se j ) : + : e j S [e i , e j ] l : = 0.</p><p>Next, we compute ? 2 i := e i? : e j : e k [e j , e k ] l : : + : e j : e k e j , e k l : : +2 : e j : e k e j , e k ? : :</p><formula xml:id="formula_123">= ? 2,1 i + ? 2,2 i + 2? 2,3 i .</formula><p>First of all, applying twice the Wick non-conmutative formula, we obtain =: e i , e j : e k [e j , e k ] l : : + : e j : e i , e k [e j , e k ] l : : + : e j : e k e i , [e j , e k ] l : : + 2?k : e j [e i , e j ] l : +?k 2 e j , e i l , e j l + e j , e i l , e j l .</p><p>In the same way, we obtain ? 2,2 i := e i? : e j : e k e j , e k l : : =: [e i , e j ] : e k e j , e k l : : + : e j : [e i , e k ] e j , e k l : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k l : : + ?k : e j e i , e j l : +?k 2 [e j , e i ] l , e j l + [e j , e i ] l , e j l , ? 2,3 i := e i? : e j : e k e j , e k ? : :</p><p>=: [e i , e j ] : e k e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e i , e k e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? : :</p><p>+ ?k : e j e i , e j ? : +?k e j , e i ? , e j l + e j , e i l , e j ? + [e j , e i ] ? , e j l .</p><p>Applying now the involutivity of l and l, we have that + : e j : e i , e k ? e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k e k , e j , e i ? ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : + ?k 2 : e j [e i , e j ] l : + : e j e i , e j l : +2 : e j e i , e j ? : + ?k 2 e j , e i l , e j l + e j , e i l , e j l + 2 [e j , e i ] l , e j l + 2 e j , e i ? , e j l + 2 e j , e i l , e j ? , where we have used the identities (A.8) and (A.9), combined with invariance, antisymmetry and the Jacobi identity on g, to add together all the double normally ordered products. Moreover, we have used the identity given in Lemma 3.11 to simplify all the terms that do not have any part in V ? .</p><formula xml:id="formula_124">? 2 i = ? 2,1 i + ? 2,2 i + 2? 2</formula><p>The terms of [e i? H 0 ] ? (? + ?S) ke i that are linear in ? and ? can be simplified as follows.</p><p>Using antisymmetry and invariance on g, we have k? ? ([e i? H 0 ] ? (? + ?S) e i ) = ? : e j e i , e j : ? : e j [e i , e j ] l : + 2 : e j [e i , e j ] l : + : e j e i , e j l : +2 : e j e i , e j ? : =: e j e i , e j ? :, k? ? ([e i? H 0 ] ? (? + ?S) e i ) = ? [e j , e i ] l , e j ? e j , e i , e j + 2 e j , e i ? , e j l + 2 e j , e i l , e j ? + 2 e j , e i l , e j l + e j , e i l , e j l + 2 [e j , e i ] l , e j l = e j , e i ? , e j l + e i , e j ? , e j ? , where in the last expression we have used the involutivity of l and l. From this, we obtain   </p><formula xml:id="formula_125">[e i? H 0 ] = 1 k ? 1 i + 1 k 2 ? 2 i = (? + ?S) e i + 1 k : e j S e</formula><formula xml:id="formula_126">[T w ? e i ] = ?? [w ? e i ] = ? ([e i , w] ? ?k(e i |w)) .</formula><p>which implies (3.30c).</p><p>We are ready to state the first main result of our paper.  </p><formula xml:id="formula_127">I 1 := ? ? A i ? e i , I 2 := ? ? B i ? e i , I 2 := ? ? C i ? e i ,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_128">C i = ? k e i , w + (? + 2T + ?S) e i .</formula><p>We proceed as follows. By conmutativity of the ?-bracket, we can write</p><formula xml:id="formula_129">I 1 = (?1) | A i ||ei| ? ? e i???? A i = ? ? e i? A i : := 1 k I 1 1 ? 2I 2 1 ? 2 k 2 I 3 1 + I 4 1 + I 5 1 + I 6 1 + I 7 1 ,</formula><p>where I 1 1 := ? ? e i? ? : e j e i , e j ? : = ? ? ? e i? : e j e i , e j ? : = ??k e j , e j ? = 0, I 2 1 := ? ? e i? : e j S e i , e j ? : = kS e j , e j ? ? : e j e i , e i , e j ? := ? : e j e k , e k , e j ? :,  By sesquilinearity and the D-term gravitino equation (2.32), it is straightforward to show</p><formula xml:id="formula_130">I 2 = (? ? 2?) e j , e i , e j ? l e i = (? ? 2?) e j , e k ? e j , e k ? ,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_131">I 3 = ? k e j , e j l e i , e i l ? e j , e j l e i , e i l + ? ? (? ? 2? ? ??) e i ? e i = k (? ? 2?) e i e i + ? e i , e i + ,</formula><p>which lead us to the formula</p><formula xml:id="formula_132">I = ?? e i , e i + ? 2 ? k : e j e i , e i , e j ? l</formula><p>: .</p><p>Next, we compute</p><formula xml:id="formula_133">P = P 1 + P 2 + P 3</formula><p>in several steps, where : .</p><p>Next, we expand Q using the special identities given in Lemma A.2 (matching the summands in pairs corresponding to the same line). Applying the antisymmetry and invariance on g, combined with (A.3), (A.8) and (A.9), we obtain the following decomposition:</p><formula xml:id="formula_134">Q := Q 1 + Q 2 + Q 3 + Q 4 + Q 5 ,</formula><p>where Q 1 :=: : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : e i : + : : e k : e i , e j , e k ? l e i : : e j :, The next step is to decompose R as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_135">R := ?R 1 ? 2R 2 + ?R 3 + 2R 4 ,</formula><p>where R 1 :=: : e j e k , e j ? : e k : ? : e k : e j e k , e j ? : :, .</p><p>Using now the hypothesis w ? [l, l] ? ? l, l ? combined with the properties of invariance and antisymmetry on g, we see that</p><formula xml:id="formula_136">P 2 = ? k</formula><p>: e j e j , e k , e k l ? e k , e k l : + : e j , e k , e k l ? e k , e k l e j :</p><p>+ : e j ?? e j e k , e k : ? : ?? e j e k , e k e j :</p><p>= ??? e j , e j + + ? k : e j , e k , e k ? e j : ? : e j e j , e k , e k ? : ,</p><p>where, for the last two terms, we have used the F -term and D-term gravitino equations (2.29) and <ref type="bibr">(2.32)</ref> in order to apply the Jacobi identity for the Lie bracket.</p><p>At last, using that T is a derivation and S is an antiderivation for the normally ordered product, it is easy to check that P 3 = (2? + 2T + ?S) : e j e j : .</p><p>To conclude, by the Jacobi identity, we have that P = (2? + 2T + ?S) : e j e j : ??? e j , e j + + 2? k : e j , e k , e j ? l e k : + ? k : e j , e k ? , e k ? e j : + : e j e j , e k ? , e k ? : + : e j , e k , e k ? e j : ? : e j e j , e k , e k ? : = (2? + 2T + ?S) : e j e j : ??? e j , e j + + 2? k : e j , e k , e j ? l e k : .</p><p>which, combined with our formula for the integral I, now implies H ? ? : e j e j : = (2? + 2T + ?S) : e j e j : . This is equivalent to (3.28a), and hence the statement follows from Proposition 3.6 and Remark 3.3.</p><p>Remark 3.14. Under the hypothesis of Theorem 3.13, if we assume further that l ? l = g, then (g, l, l) is a Manin triple and we recover a construction by E. Getzler <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref>.</p><p>To prove our second main theorem, we need the following technical lemma. Proof. The holomorphicity of ? ? l ? l implies that</p><formula xml:id="formula_137">H = H ? ? 2 k T e = H 0 + 1 k T (w ? 2e). (3.31)</formula><p>This follows from the basic identity : [a, e j ] l e j : + : e j [a, e j ] l := 0 for all a ? ?g (by invariance of (?|?) and antisymmetry of [?, ?]). Note also that the D-term dilatino equation  Proof. The proof reduces to checking the identity (3.28b). By sesquilinearity, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_138">[H ? J] = [H ? ? J 0 ] ? i 2 k [H ? ? Su] ? 2 k [T e ? J 0 ] + i 4 k 2 [T e ? Su] = [H ? ? J 0 ] ? i 2 k (S + ?) [H ? ? u] + 2 k ? [e ? J 0 ] ? i 4 k 2 ? (? + S) [e ? u]</formula><p>. The first summand corresponds to the identity (3.28a), which we proved in Theorem 3.13. We next compute the other summands in a series of steps.</p><p>By hypothesis ? is an infinitesimal isometry (Definition 2.25), and therefore e l , l ? l ? l and [e l , l] ? l ? l.</p><p>(3.34)</p><p>By sesquilinearity and Lemma 3.12, using the equations (3.34) above, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_139">[H ? ? u] = e e i [H ? ? e i ] ? (e|e i ) H ? ? e i = (? + 2T + ?S) u + ? k [u, w] + + ?? e e j , e j .</formula><p>By <ref type="bibr">(3.24)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">(3.23)</ref>, and using that ? is an infinitesimal isometry, we have the following: Here we used the identity using that : [a, e j ] l e j : + : e j [a, e j ] l := 0 for all a ? g (see the proof of Lemma 3.15). Using again the infinitesimal isometry condition (2.12), a simple application for sesquilinearity shows that    <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24]</ref>, for Riemannian generalized metrics and a special class of divergences called closed <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>. As we will see in Proposition 4.5, restricting to invariant solutions on a homogeneous manifold, we obtain Killing spinors on a quadratic Lie algebra in the sense of Definition 2.13. These are the basic ingredients of our construction of (0,2) mirrors in Section 4.4.</p><p>Let M be a smooth oriented spin manifold endowed with an exact Courant algebroid (see e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_140">0 ?? T * ? * ?? E ? ?? T ?? 0. (4.1)</formula><p>We will denote the indefinite pairing and the Dorfman bracket on sections of E by , and [, ], respectively. Recall that a choice of isotropic splitting s : T ? E of (4.1) induces a vector bundle isomorphism E ? = T ? T * , such that</p><formula xml:id="formula_141">X + ?, X + ? = ?(X), [X + ?, Y + ?] = [X, Y ] + L X ? ? i Y d? + i Y i X H,<label>(4.2)</label></formula><p>where H ? ? 3 (M) is a closed three-form determined by s. The Killing spinor equations on E are defined in terms of a pair (V + , div), as given in the following definition. (1) A (Riemannian) generalized metric on E is an orthogonal decomposition E = V + ? V ? , so that the restriction of ?, ? to V + is positive-definite.</p><formula xml:id="formula_142">(2) A divergence operator on E is a map div : ?(E) ? C ? (M) satisfying div(f a) = f div(a) + ?(a)(f ) for any f ? C ? (M).</formula><p>A choice of generalized metric V + ? E determines an isotropic splitting s : T ? E, and hence a preferred presentation of the Courant algebroid structure as in (4.2). In particular, in this splitting one has V ? = {X ? g(X) | X ? T } for a uniquely determined Riemannian metric g on M. Consequently, the generalized metric has an associated Riemannian divergence defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_143">div 0 (X + ?) = L X ? g ? g (4.3)</formula><p>where ? g is the volume element of g. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>, we introduce next a compatibility condition for pairs (V + , div).</p><formula xml:id="formula_144">Definition 4.2. A pair (V + , div) is compatible if e := div ? div 0 is an infinitesimal isometry of V + , that is, [e, V + ] ? V + .</formula><p>Furthermore, we say that (V + , div) is closed if ?(e) = 0.</p><p>Given a compatible pair (V + , div), we have that e = X + ? in the splitting determined by V + and the infinitesimal isometry condition reads (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr">Lemma 2.50]</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_145">L X g = 0, d? = i X H. (4.4)</formula><p>Thus, the condition of being closed corresponds to X = 0 and d? = 0.</p><p>To introduce the Killing spinor equations on E, let us fix a pair (V + , div) as above. The fixed spin structure on M combined with the isometries ? ? : (T, ?g) ? V ? : X ? X ? g(X).</p><p>determine complex spinor bundles S ? for V ? . Associated to the pair (V + , div) there are canonical first order differential operators (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_146">D S + ? : ?(S + ) ? ?(V * ? ? S + ), / D + : ?(S + ) ? ?(S + ), D S ? + : ?(S ? ) ? ?(V * + ? S ? ), / D ? : ?(S ? ) ? ?(S ? ). (4.5)</formula><p>The operators D S ? ? correspond to the unique lift to S ? of the metric-preserving operators</p><formula xml:id="formula_147">D a ? b + = [a ? , b + ] + , D a + b ? = [a + , b ? ] ? ,</formula><p>acting on sections a ? , b ? ? ?(V ? ). The Dirac type operators / D ? are more difficult to construct, as they involve the use of torsion-free generalized connections (similarly as in Section 2). In the situation of our interest, they can be described very explicitly in terms of the following affine metric connections with totally skew-symmetric torsion</p><formula xml:id="formula_148">? ? = ? + 1 2 H, ? ? 1 3 = ? + 1 6 H. Lemma 4.3 ([22]</formula><p>). Let (V + , div) be a pair given by a generalized metric and a divergence operator. Denote div 0 ? div = e, ? , and set ? ? = g(?e ? , ?) ? T * . Then, for any spinor ? ? ?(S ? ) one has</p><formula xml:id="formula_149">D S ? ? ? X ? = ? ? X ?, / D ? ? = / ? ? 1 3 ? ? 1 2 ? ? ? ?.</formula><p>Observe that D S ? ? are independent of the choice of divergence, while the dependence of / D ? on div is only through the partial divergence operator</p><formula xml:id="formula_150">div ? := div |V ? : ?(V ? ) ? C ? (M).</formula><p>We are ready to introduce the equations of our interest. As we show in our next result, there is a perfect match between the geometric Definition 4.4 and the algebraic Definition 2.13, provided that we consider invariant solutions of (4.6) on a homogeneous manifold. Assume that M is endowed with the action of a Lie group K. Then, we say that E is equivariant if the K-action on M lifts to E preserving the Courant algebroid structure. Proof. The first part of the statement is straightforward from the axioms of a Courant algebroid, transitivity of the action, and the equivariance of E. As for the second part, it follows from the natural construction of the operators D S ? ? and / D ? using torsion-free generalized connections <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. Observe here that an invariant generalized connection on E corresponds to an element D ? g * ? ? 2 g as in Definition 2.2. Similarly, for an invariant pair (V + , div ? ) one has div 0|V ? ? div ? = e ? , ? ? V * ? .</p><p>We finish this section with a more explicit description of the solutions of the Killing spinor equations on an even-dimensional manifold for closed pairs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_26">(Definition 4.2</ref>). This will be useful for understanding the salient geometric implications of (0,2) mirror symmetry in the following sections. Recall that, in even dimensions, our spinor bundle decomposes as</p><formula xml:id="formula_151">S + = S + + ? S ? + ,</formula><p>where the factors correspond to irreducible spin representations (cf. Section 2). The resulting system of equations (4.7) below was first considered in <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref> in relation to holomorphic Courant algebroids. The next result is a particular case of [27, Proposition 3.1], but we include a sketch of the proof here for the convenience of the reader. Proposition 4.6. Let M be a smooth oriented spin manifold of dimension 2n endowed with an exact Courant algebroid E. Then, a solution (V + , div + , ?) of the Killing spinor equations (4.6), with div + = div |V + for (V + , div) closed and ? ? ?(S + + ) pure, is equivalent to a SU(n)structure (?, ?) with integrable almost complex structure J and metric g = ?(?, J?), such that d? ? ? ? ? ? = 0, d? ? = 0, dd c ? = 0, where H = ?d c ? and 1 2 (div 0 ? div) = ? ? := Jd * ? is the Lee form of (?, ?).</p><p>Proof. Given a solution of (4.6), ? determines a reduction of the orthonormal frame bundle of (X, g) to SU(n). This reduction is equivalent to a pair (?, ?), where ? is a nondegenerate real two-form ? and ? is a locally decomposable complex n-form satisfying:</p><formula xml:id="formula_152">? ? ? = 0, i k (?1) n?1 ? ? ? = ? n n! . (4.8)</formula><p>In terms of the almost complex structure J determined by ?, ? is of type (1, 1), g = ?(?, J?), and we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_153">T 0,1 M = {X ? T ? C : ? X ? = 0}.</formula><p>Using Lemma 4.3, the first equation in (4.6) implies that the triple (?, J, ?) is parallel with respect to ? + . The second equation in (4.6) implies, as it happens in [24, Theorem 5.1], that the almost complex structure is integrable and furthermore:</p><formula xml:id="formula_154">H = ?d c ?, ? ? = ? + . (4.9)</formula><p>Using that div 0 ? div = ? = 2? + ? ? 1 (M) and d? = 0, we obtain d? ? = 0. The rest of the proof follows as in <ref type="bibr">[</ref> Consider the compact four-dimensional manifold M = S 3 ? S 1 endowed with the canonical orientation. We use the Lie group structure given by identifying</p><formula xml:id="formula_155">M ? = K = SU(2) ? U(1).</formula><p>Consider generators for the Lie algebra of left-invariant vector fields</p><formula xml:id="formula_156">k = su(2) ? R = v 1 , v 2 , v 3 , v 4 , with relations [v 2 , v 3 ] = ?v 1 , [v 3 , v 1 ] = ?v 2 , [v 1 , v 2 ] = ?v 3 , [v 4 , ?] = 0. (4.10)</formula><p>Equivalently, dv 1 = v 23 , dv 2 = v 31 , dv 3 = v 12 , dv 4 = 0, for {v j } the dual basis satisfying v j (v k ) = ? jk . Here, we use the notation v ij = v i ? v j . We take ? ? R and define a left invariant three-form Our next goal is to define a one-parameter family of left-invariant solutions of the Killing spinor equations on E ? . Given x, a &gt; 0 positive real numbers, consider the bi-invariant metric on K defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_157">H ? = ?v 123 .</formula><formula xml:id="formula_158">g x,a = a x (v 1 ? v 1 + v 2 ? v 2 + v 3 ? v 3 + x 2 v 4 ? v 4 ).</formula><p>We define a bi-invariant generalized metric on E ? V x,a ? = {v ? g x,a (v) | v ? k} and a bi-invariant divergence div x,a = div 0 ? ? x , , for div 0 the Riemannian divergence of g x,a (see (4.3)) and ? x = ?xv 4 .</p><p>Lemma 4.7. For any x, a &gt; 0 and ? ? R, the pair (V x,a ? , ? x ) is closed, that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_159">[? x , V x,a ? ] ? V x,a ? , ?(? x ) = 0.</formula><p>Proof. The statement follows trivially from (4.4).</p><p>It remains to specify a left-invariant spinor line ? ? S + + corresponding to an almost complex structure on V x,a + . For this, note that the anchor map ? : E ? ? T induces an isomorphism V x,a + ? = T, and we set</p><formula xml:id="formula_160">J x v 4 = xv 1 , J x v 2 = v 3 . (4.12)</formula><p>For div x,a + := div x,a|V x,a + , we shall prove that (V x,a + , div x,a + , J x ) defines a solution of the Killing spinor equations, provided that ? = a/x. For this, we adopt an algebraic approach. By Proposition 4.5, the space of left-invariant section of ?(E ? ) K inherits a structure of quadratic Lie algebra g ? := ?(E ? ) K with underlying vector space g ? ? = k ? k * , pairing</p><formula xml:id="formula_161">(v + ?|v + ?) = ?(v)</formula><p>and Lie bracket</p><formula xml:id="formula_162">[v + ?, w + ?] = [v, w] ? ?([v, ]) + ?([w, ]) + ?i w i v v 123 .</formula><p>For fixed x, a &gt; 0, (V x,a + , div x,a ) can be regarded as the pair (V x,a + , ? x ) of generalized metric and divergence on the quadratic Lie algebra g ? (see Section 2.1). Observe that, being g x,a bi-invariant, the Riemannian divergence div 0 corresponds to the zero element in g * ? . </p><formula xml:id="formula_163">if ? = a/x. We have that J x (v + g x,a (v)) := J x v + g x,a (J x v) .</formula><p>Hence, an oriented orthonormal basis for V x,a + is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_164">x a v 2 + a x v 2 , x a v 3 + a x v 3 , 1 ? xa v 4 + ? xav 4 , x a v 1 + a x v 1 ,<label>(4.13)</label></formula><p>with associated basis of V 1,0 + and V 0,1 + satisfying (2.23) given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_165">? + 1 = 1 ? 2 x a v 2 + a x v 2 ? i x a v 3 + a x v 3 , ? + 1 = ? + 1 , ? + 2 = 1 ? 2 1 ? xa v 4 + ? xav 4 ? i x a v 1 + a x v 1 , ? + 1 = ? + 1 .</formula><p>(4.14)</p><p>Now, a direct calculation shows that</p><formula xml:id="formula_166">? + 1 , ? + 2 = 1 2 x a v 2 + 2 ? ? x a v 2 ? i 2 x a v 3 + 2 ? ? x a v 3 . Hence, ? + 1 , ? + 2 ? V C + if</formula><p>and only if ? = a/x and, assuming this condition, it follows that</p><formula xml:id="formula_167">[V 1,0 + , V 1,0 + ] ? V 1,0 + , where V 1,0 + ? V x,a + ? C is the i-eigenbundle of J x . Similarly, v := 2 j=1 ? + j , ? + j = i ? x a v 1 ? 2 ? ? x a v 1 ,</formula><p>and therefore v ? V C + if and only if ? = a/x. Finally, assuming this condition and using that Our solutions of the Killing spinor equations in the previous lemma are such that ? x is an infinitesimal isometry for V x,a + in the sense of Definition 2.10 (see <ref type="bibr">Lemma 4.7)</ref>. In the next result we prove that the dual vector field ?? x + is holomorphic with respect to J x .</p><formula xml:id="formula_168">J x (? x + ) = ? 1 2 J x 1 a v 4 + xv 4 = ? 1 2 x a v 1 + v 1 ,</formula><p>Lemma 4.9. The left invariant vector field ?? x + is J x -holomorphic, that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_169">[? x + , V 1,0 + ] ? V 1,0 + , where V 1,0 + ? V x,a + ? C is the i-eigenbundle of J x .</formula><p>Proof. The statement follows from the fact that ? x + = ? 1 2 1 a v 4 + xv 4 is in the center of the Lie algebra g ? .</p><p>We analyse next our family of Killing spinors in terms of complex geometry by means of Proposition 4.6. Assuming that ? = a/x, the family of solutions of (4.7) induced by</p><formula xml:id="formula_170">(V x + , div x + , ? x ) := (V x,?x + , div x,?x + , ? x ) (4.15)</formula><p>is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_171">? x = ?xv 41 + ?v 23 , ? x = ? 2 (iv 1 + xv 4 ) ? (v 2 + iv 3 ),<label>(4.16)</label></formula><p>with Lee form ? x = ?xv 4 . A classification of solutions of (4.7) on compact four-manifolds was obtained in <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>: either (M, g, J) is a flat torus or a K3 surface with a K?hler Ricci-flat metric (and hence ? ? = 0), or (M, g, J) is a quaternionic Hopf surface and ? ? = 0. To see this more explicitly, we note that the complex manifold (K, J x ) is biholomorphic to the diagonal Hopf surface</p><formula xml:id="formula_172">X x = (C 2 \{0})/ ? x</formula><p>where ? x ? = Z is generated by ? x (z 1 , z 2 ) = (e x z 1 , e x z 2 ). With this identification, there is an isomorphism (see [4, Thm. 1.2])</p><formula xml:id="formula_173">H 1,1 A (X x ) ? = C [? 1 x ? ? 1 x ] ? = C [v 41 ] ,</formula><p>where H 1,1 A (X x ) stands for the Aeppli cohomology group of X x and ? 1 x = iv 1 + xv 4 . Therefore, we obtain an interpretation of the parameter a = ?x &gt; 0 as the Aeppli class of the pluriclosed metric ? x (see <ref type="bibr">Proposition 4.6)</ref> [  <ref type="figure">6)</ref> are preserved under T-duality, and we shall prove that the T-dual of (V x + , div x + , ? x ) (see <ref type="bibr">(4.15)</ref>) is a different element in the same family.</p><formula xml:id="formula_174">? x ] = a[v 41 ] ? H 1,1 A (X x</formula><p>We start recalling some background on topological T-duality following <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15]</ref>. Let T k be a k-dimensional torus acting freely and properly on a smooth compact manifold M, so that M is a principal T k -bundle over the smooth manifold B := M/T k . We endow M with a choice of T k -invariant cohomology class </p><formula xml:id="formula_175">? ? H 3 (M, R) T k .</formula><formula xml:id="formula_176">q * H ?q * ? = dB, (4.18) where B ? ? 2 (M) T k ?T k is such that B : ker dq ? ker dq ? R (4.19)</formula><p>is non-degenerate.</p><p>Given M as above, the natural exact sequence</p><formula xml:id="formula_177">0 ? t ? T M T k ? T B ? 0, (4.20) where t = B ? Lie T k , induces a filtration ? * (B) ? = F 0 ? F 1 ? ? ? ? ? F ? = ? * (M) T k ,<label>(4.21)</label></formula><p>where F i = Ann(? i+1 t). Given now T-dual pairs (M, ? ) and (M ,? ), there exists representatives H ? ? and? ?? in F 1 of M andM , respectively, which satisfy the conditions in Definition 4.10 (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr">Lemma 10.5]</ref>).</p><p>Let E be an exact Courant algebroid E over M which is equivariant with respect to the T k -action. Recall that such an E has an associated?evera class</p><formula xml:id="formula_178">[E] ? H 3 (M, R) T k .</formula><p>Consider the vector bundle E/T k ? B, whose sheaf of sections is given by the invariant section of E, that is, ?(E/T k ) = ?(E) T k . We can endow E/T k with a natural structure of Courant algebroid, with pairing and Dorfman bracket given by the restriction of the neutral pairing and the Dorfman bracket on E to ?(E) T k . We will call E/T k the simple reduction of E by T k .  We briefly describe the construction of the isomorphism ?, which we will need. We choose equivariant isotropic splittings of E and? such that the corresponding three-forms H and H are in F 1 of their respective fibrations. Given X + ? ? ?(T M ? T * M) T k , choose the unique lift X of X to ?(TM ) T k ?T k such that</p><formula xml:id="formula_179">q * ?(Y ) ? B(X, Y ) = 0, for all Y ? t. (4.23)</formula><p>Due to this condition the form q * ? ? B(X, ?) is basic for the bundle determined byq, and can therefore be pushed forward toM . Then, ? is defined by the explicit formula ?(X + ?) =q * (X + q * ? ? B(X, ?)).</p><p>To apply T-duality to the situation of our interest, we regard K as in Section 4.2 as a T 1 -principal bundle over S 3 ? = SU(2), via the natural left action of the central subgroup</p><formula xml:id="formula_180">T 1 = U(1) ? SU(2) ? U(1)</formula><p>given by the second factor. Given ? ? R we consider the closed three-form H ? in (4.11).  Proof. We calculate first the isomorphism (4.22) in Theorem 4.11 corresponding to the two-form (4.24). Firstly, notice that by (4.23) we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_181">?(v j ) =v j , ?(v j ) =v j , for j = 1, 2, 3.</formula><p>A direct calculation also shows that</p><formula xml:id="formula_182">?(v 4 ) =v 4 , ?(v 4 ) =v 4 . By definition of V x + (see (4.15)) we have V x + = v 2 + ?v 2 , v 3 + ?v 3 , v 1 + ?v 1 , v 4 + ?x 2 v 4 ? T ? T * , and therefor? V + := ?(V x + ) = v 2 + ?v 2 ,v 3 + ?v 3 ,v 1 + ?v 1 ,v 4 + ?x 2v 4 ? T ? T * .</formula><p>From this, the T-dual metric i?</p><formula xml:id="formula_183">g = ?(v 1 ?v 1 +v 2 ?v 2 +v 3 ?v 3 + (?x) ?2v4 ?v 4 ) = gx,</formula><p>wherex is defined as in <ref type="bibr">(4.26)</ref>. Similarly, we have that</p><formula xml:id="formula_184">?(? x + ) = ? 1 2 ? 1 ?x v 4 + xv 4 = ? 1 2 1 ?xv 4 + xv 4 = ?x + ,</formula><p>where (?x) + denotes the orthogonal projection of ?x ontoV + = Vx ,? + . Finally, the T-dual complex structure? := ?J x ? ?1 |V x.a + is given b?</p><formula xml:id="formula_185">Jv 2 =v 3 ,?v 4 = 1 ?xv 1 . Remark 4.14.</formula><p>Observe that the volume element along the fibres of K ? SU(2) is constant on the base, and hence there is no dilaton shift (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr">Proposition 6.8]</ref>). This implies</p><formula xml:id="formula_186">? * div x = divx + xv 4 ? (?x) ?1v</formula><p>4 , ? = divx, unless ?x 2 = 1. Nonetheless, the Killing spinor equations (4.6) only depend on div x + , and this is precisely the quantity exchanged under T-duality in the previous result.</p><p>Geometrically, Proposition 4.13 implies that T-duality exchanges the complex structure parameter x with the Aeppli class a = ?x of the T-dual solution (see <ref type="bibr">(4.17)</ref>), and vicevers?</p><formula xml:id="formula_187">x = 1 a ,? = 1 x . (4.26)</formula><p>This phenomenon is strongly reminiscent of the rotation of the Hodge diamond on mirror symmetry for algebraic Calabi-Yau manifolds. The goal of the next section is to turn this observation into a precise statement on (0,2) mirror symmetry, using vertex algebras.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.4.</head><p>An example of (0, 2) mirror symmetry. We start recalling the coordinate independent description of the chiral de Rham complex using Courant algebroids. Let E be an exact Courant algebroid over a smooth manifold M . Let ?E be the corresponding purely odd super vector bundle. We will abuse notation and denote by , the corresponding super-skew-symmetric bilinear form, and by <ref type="bibr">[, ]</ref> the corresponding super-skew-symmetric degree 1 bracket on ?E. Similarly, we obtain an odd differential operator</p><formula xml:id="formula_188">D : C ? (M) ? ?(?E)</formula><p>defined by the composition of the exterior differential d, the map ? * : T * ? E * , and the isomorphism E * ? = E provided by , , and the parity change operator ?.</p><p>As in Section 3.1, we denote by H the translation algebra. Let R be the H-module  ). The following endows R with the structure of SUSY Lie conformal algebra: Observe that R admits a natural sheafification, which we denote in the same way. The next result provides a coordinate-free description of the chiral de Rham complex on the smooth manifold M. the generators of the N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra constructed in Theorem 3.16, then (see Remark 3.9)</p><formula xml:id="formula_189">[f ? g] = 0, ?f, g ? C ? (M), [A ? B] = [A, B] + (2? + D) A, B , ?A, B ? ?(?E), [A ? f ] = ?(A)f, ?A ? ?(?E), f ? C ? (M).</formula><formula xml:id="formula_190">J(V + , ? + , ?J) = ?J, H(V + , ? + , ?J) = H. (4.29)</formula><p>Finally, by a theorem of Linshaw and Mathai <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[46]</ref> the T-duality isomorphism ? in Theorem 4.11 induces an isomorphism</p><formula xml:id="formula_191">? ch : p * ? ch K (E ? ) T 1 ?p * ? ch K (E ? ) T 1 . (4.30)</formula><p>where ? ch K (E ? ) T 1 is the sheaf of SUSY vertex algebras on K generated by T 1 -invariant sections of E ? and functions on K/T 1 ? = SU(2) (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[46,</ref><ref type="bibr">Section 4.2</ref>] for a precise definition). Observe that, in particular, we have an embedding  Proof.  </p><formula xml:id="formula_192">V 2 (g super ) ?? H 0 (SU(2), p * ? ch K (E ? ) T 1 ) induced</formula><formula xml:id="formula_193">Q 0 = 1 2 (H (0|1) + iJ (0|0) ), G 0 = 1 2 (H (0|1) ? iJ (0|0) ),<label>(4.</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_194">? T 1 x,A := H * (? ch K (E ? ) T 1 , Q 0 ). (2) The equivariant B-half twisted model of (V x + , div x + , J x )</formula><p>is is the sheaf of SUSY vertex algebras given by the cohomology</p><formula xml:id="formula_195">? T 1 x,B := H * (? ch K (E ? ) T 1 , G 0 ).</formula><p>The good definition of the equivariant A-half and B-half twisted models follows as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> once we notice that (g x , J x ) is part of a generalized K?hler structure, where the second complex structure is given by the right invariant extension of J x to K (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr">Example 4.8]</ref>). The conditions Q 2 0 = G 2 0 = 0 follow from the generalized K?hler identities. To give a more explicit description of the twisted models, recall that our solution of the Killing spinor equations (V x + , div x + , J x ) has associated holomorphic Courant algebroids Q x,? ? X x := (K, J x ), Q x,? ? X x := (K, ?J x ) defined by reduction (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr">Theorem 1.20]</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_196">Q x,? := ((V x + ) 0,1 ) ? /(V x + ) 0,1 , Q x,? := ((V x + ) 1,0 ) ? /(V x + ) 1,0 .</formula><p>Here ((V x + ) 0,1 ) ? denotes the orthogonal complement of the ?i-eigenbundle </p><formula xml:id="formula_197">(V x + ) 0,1 of J x on V x + ? C ? E ? ? C.</formula><formula xml:id="formula_198">x,A ? = ? ch Xx (Q x,? ) T 1 , ? T 1 x,B ? = ? ch Xx (Q x,? ) T 1 .</formula><p>Our next result provides the desired identification between the equivariant half-twisted models for the pairs of (0, 2) mirrors in Theorem 4.18. </p><formula xml:id="formula_199">? T 1 x,A ? = ? T 1 x,B , ? T 1 x,B ? = ? T 1 x,A .</formula><p>Consequently, there is an isomorphism of sheaves of SUSY vertex algebras</p><formula xml:id="formula_200">? ch Xx (Q x,? ) T 1 ? = ? ch Xx (Qx ,? ) T 1 . (4.33)</formula><p>Proof. The first part of the statement follows from Theorem 4.18. In particular, (4.31) implies</p><formula xml:id="formula_201">? ch (Q 0 ) =? 0 , ? ch (G 0 ) =Q 0 .</formula><p>The second part of the statement follows from Proposition 4.20.</p><p>The identity (4.33) is remarkable, as it gives an isomorphism of holomorphic sheaves of SUSY vertex algebras over different complex manifolds. It shall be compared with a fundamental result of Borisov and Libgober <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>, which matches the elliptic genera of a Calabi-Yau hypersurface on a Fano toric manifold with the one of its mirror. Here, the term holomorphic stands for the fact that ? ch Xx (Q x,? ) T 1 is locally generated by the T 1invariant holomorphic sections of Q x,? (after parity change) and T 1 -invariant holomorphic functions on X x . Observe that, in the present setup, there is a natural elliptic fibration structure X x ? P 1 and any T 1 -invariant holomorphic function on X x is necessarily pull-back from P 1 . Inspired by <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43]</ref>, one can speculate that there should be a homological version of (0, 2) mirror symmetry for pairs (X, Q), given by a compact complex manifold X and a holomorphic string algebroid Q <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>, which replaces (4.33) by an equivalence of suitable categories of vertex algebra modules. To start, it would be interesting to obtain an explicit calculation of ? ch Xx (Q x,? ) T 1 in the present example.</p><p>Remark 4.22. The use of generalized K?hler geometry in Definition 4.19 suggests that Theorem 4.18 can possibly be regarded as an example of (2, 2)-mirror symmetry. However, we would like to stress that neither our methods nor the ones from <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> apply directly in the present situation to achieve such result. On the one hand, the generalized K?hler structure underlying (g x , J x ) is not left-invariant, and hence it cannot be regarded as a pair Killing spinors on the quadratic Lie algebra g ? . On the other hand, <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38,</ref><ref type="bibr">Theorem 2]</ref> only applies to generalized Calabi-Yau metric structures, which are always K?hler on a compact manifold.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.5.</head><p>A family of N = 4 algebras. In this section we discuss an explicit application of Theorem 3.13. More precisely, we will show that each element of the family of N = 2 superconformal structures induced by Lemma 4.8 and Theorem 3.13 embeds in a N = 4 superconformal vertex algebra with central charge c = 6. Our construction seems to be related to a N = 4 superconformal algebra originally discovered by Sevrin, Troost, and Van Proeyen <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[56]</ref> (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>), but we have not been able to find a precise match.</p><p>We fix ?, x &gt; 0 and consider the solution of the killing spinor equations (V x + , div x + , J x ) (see (4.15)) on the equivariant Courant algebroid E ? over K = SU(2) ? U(1) obtained in Lemma 4.8. We start with the observation that g x is compatible with a left-invariant hyperholomorphic structure (I, J, K) on K, defined by (see <ref type="bibr">(4.16)</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_202">I = J x , 2? x = ? J + i? K ,</formula><p>where g = ? J (, J) = ? K (, K). More explicitly, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_203">Jv 4 = xv 2 , Jv 3 = v 1 , Kv 1 = v 2 , Kv 4 = xv 3 ,</formula><p>and it is straightforward to check that the standard Hamilton relations hold</p><formula xml:id="formula_204">I 2 = J 2 = K 2 = IJK = ? Id .</formula><p>In the next result, we show that (V x + , div x + ) combined with either I, J, or K, gives a solution of the Killing spinor equations (4.6). Proof. The claim in complex structure I has been verified in Lemma 4.8. We check that (V x + , div x + , K) is a solution of (4.6) on E ? , and leave the other case for the reader. By Proposition 4.6, it suffices to prove that ? K = ?v 12 + ?xv <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">43</ref> ,</p><formula xml:id="formula_205">? K = (v 1 + iv 2 ) ? (iv 3 + xv 4 )</formula><p>satisfies (4.7) with d c K ? K = ?H ? and ? ? K = ?xv 4 . We calculate d? K = ixv 43 ? (v 1 + iv 2 ) = ?xv 4 ? ? K , d? K = ??xv 412 = ?xv 4 ? ? K , d c K ? K = ?d? K (K, K, K) = ?xv 412 (K, K, K) = ??v 123 = ?H ? . The statement follows from the structure equation for the Lee form on a complex surface, given by d? K = ? ? K ? ? K .</p><p>In the next result, we construct the desired family of N = 4 superconformal vertex algebras by application of Theorem 3.13. By Lemma 4.23 and Proposition 2.19 it follows that w := w J = w I = w K = ? x + , and hence condition (2.41) holds by Lemma 4.9.</p><p>Proposition 4.24. The solutions of the Killing spinor equations in Lemma 4.23 induce an embedding of the N = 4 superconformal vertex algebra of central charge c = 6 into the universal superaffine vertex algebra associated to g ? with level k = 2. More precisely, if we denote by We compute the ?-brackets:  A.3. Superaffine vertex algebras. Let V k (g super ) be the universal superaffine vertex algebra with level k associated to a quadratic Lie algebra (g, (?|?)), for a scalar k ? C (see Example 3.5). Proof. The first identity follows from the quasiconmutativity, and the second one follows from the quasiassociativity.</p><formula xml:id="formula_206">J I 0 = J 0 (V x + , div x,a + , I), H ? I = H ? (V x + , div x + , I), J J 0 = J 0 (V x + , div x + , J), H ? I = H ? (V x + , div x + , J), J K 0 = J 0 (V x + , div x + , K), H ? K = H ? (V x + , div x + , K),</formula><formula xml:id="formula_207">w</formula><p>Remark A.3. Observe that the formula for the Weyl endomorphism (2.6) appears naturally in several of the previous identities.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Lemma 2 . 17 .</head><label>217</label><figDesc>A pair (V + , ?), with dim V ? = 2n ? and ? ? S + ? pure, is a solution of the gravitino equation (2.17) if and only if the following conditions are satisfied</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Lemma 2 . 23 .</head><label>223</label><figDesc>Let g be a real quadratic Lie algebra and consider g c = g ? R C. Denote by ? : g c ? g c the involution induced by conjugation. Then any solution (V + , ?) of the gravitino equation (2.17), with dim V + = 2n + and ? ? S + + pure, determines a solution of the F-term and D-term gravitino equations (2.29) and (2.32), given by (2.35), such that 1) ? (l) = l, 2) (a|? (a)) &gt; 0 for any 0 = a ? l. (2.36) Conversely, any solution of (2.29) and (2.32) satisfying (2.36) determines a solution (V + , ?) of the gravitino equation, with dim V + = 2n + and ? ? S + + pure, uniquely up to rescaling of the spinor.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>by [45, Prop. 9.7, p. 337], J determines a spinor line ? ? S + + . Applying now Lemma 2.17, it follows that (V + , ??) is a solution of the gravitino equation (2.17), for any ? ? C * , satisfying the hypotheses in the statement of the lemma. The converse follows from Proposition 2.19.Under the above assumption g c = g ? R C, we have an analogue relation between the dilatino equation(2.20), and the F-term and D-term dilatino equations (2.30) and(2.33). Similarly, any solution of the Killing spinor equations determines a solution of the F-term and D-term equations, (2.31) and (2.34), given by</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Example 3 . 2 )</head><label>32</label><figDesc>under natural assumptions studied in Section 2.4. Our construction extends a construction by E. Getzler for Manin triples<ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref> (seeRemark 3.14).Before we address this question in Section 3.3, in the present section we undertake the calculation of the ?-brackets [J 0? J 0 ] and [J ? J] without making any assumptions. Define w := e j , e j l ? e j , e j l = ?([? j , ? j ] l ? [? j , ? j ] l ) ? ?g.(3.18)   </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>k e j , e k : : + : e j : e k e j , e k : : ? : e j : e k e j , e k : : ? : e j : e k [e j , e k ] : : .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>k , e j e j : + : e j e k , e j : ??ke k + ?k e k e j , e j ; which implies J 0? e k = i k : e k , e j e j : + : e j e k , e j : + i ?e k + Se k ? ? e k e j , e j , (3.23)[J 0? e k ] = i k : e k ,e j e j : + : e j [e k , e j ] : ? i ?e k + Se k + ? e k e j , e j . (3.24) Applying now sesquilinearity in the ?-bracket in the integrand of (3.22), we obtain that J 0? : e j e j : = i k : : e j , e k e k : e j : + : : e k e j , e k : e j : ? ? : e j : e j , e k e k : : ? : e j : e k [e j , e k ] : : + + i : Se j e j : + : e j (Se j ) : +? e j , e j l ? e j , e j l + + i k ? 0 d? : e j , e k e k : + : e k e j , e k : ? e j + + i ? 0 d? (? ? ?) e j , e j + ?k e j e j .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Finally, (A. 3 )</head><label>3</label><figDesc>and (A.5) imply that : : e j , e k e k : e j : = ? : e j : e k e j , e k : : +kT ( e j | e k ) e j , e k ? e j e j , e k e k = ? : e j : e k e j , e k : : +kT e j , e j l and thereforeH = H ? as claimed.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Remark 3 . 7 .k 2 S</head><label>372</label><figDesc>Our formula (3.20) for H 0 shall be compared with the formula for the vector H + in [38, Theorem 2]. We next calculate the ?-bracket [J ? J], where J is defined in (3.17b).Proposition 3.8. Define c := 3 dim l + 4 k (e|w ? e) . : u, e j e j : + : e j [u, e j ] : ? V k (g super ). (3.26)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(3.23) with (3.24) we have [J 0? u] = e e k [J 0? e k ] ? (e|e k ) J 0? e k = e e k i k : e k , e j e j : + : e j [e k , e j ] : ? i (? + S) e k + ? e k e j , e j ? (e|e k ) i k : e k , e j e j : + : e j e k , e j : + i (? + S) e k ? ? e k e j , e j = ?i (? + S) e + ? u e j , e j + i k : u, e j e j : + : e j [u, e j ] : . Applying conmutativity of the ?-bracket, we also obtain [u ? J 0 ] = (?1) |u||J| [J 0???? u] = i ?e + ? u e j , e j + i k : u, e j e j : + : e j [u, e j ] : , while application of sesquilinearity shows that [u ? u] = [u, u] + k?(u|u) = k?(u|u) = ?k?(e|e).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>2 SRemark 3 . 9 .</head><label>239</label><figDesc>e j e j : + : e j [u, e j ] : + 4 k ? (S + ?) ?(e|e) + i 2 k (? + S) ?i (? + S) e + ? u e j , e j ? i 2 k ? i ?e + ? u e j , e j : u, e j e j : + : e j [u, e j ] : + ?? 3 (c 0 + 12??(e|w ? e)) = ? H + ?? 3 c . In the definition of J 0 and J in (3.17a) and (3.17b), we consider l ? l as an ordered pair. Note that, if we denote by J 0 the vector associated to l ? l, by (A.3) we have J 0 := i k : e j e j := ? i k : e j e j := ?J 0 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>3. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>N = 2 supersymmetry from the F -term and D-term equations. Our main goal in this section is to prove that, under natural assumptions studied in Section 2.4, the vectors J 0 and J (see(3.17a) and (3.17b)) induce N = 2 superconformal structures on the universal superaffine vertex algebra associated to (g, (?|?)). As a consequence of Proposition 3.6 and Proposition 3.8, this reduces to proving the identities (seeRemark 3.3) [H ? ? J 0 ] = (2? + 2T + ?S) J 0 , (3.28a) [H ? J] = (2? + 2T + ?S) J. (3.28b)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Lemma 3 . 10 . 1 k 2 2 :</head><label>31012</label><figDesc>Assume that l ? l satisfies the F -term equation (2.31). Then the vector H 0 defined by (3.20) can be written as follows: H 0 = 1 k : e j Se j : + : e j (Se j ) : + e j : e k e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k [e j , e k ] l : : + : e j : e k e j , e k l : : .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>(3. 29 )</head><label>29</label><figDesc>Proof. Without any hypothesis, it follows from (A.8) that : e j : e k e j , e k : :=: e j : e k e j , e k : : .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Lemma 3 . 11 .</head><label>311</label><figDesc>Assume that l ? l satisfies the F -term equation (2.31). Then, for all i ? {1, . . . , n}, we have 2 : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k l : : =: e i , e j + : e k [e j , e k ] l : : + : [e i , e j ] l : e k e j , e k l : :+ : e j : [e i , e k ] l e j , e k l : : + : e j : e i , e k + [e j , e k ] l : :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head>+:</head><label></label><figDesc>: + : e j : e k e j , e i , e k + + : : + : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k + : : + : e j : e k e j , e i , e k ? + : : . By (A.3) and (A.8) combined with the invariance of (?|?) we also obtain</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>j a l , e j ? : ?2 : e j S a l , e j ? : +2T e j , a l , e j ? l+ ? e j , a l , e j ? l + a l , e j ? , e j ? + (? + 2T + ?S) a l , (3.30a) [H 0? a l ] = ? 2 k 2 : e j : ek [a l , e j ] ? , e k l : : + : e j : e k [a l , e j ] ? , e k ? : : + : [a l , e j ] ? : e k e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k a l , e j , e k ? l : : + : e j : e k [e k , a l ] ? , e j ? : :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>? 2, 1 i</head><label>1</label><figDesc>:= e i? : e j : e k [e j , e k ] l : : =: e i , e j : e k [e j , e k ] l : : + : ?k? j i : e k [e j , e k ] l : : + : e j : e i? e k [e j , e k ] l : + : e k e i? [e j , e k ] l : + ? 0 d? e i? e k ? [e j , e k ] l : + ? 0d? : e i , e j ? e k [e j , e k ] l : + : e k e i , e j ? [e j , e k ] l :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>, 3 i= 2 :</head><label>32</label><figDesc>e j : e k e j , e i , e k ? ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k l : :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head>2 k 2 :</head><label>22</label><figDesc>i , e j ? : + : e i , e j ? (Se j ) : + ? : e j e i , e j ? : +? e j , e i ? , e j l + e i , e j ? , e j ? + e j : e k e j , e i , e k ? ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k l : :+ : e j : e i , e k ? e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k e k , e j , e i ? ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head>Finally, to prove ( 3 .? 2 k 2 :</head><label>32</label><figDesc>30a), we use that S is an antiderivation of the product :: and (A.4): [H 0? e i ] = ? [e i???? H 0 ] = e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k l : : + : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : + : e i , e j ? : e k e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : + : e j : e k e k , e i ? , e j j e i , e j ? : ?2 : e j S e i , e j ? : +2T e j , e i , e j ? l + ? e j , e i , e j ? l + e i , e j ? , e j ? + (? + 2T + ?S) e i .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>Theorem 3 . 13 . 1 k 2 : 0 (I 1 +</head><label>3131201</label><figDesc>Assume that l ? l satisfies the F -term equation (2.31) and the D-term gravitino equation (2.32), and that w ? [l, l] ? ? [l, l] ? . Se j : + : e j (Se j ) : + + e j : e k e j , e k : : + : e j : e k e j , e k : : ? : e j : e k e j , e k : : ? : e j : e k [e j , e k ] : : + 1 k T w, induce an embbeding of the N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra with central charge c = 3 dim l into the universal superaffine vertex algebra V k (g super ) with level 0 = k ? C. Proof. By the Wick non-conmutative formula, it suffices to calculate H ? ? : e i e i : =: H ? ? e i e i : +(?1) (|H ? |+1) | e i | : e i [H ? ? e i ] : + ? 0 d? H ? ? e i ? e i : =: P + I, where I corresponds to the third summand in the first line. Firstly, we compute I = ? I 2 + I 3 ) d?, where</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>j e i , e j ? : ?2 : e j S e i , e j ? : ? 2 k 2 : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k l : : + : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : + : e i , e j ? : e k e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : + : e j : e k e k , e i ? , e j ? j , e i , e j ? l + e i , e j ? , e j ? + 2T e j , e i , e j ? l ,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head>I 3 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>= ? ? e i? : e j : e k e j , e i , e k ? l : : = k : e k e j , e j , e k ? l : ? : e j e j , e k , e k ? l := k : e j e k , e k , e j ? l :,I 4 1 := ? ? e i? : ej : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : = k : e k e j , e j ? , e k ? : ? : e j e k , e j ? , e k ? : = k : e j e k , e k , e j ? ? :, I 5 1 := ? ? e i? : e i , e j ? : e k e j , e k ? : : = ?k : e k , e j ? e j , e k ? : = k : e j , e k ? e k , e j ? := 0,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head>I 6 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>= ? ? e i? : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : = k : e k e j , e j , e k ? l : ? : e j e k , e k ? , e j l : = k : e j e k , e k , e j ? ? e i? : e j : e k e k , e i ? , e j ? : : = k : e j e k , e k ? , e j ? := 0. These equalities are derived combining the Wick non-conmutative formula, the D-term gravitino equation (2.32), (A.3), and the antisymmetry of the Lie bracket g. Combining the previous expressions, we have proved that I 1 = ? 2 k : e j e k , e k , e j ? l : .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_25"><head>P 1 :First, we can compute directly P 1 = ? 2 k 2 :: : e i : + 1 k</head><label>1121</label><figDesc>=: H 0? e j ? (? + 2T + ?S) e j e j : + : e j ([H 0? e j ] ? (? + 2T + ?S) e j ) :, P 2 :=: (H ? ? H 0 ) ? e j e j : + : e j [(H ? ? H 0 ) ? e j ] e j :, P 3 :=: (? + 2T + ?S) e j e j : + : e j ((? + 2T + ?S) e j ) : . e i : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k l : : + : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : + : e i , e j ? : e k e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : + : e j : e k e k , e i ? , e j ? : : : + : : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k l : : + : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : + : e i , e j ? : e k e j , e k ? : : + : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : + : e j : e k e k , e i ? , e j ? : e i ? : e j e i , e j ? : ?2 : e j S e i , e j ? : + + ? e j , e i , e j ? l + e i , e j ? , e j ? + 2T e j , e i , e j ? l : + : ? : e j e i , e j ? : ?2 : e j S e i , e j ? : + + ? e j , e i , e j ? l + e i , e j ? , e j ? + 2T e j , e i , e j ? l e i : reordering the terms and changing indices, we have Q =: e i : e j : e k e j , e i , e k ? l : : : + : e i : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : : + : e i : e j , e i ? : e k e k , e j ? : : : + : e i : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : : + : e i : e j : e k e k , e i ? , e j ? : : : + : : e j : e k e j , e i , e k ? l : : e i : + : : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : e i : + : : e i , e j ? : e k e j , e k ? : : e i : + : : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : e i : + : : e j : e k e k , e j , e i ? ? : : e i : R :=: ? : e j e k , e j ? : ?2 : e j S e k , e j ? : +? e j , e k , e j ? l + e k , e j ? , e j ? +2T e j , e k , e j ? l e k : + : e k ? : e j e k , e j ? : ?2 : e j S e k , e j ? : + ? e j , e k , e j ? l + e k , e j ? , e j ? + 2T e j , e k , e j ? l</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_26"><head>Q 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>=: e i : e j : e k e i , e j , e k ? l : : : + : e k : e i , e j , e k ? l : e j e i : : :,Q 3 :=: : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : e i : + : e j : e k : e i e i , e j ? , e k ? : : :, Q 4 :=: : e i , e j ? : e k e j , e k ? : : e i : + : e k : e j , e k ? : e i e i , e j ? : : :, Q 5 :=: : e j : e k e i , e j ? , e k ? : : e i : + : e j : e i : e k e j , e i ? , e k ? : : : . Applying (A.11), (A.10) and (A.7) in this order, we obtain Q 1 = 0, while applying (A.10), (A.8), (A.11) and (A.7) in this order, we obtain Q 2 = 0. By (A.11), (A.7) and (A.3) in this order, we obtain Q 3 = ?kT : e j e k , e j ? , e k ? : . Similarly, applying (A.5), (A.7), (A.11) and (A.7) in this order, we obtain Q 4 = 0, while applying (A.11), (A.7), (A.9) and antisymmetry of the bracket in this order, we obtain Q 5 = 0. Putting all together, we have that Q = Q 3 = ?kT : e j e k , e j ? , e k ? : . (0,2) MIRROR SYMMETRY ON HOMOGENEOUS HOPF SURFACES 33</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_27"><head>R 2 :R 4 =:?, 2 :</head><label>242</label><figDesc>=: : e j S e k , e j ? : e k : + : e k : e j S e k , e j ? : :, R 3 :=: e j , e k , e j ? l e k : + : e k e j , e k , e j? l : + : e k , e j ? , e j ? e k : + : e k e k , e j ? , e j ? :, R 4 :=: T e j , e k , e j ? l e j : + : e k T e j , e k , e j ? l : . Applying (A.7) and (A.3) we have that R 1 = 0, while applying (A.6) and (A.4), we obtain R 2 = T : e j e k , e j ? , e k : . By antisymmetry and invariance, we trivially have that R 3 = 2 : e j , e k , e j ? l e k : + : e j , e k ? , e k ? e j : + : e j e j , e k ? , e k ? :, T : e j e k , e j ? , e k l : . Putting all together, by Remark 2.22, we have that R = ? 2 : e j , e k , e j ? l e k : + : e j , e k ? , e k ? e j : + : e j e j , e k ? , e k ? 2T : e j e k , e j ? , e k ? e j , e k , e j ? l e k : + : e j , e k ? , e k ? e j : + : e j e j , e k ? , e k ? :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_28"><head>Lemma 3 . 15 .</head><label>315</label><figDesc>Assume that l ? l satisfies the D-term dilatino equation (2.33) and that ? ? l ? l is holomorphic (Definition 2.25). Then H = H 0 , where the vectors H and H 0 are defined in (3.26) and (3.20), respectively. Furthermore, the constant c in (3.25) equals c = 3 dim l + 12 k (e|e).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_29"><head>( 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33</ref>) is equivalent to [e j , e j ] + = 2u and, equivalently, to w = 2e.(3.32)The lemma follows from (3.31) and(3.25).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_30"><head>Theorem 3 . 16 .= i k : e j e j : ? 2 1 k 2 :</head><label>316212</label><figDesc>Assume that l ? l satisfies the F -term equation (2.31) and the D-term equation (2.34), and that ? ? l ? l is holomorphic. Then the vectors J Se j : + : e j (Se j ) : + e j : e k e j , e k : : + : e j : e k e j , e k : : ? : e j : e k e j , e k : : ? : e j : e k [e j , e k ] : : , induce an embbeding of the N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra with central charge c = 3 dim l + 4 k (e|e) . (3.33)into the universal superaffine vertex algebra V k (g super ) with level 0 = k ? C.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_31"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>[e ? J 0 ] = e e k [e k? J 0 ] + (e|e k ) e k ? J 0 = i k e e k : e k , e j e j : + : e j [e k , e j ] : +k?e k + k? e k e j , e j + (e|e k ) : e k , e j e j : + : e j e k , e j : ?k?e k + k? e k e j , e j = i?u + i? e e j , e j .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_32"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>[e ? u] = [e, u] + k?(e|u) = [e, u] + .Applying now the D-term equation (3.32), we obtain the required identity (3.28b):[H ? J] = [H ? ? J 0 ] ? i 2 k (S + ?) [H ? ? u] + 2 k ? [e ? J 0 ] ? i4 k 2 ? (? + S) [e, u] = ?i 4 k 2 ? (S + ?) [u, e] + + [e, u] + + (2? + 2T + ?S) J = (2? + 2T + ?S) J. The formulae for H and the central charge follow from Lemma 3.15.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_33"><head>Remark 3 . 17 .</head><label>317</label><figDesc>Assume that l ? l satisfies the F -term equation (2.31) and the D-term gravitino equation (2.32) and that ? ? l ? l is holomorphic. Then, by the proof of the previous theorem, there is an embedding of the N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra generated by (J, H) with central charge(3.25), where H is defined by (3.31), on the universal superaffine vertex algebra V k (g super ) with level 0 = k ? C.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_34"><head>4 . 1 .</head><label>41</label><figDesc>Examples of (0, 2) mirror symmetry 4.Killing spinors on exact Courant algebroids. In this section we study the Killing spinor equations on an exact Courant algebroid</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_36"><head>Definition 4 . 4 .</head><label>44</label><figDesc>Let M be a smooth oriented spin manifold endowed with an exact Courant algebroid E. A triple (V + , div ? , ?), given by a generalized metric V + , a partial divergence operator div ? , and a non-vanishing spinor ? ? S ? , is a solution of the Killing spinor equations,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_37"><head>Proposition 4 . 5 .</head><label>45</label><figDesc>Let M be a smooth oriented spin manifold endowed with a left transitive action of a Lie group K. Let E be an exact equivariant Courant algebroid over M. Then, the space of invariant sections g = ?(E) K of E, endowed with the induced bracket and pairing, defines a quadratic Lie algebra. Furthermore, there is a one-to-one correspondence between invariant solutions of (4.6) and solutions to the Killing spinor equations (2.16) on g.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_39"><head>(4. 11 )</head><label>11</label><figDesc>This corresponds to a constant multiple of the Cartan three-form on the SU(2) factor, and hence it is bi-invariant and closed. Thus, it defines an equivariant Courant algebroid E ? = T ? T * , with pairing and Dorfman bracket as in (4.2) (with H = H ? ).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_40"><head>Lemma 4 . 8 .</head><label>48</label><figDesc>Denote by ? x ? S + + a non-vanishing pure spinor in the spinor line determined by J x . Then, (V x,a + , ? x + , ? x ) is a solution of the Killing spinor equations (2.16) on g ? if and only if ? = a/x. Consequently, (V x,a + , div x,a + , ? x ) is a left-invariant solution of the Killing spinor equations (4.6) on E ? if and only if ? = a/x. Proof. By Proposition 2.19, it suffices to prove that (2.26) holds if and only</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_41"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>it follows that the second equation in (2.26) holds. The last part of the statement follows by direct application of Proposition 4.5.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_42"><head>Definition 4 . 10 .</head><label>410</label><figDesc>Consider the fibre product M = M ? BM and the diagram We say that two pairs (M, ? ) and (M ,? ) as above are T-dual if there exists representatives H ? ? 3 (M) T k and? ? ? 3 (M )T k of ? and? , respectively, such that</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_43"><head>Theorem 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>11 ([15]). Let E ? M and? ?M be equivariant exact Courant algebroids. Assume that (M, [E]) is T-dual to (M, [?]). Then there exists a canonical isomorphism of Courant algebroids between the simple reductions ? : E/T k ??/T k .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_45"><head>Lemma 4 . 12 .</head><label>412</label><figDesc>For any ? ? R, the pair (K, [H ? ]) is self-T-dual. Proof. We regard the correspondence space K in Definition 4.10 inside the Lie group ? : K ?? K ?K, whereK denotes another copy of K. Then, define B as the pull-back to K of a left-invariant two-form B = ?? * (v 4 ?v 4 ). (4.24) Then we have dB = 0 = p * H ? ?p * ? ? , where we used that H ? and? ? are both pull-back of the same three-form on B = SU(2).The non-degeneracy condition on B follows from the fact that this two-form is bi-invariant.We are ready to construct our pairs of T-dual solutions of the Killing spinor equations on the compact Lie group K.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_46"><head>Proposition 4 . 13 .</head><label>413</label><figDesc>Given 0 &lt; ? ? R, consider the equivariant exact Courant algebroid E ? over K. Then two solutions (V x + , div x + , ? x ) and (Vx + , divx + , ?x) of the Killing spinor equations (4.6) on E ? in Lemma 4.8 are exchanged under T-duality, provided that</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_47"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>generated by C ? (M) ? ?(?E) with the relation Sf = Df for all f ? C ? (M).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_48"><head>Proposition 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>15 ([34]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_50"><head>Theorem 4 . 18 .</head><label>418</label><figDesc>Given 0 &lt; ? ? R, consider the one-parameter family of solutions of the Killing spinor equations (V x + , div x + , J x ) on E ? in Lemma 4.8 parametrized by x &gt; 0. Then (V x + , div x + , J x ) and (Vx + , divx + , ?Jx)are related by (0, 2) mirror symmetry provided thatx = 1/?x. More precisely, if we denoteJ = J(V x + , div x + , J x ), H = H(V x + , div x + , J x ) J = J(Vx + , divx + ,?Jx),? = H(Vx + , divx + , ?Jx) the generators of the N = 2 superconformal vertex algebras with central charge c = 6 + 6/? constructed in Theorem 3.16, then the Linshaw-Mathai isomorphism (4.30) realises the mirror involution ? ch (J) = ?? , ? ch (H) =?. (4.31)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_51"><head>Theorem 4 . 21 .</head><label>421</label><figDesc>Given 0 &lt; ?, x ? R, setx = 1/?x and consider the pair of (0, 2) mirrors(V x + , div x + , J x ) and (Vx + , divx + , ?Jx) inTheorem 4.18. Then, the Linshaw-Mathai isomorphism (4.30) induces isomorphisms of sheaves of SUSY vertex algebras</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_52"><head>Lemma 4 . 23 .</head><label>423</label><figDesc>For any ?, x &gt; 0, (V x + , div x + , I), (V x + , div x + , J), and (V x + , div x + , K) are leftinvariant solutions of the Killing spinor equations (4.6) on E ? . Consequently, (I, J, K) is a hyperholomorphic structure compatible with g x and fixed Lee form ? = ?xv 4 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_53"><head>w 3 +x w 4 + ?x 2 w 4 w 2 + ?w 2 w 1 +x w 4 + ?x 2 w 4 w 3 +w 3 + ?w 3 w 1 + ?w 1 : ? 1 ? : w 3 +w 4 + ?x 2 w 4 w 2 + ?w 2 : ? 1 ?x : w 4 +</head><label>34221431134214</label><figDesc>the generators of each N = 2 superconformal vertex algebra constructed in Theorem 3.13, then H ? I = H ? J = H ? K and furthermoreJ I 0 ? J J 0 = ? (2? + S) J K 0 I 0 = ? (2? + S) J J 0 .Proof. Similarly as in the proof of Theorem 4.18 we obtain the explicit formulae: ?w 3 w 1 + ?w 1 : + : 1 ?w 1 w 2 + ?w 2 : + : 1 ?w 3 : .We compute J I 0 ? J J 0 and leave the rest of ?-brackets as an exercise for the reader. By the Wick non-conmutative formula, we have ?w 3 J I 0 ? w 1 + ?w 1 : ?x 2 w 4 J I 0 ? w 2 + ?w 2 :+ 1 ?x ? 0 d? J I 0 ? w 4 + ?x 2 w 4 ? w 2 + ?w 2 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_54"><head>3 + ?w 3 ? J I 0 = ?? w 2 + ?w 2 + 1 2? : w 1 + ?w 1 w 3 + ?w 3 4 + ?x 2 w 4 w 2 +? 1 x w 4 + 1 2? : w 2 + 4 + ?x 2 w 4 w 3 + 2 + ?w 2 : ? 1 x ? : w 4 +</head><label>3021133424124324</label><figDesc>?w 2 : ,w 1 + ?w 1 ? J I 0 = ?? ? ?x 2 w 4 , w 2 + ?w 2 ? J I 0 = ? w 3 + ?w 3 ? ?w 2 w 1 + ?w 1 : ?w 3 : , w 4 + ?x 2 w 4 ? J I 0 = x? w 1 + ?w 1 .Combining the Wick non-conmutative formula, the antisymmetry of ?-bracket, (A.3), and (A.4), we concludeJ I 0 ? J J 0 = 1 2? ? : w 2 + ?w 2 w 1 + ?w 1 : + : S w 2 + ?w 2 w 1 + ?w 1 : + 1 x ? : w 3 + ?w 3 w 4 + ?x 2 w 4 : ? : w 3 + ?w 3 S w 4 + ?x 2 w 4 : ? (? + T ) w 3 + ?w 3 + ? w 3 + ?w 3 ? ? ? : w 1 + ?w 1 w 2 + ?w 2 : ? : S w 1 + ?w 1 w ?x 2 w 4 w 3 + ?w 3 : ? : w 4 + ?x 2 w 4 S w 3 + ?w 3 := ? (2? + S) J K 0 , because S is an antiderivation for the normally ordered product. Finally, the identity H ? I = H ? J = H ? K follows calculating a basis as in (2.23) in each case and substituting in the formula(3.29).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_55"><head>Remark 4 . 25 .A. 2 . 1 ?</head><label>42521</label><figDesc>It is interesting to observe that the method of Proposition 4.24 does not apply to the family of N = 2 superconformal structures with central charge c = 6 + 6/? in Theorem 4.18. This seems to agree with the analysis of the Sevrin-Troost-Van Proeyen algebra made in<ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13,</ref> Section 8]. Note also that the value of the central charge c = 6 of our family of N = 4 algebras coincides with the expected value from superstring theory. Proposition 4.24 suggests a generalization of Theorem 3.13 for N = 4 algebras, when dim V + = 4k and G ? = Sp(k) in Lemma 2.14 (cf. Remark 2.15). Here Sp(k) denotes the compact symplectic group. We hope to go back to this question in future work.Appendix A. Rules and identities on supersymmetric vertex algebras In this appendix, we collect relevant remarks and identities about SUSY vertex algebras, especially in the case of the universal superaffine vertex algebras. A.1. SUSY Lie conformal algebras. Given a SUSY Lie conformal algebra R, the terms in (3.4), (3.5) and (3.6) are calculated as follows (see [36, Def. 4.10] for details): ? Sesquilinearity. To obtain (S + ?)[a ? b] as an element of L ? R in (3.4), we first calculate the ?-bracket and then commute S with ? and ? to the right using the relations [S, ?] = 0 and [S, ?] = 2?. ? Skew-symmetry. To obtain [b ???? a] as an element of L?R in (3.5), we first expand [b ? a] = n,J ? n|J c n|J in L ? ? R using the relations [?, ?] = 0, [?, ?] = ?2?, for a copy L ? of L with the formal variables ? = (?, ?) replaced by ? = (?, ?), and then replace ? by ?? ? ? = (?? ? T, ?? ? S) and apply T and S to the coefficients c n|J ? R. ? Jacobi identity. To obtain [a ? b] ?+? c ? L ? L ? ? R in (3.6), we first calculate [[a ? b] ? c] ? L ? L ?? ? V , where L ?? is another copy of L with the formal variables ? replaced by ?, and then replace ? by ? + ? = (? + ?, ? + ?) and use the relations [?, ?] = [?, ?] = [?, ?] = [?, ?] = 0. To calculate the other two terms in (3.6) as elements of L ? L ? ? R, we use the relations [?, ?] = [?, ?] = [?, ?] = [?, ?] = 0 and [a ? q(?)b] = (?1) |q|(|a|+1) q(?)[a ? b] (A.1) for any homogeneous polynomial q(?) in ? (this formula follows applying the Koszul rule to the odd ?-bracket [36, Remark 4.9]). SUSY vertex algebras. Given a SUSY vertex algebra V , the terms in (3.8), (3.9) and (3.10) are calculated as follows (see [36, (3.3.3.2); Theorem 3.3.14; (3.2.6.12)] for details): ? Quasiconmutativity. To compute the integral in (3.8), we use the expansion [b ? a] = n,J ? n|J c n|J in L ? V , and on each term A = ? n|J c n|J ? L ? V , we use the formula (left) partial derivative with respect to the odd variable ?, performing the inddefinite integral in the even variable ?, and taking the difference of the values at the limits. ? Quasiassociativity. The integrals in (3.9) are computed by expanding the ?brackets, putting the powers of ? on the left under the integral sign, and taking the definite integral as in (A.2). ? The non-conmutative Wick formula. To compute the integral in (3.10), we expand [[a ? b] ? c] = j,k?Z J,K=0,j|J ? k|K c j|J,k|K as an element of L ? L ? ? V , using the relations [?, ?] = [?, ?] = [?, ?] = [?, ?] = 0 and (A.1), and take the definite integral of each term as in (A.2).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_56"><head>Lemma A. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>For all a, b, c ? ?g, the following identities hold: : ab : = ? : ba : (A.3) : a (Sb) : =: (Sb) a : +T [a, b] (A.4) : a (: bc :) : =: (: bc :) a : +kT ((a|b)c ? (a|c)b) (A.5) : (: a (Sb) :) c : =: a (: (Sb) c :) : + : (T a) [b, c] : +kT (a|c)Sb (A.6) : (: ab :) c : =: a (: bc :) : +kT ((c|b)a ? (c|a)b) (A.7) : a (: bc :) : =: b (: ca :) := = ? : b (: ac :) : (A.8) : a (: bc :) : =: c (: ab :) := = ? : c (: ba :) : (A.9) Proof. The first three equalities (A.3), (A.4) and (A.5) are inmediate consequences of the quasiconmutativity, while (A.6) and (A.7) follow from the quasiassociativity. The last two identities (A.8) and (A.9) are obtained applying the previous ones. Lemma A.2. For all a, b, c, d ? ?g, the following identities hold: : a (: (: bc :) d :) := ? : (: (: bc :) d :) a : +k ((a|b)T (: cd :) ? (a|c)T (: bd :) + (a|d)T (: bc :)) . (A.10) : (: a (: bc :) :) d :=: a (: (: bc :) d :) : +k (: (T a) ((d|c)b ? (d|b)c) : +(a|d)T (: bc :)) . (A.11)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>= H 0,3 and H 2,1 = H 1,2 . Using the identities</figDesc><table><row><cell>where H 3,0</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Then, by Lemma 2.16, the dilatino equation is equivalent to</cell></row><row><cell>1 6</cell><cell>H ? ? = ? + ? ?.</cell></row><row><cell>Decompose H as</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">? = H 3,0 + H 2,1 + H 1,2 + H 0,3 ,</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The properties of the first operation motivate the definition [36, Def. 4.10] of a SUSY Lie conformal algebra as the data given by a supermodule R over H and a parity-reversing bilinear map</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the SUSY vertex algebra generated by R [36, ?1.8], or more precisely, V (R) is the universal enveloping SUSY vertex algebra of R [36, Theorem 3.4.2 and ?4.21].Next we describe several SUSY vertex algebras used in this paper.Example 3.1. The N = 1 superconformal vertex algebra of central charge c, also called the Neveu-Schwarz vertex algebra (see, e.g., [41, pp. 178-179], [36, Example 2.4]), is generated by the SUSY Lie conformal algebra R whose underlying H-module is freely generated by an odd vector H and a scalar c, with ?-bracket Expanding in components the corresponding superfield Y (H, Z) = G(z) + 2?L(z), and the field components in Fourier modes</figDesc><table><row><cell>?? 2 3</cell><cell>c.</cell><cell>(3.11)</cell></row></table><note>[H ? H] = (2T + ?S + 3?) H +</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Killing spinors on homogeneous Hopf surfaces. We present a family of solutions of the Killing spinor equations (4.6) on a four-dimensional compact Lie group, such that the triple (V + , div + , ?) is left-invariant, and Proposition 4.5 and Proposition 4.6 apply.</figDesc><table /><note>24, Theorem 5.1], using Gauduchon's formula for the Bismut connection on the canonical bundle.4.2.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The solutions of the Killing spinor equations (V x + , div x + , J x ) constructed in Lemma 4.8 (see(4.15)) are such that the corresponding divergence ? + ? V x + is holomorphic in the sense of Definition 2.25 (see Lemma 4.9), and hence Theorem 3.16 applies. The formula for the central charge follows from(3.33)    To see this, we write w j = ?v j and w j = ?v j for all j ? {1, 2, 3, 4}, where the v j , v j are as in Section 4.1. Applying (A.3) and setting a = ?x, a simple calculation shows that Now, using that ? ch is an isomorphism of SUSY vertex algebras (that is, in particular, is an homomorphism for the normally ordered product and S? ch = ? ch S), we obtain that To finish this section, we show that the (0, 2) mirrors constructed in Theorem 4.18 have isomorphic T 1 -equivariant half-twisted models. For the rigorous definition of the halftwisted model as a holomorphic sheaf of vertex algebras we follow<ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38,</ref> Section 8]. Consider the operators</figDesc><table><row><cell>J =</cell><cell>1 2</cell><cell>1 ?</cell><cell cols="7">: w 2 w 3 : + : w 2 w 3 : + : w 2 w 3 : +</cell><cell>a x</cell><cell>: w 2 w 3 :</cell></row><row><cell>+</cell><cell>1 a</cell><cell cols="2">: w 4 w 1 : +</cell><cell>1 x</cell><cell cols="5">: w 4 w 1 : +x : w 4 w 1 : +a : w 4 w 1 : ?</cell><cell>1 2</cell><cell>S</cell><cell>1 ?</cell><cell>w 1 + w 1 ,</cell></row><row><cell>J =</cell><cell>1 2</cell><cell>1 ?</cell><cell cols="7">: w 2 w 3 : + : w 2 w 3 : + : w 2 w 3 : +</cell><cell>a x</cell><cell>: w 2 w 3 :</cell></row><row><cell cols="6">+ x : w 4 w 1 : +a : w 4 w 1 : +</cell><cell>1 a</cell><cell cols="2">: w 4 w 1 : +</cell><cell>1 x</cell><cell>: w 4 w 1 : ?</cell><cell>1 2</cell><cell>S</cell><cell>1 ??</cell><cell>1 +? 1 .</cell></row><row><cell>? ch (J) =</cell><cell>1 2</cell><cell>1 ?</cell><cell cols="7">: w 2 w 3 : + : w 2 w 3 : + : w 2 w 3 : +</cell><cell>a x</cell><cell>: w 2 w 3 :</cell></row><row><cell>+</cell><cell>1 a</cell><cell cols="2">: w 4 w 1 : +</cell><cell>1 x</cell><cell cols="5">: w 4 w 1 : +x : w 4 w 1 : +a : w 4 w 1 : ?</cell><cell>1 2</cell><cell>S</cell><cell>1 ??</cell><cell>1 +? 1 =J.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="5">c = 3 2 + 2 ? x + ? x +</cell><cell cols="2">= 6 + 6x 2 1 x 2 ?</cell><cell>= 6 + 6/?.</cell></row><row><cell cols="10">Observe that the expansion in Fourier modes of (4.31) recovers (1.1) (see Example 3.2).</cell></row><row><cell cols="8">By (4.29) it suffices to prove the identity</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>? ch (J) =J := J(Vx + , divx + , Jx).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>) defined by the Fourier modes of J and H in Theorem 4.18 (see Example 3.2). Definition 4.19. Given 0 &lt; ?, x ? R, consider the solution of the Killing spinor equations (V x + , div x + , J x ) on E ? in Lemma 4.8. (1) The equivariant A-half twisted model of (V x + , div x + , J x ) is the sheaf of SUSY vertex algebras given by the cohomology</figDesc><table><row><cell>32)</cell></row><row><cell>on ? ch K (E ?</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Similarly as in Proposition 4.16, Q x,? (resp. Q x,? ) has an associated holomorphic sheaf of SUSY vertex algebras ? ch Xx (Q x,? ) over X x (resp. ? ch Xx (Q x,? ) over X x ). As in [46, Section 4.2], we can define subsheaves? ch Xx (Q x,? ) T 1 ? ? ch Xx (Q x,? ), ? ch Xx (Q x,? ) T 1 ? ? ch Xx (Q x,? )as the commutants with the zero mode of ?v 4 , where v 4 is the holomorphic vector field generating the T 1 -action. The next result is a direct consequence of<ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38,</ref> Proposition 13].</figDesc><table><row><cell>Proposition 4.20 ([38]). There are canonical isomorphisms of sheaves of SUSY vertex</cell></row><row><cell>algebras</cell></row><row><cell>? T 1</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> <ref type="bibr">Proposition 4.16 ([34]</ref><p>). Let E be an exact Courant algebroid over M, and R be the corresponding sheaf of SUSY Lie conformal algebras constructed above. Let U be the universal enveloping SUSY vertex algebra associated to R <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>. We define ? ch M (E) to be the quotient of U by the ideal generated by the relations (f, g ? C ? (M), A ? C ? (?E), and 1 M is the constant function 1)</p><p>To relate this with our results from the previous section, assume now that our manifold M is a compact Lie group K, and let E be a left-equivariant Courant algebroid over K. By Proposition 4.5, we can associate to E a quadratic Lie algebra given by the invariant</p><p>Applying the universal construction in Proposition 4.16, we obtain an embedding of the universal superaffine vertex algebra V 2 (g super ) of level k = 2.</p><p>Proposition 4.17. Let K be a compact Lie group and E a left-equivariant Courant algebroid over K. Then there is an embedding</p><p>Proof. By Example 3.5 we have an embedding of the Lie conformal algebra SCurg localized at k = 2 into the SUSY Lie conformal algebra R in Proposition 4.15. Furthermore, by the universal construction there is a canonical embedding R ?? H 0 (K, ? ch K (E)). Now, being V 2 (g super ) the universal enveloping SUSY vertex algebra of SCurg of level k = 2, this induces an embedding as in the statement. Indeed, this follows from the following universal property: any monomorphism from a SUSY Lie conformal algebraR into a SUSY vertex algebra can be extended to a unique SUSY vertex algebra monomorphism from the universal enveloping SUSY vertex algebra ofR.</p><p>We are ready to prove our main result, which gives our examples of (0, 2) mirror pairs on compact non-K?hler manifolds. Our result is based on two basic observations combined with a theorem by Linshaw and Mathai which provides a stronger version of Theorem 4.11 in terms of the chiral de Rham complex <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[46]</ref>. </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2) Duality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sethi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Theor. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="865" to="950" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On a Complex-Symplectic Mirror Pair</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Aldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Heluani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. Math. Res. Not</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6934" to="6960" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Derived brackets and courant algebroids</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Alekseev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.math.psu.edu/ping/anton-final.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On Bott-Chern cohomology of compact complex surfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Angella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dloussky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tomassini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann. Mat. Pura Appl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">195</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-K?hler Mirror Symmetry: the Hopf surface, talk at the &apos;Fukaya Categories: Coefficients</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Auroux</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Skeleta, Stability Conditions&apos;, Simons Collaboration on Homological Mirror Symmetry</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>IHES, Bures-sur-Yvette</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Field Algebras</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bakalov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kac</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. Math. Res. Not</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supersymmetry of the chiral de Rham complex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ben-Zvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Heluani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Szczesny</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Compositio Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">144</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="521" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">N = 1 Neveu-Schwarz vertex operator superalgebras over Grassmann algebras and with odd formal variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Barron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Representations and Quantizations</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Shanghai; Beijing</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>China High. Educ. Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="35" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vertex algebras and mirror symmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Borisov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">215</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On CY-LG correspondence for (0,2) toric mirror models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Borisov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kaufmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">230</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="531" to="551" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Elliptic genera of toric varieties and applications to mirror symmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Borisov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Libgober</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Invent. Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="485" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">T-duality: topology change from H-flux</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bouwknegt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Evslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mathai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">249</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="415" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supersymmetric string solitons</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Harvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strominger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings, String theory and quantum gravity</title>
		<meeting>String theory and quantum gravity<address><addrLine>Trieste</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="244" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A pair of Calabi-Yau manifolds as an exactely soluble superconformal field theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Candelas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>De La Ossa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Parkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">359</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized complex geometry and T-duality, In A Celebration of the Mathematical Legacy of Raoul Bott</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cavalcanti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gualtieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CRM Proceedings &amp; Lecture Notes)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supergravity as Generalised Geometry I: Type II Theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Coimbra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Strickland-Constable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Waldram</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">91</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">F Terms and D Terms in String Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ichinose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Seiberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">293</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="265" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A mathematical theory of quantum sheaf cohomology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Donagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guffin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sharpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Asian J. Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="418" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Invariant Solutions to the Strominger System on Complex Lie Groups and Their Quotients</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Fei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-T</forename><surname>Yau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">338</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1183" to="1195" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">,2)-trialities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gadde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gukov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Putrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1403</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">76</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Torsion-free generalized connections and heterotic supergravity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Garcia-Fernandez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">332</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Killing spinors, and T-duality in generalized geometry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ricci</forename><surname>Flow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">350</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1059" to="1108" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">T-dual solutions of the Hull-Strominger system on non-K?hler threefolds</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Reine Angew. Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">776</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="150" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Infinitesimal moduli for the Strominger system and Killing spinors in generalized geometry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Garcia-Fernandez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Rubio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tipler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Math. Ann</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">369</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="539" to="595" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Holomorphic string algebroids</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trans. Amer. Math. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7347" to="7382" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Garcia-Fernandez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Rubio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shahbazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tipler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1803.01873</idno>
		<title level="m">Canonical metrics on holomorphic Courant algebroids</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Heterotic supergravity and moduli stabilization</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>to appear</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Garcia-Fernandez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2008.07004</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Streets, Generalized Ricci flow</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manin Pairs and Topological Conformal Field Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Getzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">237</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="201" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gerbes of chiral differential operators. II. Vertex algebroids</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Gorbounov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Malikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Schechtman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Invent. Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">155</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="605" to="680" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sharpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1908.06036</idno>
		<title level="m">A proposal for nonabelian (0, 2)-mirrors</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The many facets of geometry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gualtieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Branes on Poisson varieties</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Oxford</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford Univ. Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="368" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized K?hler Geometry</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supersymmetry of the chiral de Rham complex II: Commuting sectors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Heluani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. Math. Res. Not</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="953" to="987" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recent advances and open questions on the susy structure of the chiral de Rham Complex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Heluani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. A: Math. Theor</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">423002</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supersymmetric vertex algebras</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Heluani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kac</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">271</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized Calabi-Yau manifolds and the chiral De Rham complex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Heluani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zabzine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">223</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1815" to="1844" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Superconformal Structures on Generalized Calabi-Yau Metric Manifolds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Heluani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zabzine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">306</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="364" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized Calabi-Yau manifolds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Hitchin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Q. J. Math</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="308" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Superstring compactifications with torsion and space-time supersymmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hull</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Turin 1985 Proceedings &quot;Superunification and Extra Dimensions</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="375" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vertex algebras for beginners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kac</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">University Lecture series</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Amer. Math. Soc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Second Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Chiral de Rham complex and the half-twisted sigma-model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kapustin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>arXiv:0504074</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">CALT-68-2547</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Homological Algebra of Mirror Symmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kontsevich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Congress of Mathematicians</title>
		<editor>Chatterji S.D.</editor>
		<meeting>the International Congress of Mathematicians</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Birkh?user</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-Kaehler SYZ mirror symmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-C</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L.-S</forename><surname>Tseng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-T</forename><surname>Yau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">340</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="170" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Michelsohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Spin geometry, 38 of Princeton Mathematical Series</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Princeton, N. J.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twisted Chiral de Rham Complex, Generalized Geometry, and T-duality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Linshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mathai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">339</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="663" to="697" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chiral de Rham complex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Malikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Schechtman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vaintrob</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comm. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">204</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="439" to="473" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The revival of (0,2) linear ?-models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcorist</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Mod. Phys. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An introduction to two-dimensional quantum field theory with (0,2) supersymmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Melnikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lecture Notes in Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">951</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A (0, 2) mirror map</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Melnikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Plesser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Melnikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sethi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sharpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">68</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>SIGMA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Recent developments in (0,2) mirror symmetry</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Invariant solutions to the Strominger system and the heterotic equations of motion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Otal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ugarte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Villacampa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">920</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="474" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Geometric flows and Strominger systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D.-H</forename><surname>Phong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Picard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Math. Z</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">288</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-K?hler Mirror Symmetry of the Iwasawa Manifold</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Popovici</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/imrn/rny256</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/imrn/rny256" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. Math. Res. Notices</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Poisson-Lie T-duality, and type II supergravities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>?evera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Valach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Courant algebroids</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="344" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Superconformal Algebras in Two Dimensions with N = 4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sevrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Troost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Van Proeyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">208</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">447</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Superstrings with torsion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strominger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">274</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mirror symmetry is T-Duality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strominger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-T</forename><surname>Yau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zaslow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucl. Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">479</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="259" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two-dimensional twisted sigma models, the mirror chiral de Rham complex, and twisted generalized mirror symmetry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-C</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JHEP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">07</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Homological mirror symmetry for elliptic Hopf surfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Stanford University Thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Mirror manifolds and topological field theory</title>
		<editor>S. T. Yau</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Hong Kong</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>International Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="158" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Essays on Mirror Manifolds</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Phases of N = 2 theories in two dimensions</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nuclear Phys. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">403</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="222" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two dimensional models with (0,2) supersymmetry: perturbative aspects</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Theor. Math. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
