<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning Cross-Video Neural Representations for High-Quality Frame Interpolation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wentao</forename><surname>Shangguan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Washington University in St. Louis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>63130</postCode>
									<region>MO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Washington University in St. Louis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>63130</postCode>
									<region>MO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weijie</forename><surname>Gan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Washington University in St. Louis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>63130</postCode>
									<region>MO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulugbek</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kamilov</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Washington University in St. Louis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>63130</postCode>
									<region>MO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Washington University in St. Louis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>63130</postCode>
									<region>MO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning Cross-Video Neural Representations for High-Quality Frame Interpolation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>* These authors have contributed equally to the work and are ordered alphabetically</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2022-11-12T09:43+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper considers the problem of temporal video interpolation, where the goal is to synthesize a new video frame given its two neighbors. We propose Cross-Video Neural Representation (CURE) as the first video interpolation method based on neural fields (NF). NF refers to the recent class of methods for neural representation of complex 3D scenes that has seen widespread success and application across computer vision. CURE represents the video as a continuous function parameterized by a coordinate-based neural network, whose inputs are the spatiotemporal coordinates and outputs are the corresponding RGB values. CURE introduces a new architecture that conditions the neural network on the input frames for imposing space-time consistency in the synthesized video. This not only improves the final interpolation quality, but also enables CURE to learn a prior across multiple videos. Experimental evaluations show that CURE achieves the state-of-the-art performance on video interpolation on several benchmark datasets.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The problem of temporal video interpolation seeks to synthesize new video frames given the observation of the neighboring frames. Video interpolation is crucial for many applications, including video compression <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref>, frame-rate conversion <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[3]</ref>, novel view synthesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref>, and frame recovery <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[49]</ref>. Traditional video interpolation approaches have considered variational optimization <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[2]</ref>, nearest neighbor search <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[5]</ref>, or kernel filtering <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[47]</ref>. Recent work in the area has focused on deep learning (DL), where convolutional neural networks (CNNs) are trained to synthesize the desired frames. Two most widely-used classes of DL video interpolation methods are kernel-based <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32]</ref> or flow-based <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">48,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">1]</ref> methods. NSFF ABME CURE CURE NSFF ABME <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 1</ref>: Visual illustration of a frame interpolated by CURE, NSFF <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref>, and AMBE <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[34]</ref>. NSFF and AMBE are the state-of-the-art methods for dynamic-scene view synthesis and video interpolation, respectively. Note how CURE substantially improves the visual quality and reduces the residual error in the second row.</p><p>There has been considerable recent interest in the class of methods known as neural fields (NF) <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[44,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35]</ref>. NF seeks to represent varying physical quantities of spatial and temporal coordinates using fully-connected coordinate-based neural networks. The NF neural networks take spatial or temporal coordinates at the input and produce the corresponding physical quantity at the output. This coordinate-based representation frees NF methods from pre-defined pixel/voxel grids, thus enabling the learning of continuous fields from discrete observations. For example, the popular neural radiance fields (NeRF) <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27]</ref> and its various extensions <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">25]</ref> have achieved the state-of-the-art results in synthesizing novel views of complex 3D scenes from a set of 2D images. The NF approach has also been extended to the video setting by learning the representation of temporally-varying scenes from a set of videos <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">50,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">37,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">16]</ref>. Despite the recent activity, to the best of our knowledge, there is no NF method for temporal video interpolation that jointly addresses the lack of the camera-pose information, the need for test-time optimization, and the use of priors on the unknown video frames.</p><p>In this paper, we propose Cross-Video Neural Representation (CURE) as a novel NF method for high-quality temporal video interpolation. Unlike traditional NF methods for representing dynamic scenes, CURE uses a deep neural network to directly represent a video as a continuous function of time and space. This conceptual change significantly simplifies the setup by circumventing the reliance on the camera pose information, which is usually difficult to estimate in certain applications such as handheld filming. The direct application of NF to video interpolation leads to poor performance due to the challenge of representing complex space-time variations from limited data. CURE addresses this issue by introducing a novel strategy based on conditioning the neural field on the input frames using our spatiotemporal encoding module <ref type="bibr">(STEM)</ref>. For each queried pixel, STEM generates a local feature code that contains the spatial information around the pixel as well as the temporal information from the neighboring frames. STEM thus incorporates a space-time consistency prior into the representation network for mitigating visual artifacts. The architecture of conditioning also allows CURE to learn a video prior across different videos, enabling fast frame interpolation with a simple feed-forward pass. This is fundamentally different from the traditional NF approach of optimizing the weights of neural network for every new test video, thus making the inference computationally expensive. Contributions: The technical contributions of this work are as follows:</p><p>1. We propose CURE as a novel NF approach for temporal video interpolation without any information on the camera pose. CURE is fundamentally different from the existing flow-based and kernel-based DL approaches.</p><p>2. We develop a new architecture for CURE that leverages prior information over video frames, thus enforcing plausibility of the synthesized frames. The prior is obtained by conditioning the neural network on local feature codes encoding both temporal and spatial information extracted from the neighboring frames.</p><p>3. We perform extensive validation of CURE on several benchmark datasets, including UCF101 <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[45]</ref>, Vimeo90K <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[51]</ref>, SNU Films <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7]</ref>, Nvidia Dynamic Scene Dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[52]</ref>, and Xiph4K. The empirical results show the state-of-the-art performance of CURE for temporal video interpolation as well as highlight its advantage over the current NF methods (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Fig. 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>In this section, we briefly review the DL-based methods for video interpolation and discuss several recent results in the area of neural fields.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Deep Learning for Video Interpolation</head><p>A number of DL methods have been developed for video frame interpolation. Early work has proposed direct <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref> and phase-base <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref> methods that pioneered the usage of deep learning for the task. Recently, the research effort has shifted to flow-based and kernel-based methods due to their improved performance. In the following, we highlight some recent methods from these two classes.</p><p>Flow-based methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">12]</ref> rely on the optical flow to synthesize new temporal frames by warping the existing frames. A common scheme consists of two modules, where the first module predicts the optical flow and the second module performs frame synthesis. A recent line of work has considered improvements due to the estimation of task-oriented flow in a self-supervised manner <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[51]</ref>, leveraging of multiple optical flow maps for characterizing bilateral motion <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">34]</ref>, and adoption of recursive multi-scale flow learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[42]</ref>. Another line of work has investigated different warping strategies, such as warping both the original frames and their feature representations for extra information <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[28]</ref> and softmax splatting for differentiable forward warping <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref>.</p><p>Kernel-based methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[32]</ref> view frame interpolation as convolution operations over local patches. The idea was first introduced in AdaConv <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[30]</ref>, which uses spatial-adaptive kernels to capture both the local motion between the input frames and the coefficients for pixel synthesis in the interpolated frame. The empirical success of AdaConv has spurred various follow-up work, including on the use of separable convolutional kernels <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[31]</ref>, jointly leveraging optical flow and adaptive convolutions <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[1]</ref>, introducing spatiotemporal deformable convolutions <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">41]</ref>, and combining channel attention modules <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7]</ref>.</p><p>The proposed CURE method represents a new approach based on continuous cross-video neural representation of videos using conditional NF.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Neural Fields</head><p>NF has emerged as a popular vision paradigm with applications in 3D image and shape synthesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">43]</ref>, tomography <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">19]</ref>, audio processing <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[44]</ref>, and view rendering <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">53]</ref>. A line of work related to this paper has considered applying NF for view synthesis of dynamic scenes, where the goal is to render a novel image of a temporally-varying scene from an arbitrary viewpoint. Examples include learning a moving human body from sparse multi-view videos <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref>, jointly learning deformable fields and scenes <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">36]</ref>, and 3D video synthesis from multi-view videos <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[16]</ref>. Although these method can be applied for video interpolation (e.g. by fixing the viewpoint in space), they are not designed for this task and usually lead to poor interpolation quality. Another related line of work has applied NF to low-level video processing, including video denoising <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">4]</ref>, video super-resolution <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8]</ref>, and video compression <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[4]</ref>. To the best of our knowledge, CURE is the first NF model designed for temporal frame interpolation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Cross-Video Neural Representation</head><p>We now present the technical details of CURE. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Fig. 3</ref> illustrates the overall structure of the proposed method. We begin by introducing the idea of representing a video segment as a function and then explain the architecture of STEM that infuses the consistency prior into CURE.              </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">C M K H A o Q M Y c Y o t i h G J F 2 S C N a O N T 2 Q u R Q h G j p 0 B L R j U M 3 i J R D C t G V Q 1 e I h E N t l + Y O 5 Y i O H T p G d O 3 Q N</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">k W e Q h Y h Y x R K F F I S J l k U I 0 t 6 j t h c C i A F F u U Y 7 o z q I 7 R N I i i e j G o h t E i U V t l 2 Y W Z Y h O L T p F d G v R L a K Z R T N E I m Y B y l g / o Q 8 O n m 5 9 1 V P Z 6 R N h K P w N L N u 3 s f s Y d m j R I a I T i 0 6 W b S y Z w W 8 G g T 5 h k s 9 R 8 7 q V K t l t E 1 m h 0 Z X 3 X X c d 1 1 2 / 9 R b K h V R j K b A h a c a n z F h 2 q 5 t M R Z O m X y + g R b F X L 3 B x r 7 r 4 V S t D F 7 d S v O z i l 4 i P u / g Y 8 V k X n y E + 6 u K j V u Y u P k E 8 7 u I x 4 v M u P k d 8 2 c W X / z H B W p 7 O 1 1 Y l 7 o 5 i W h H h E / j J d u E T 8 0 m d P q p z X b c Y Y X 1 E 5 x a 9 Q P Q C F U B 0 Z t E 7 R O / w z Q K 7 2 3 z y N P W A N P M 1 1 q h V t O / o</formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">J 7 E V b b 5 c Z Q A f 5 R X K 9 r k Y v I s 8 h D x C x i i E K L Q k T K I o V o Y V H b C 4 F F A a L c o h z R r U W 3 i K R F E t G 1 R d e I E</formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">q V K t l t E 1 m h 0 Z X 3 X X c d 1 1 2 / 9 Z b K h V R j K b A h a c 5 n z F h 2 q 5 t M R Z O m X y + g R b F X L 3 B x r 7 v 4 d S t D F 7 d S v O z i l 4 i P u / g Y 8 V k X n y E + 6 u K j V u Y u P k E 8 6 e I J 4 v M u P k d 8 2 c W X / z H B W p 7 O 1 1 Y l 7 j P F t C L C J / C T 7 c L 3 5 D d 1 + r j O d d 1 i j P U R n V v 0 A t E L V A D R m U X v E b 3 H N w v</formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">= " &gt; A A A M V n i c j Z Z R b 9 x E E M f d Q m m 5 B E j h k Z d V o k h F C u E u Q v C E a H J p k 0 h R d E 2 T t i p X o r V v b</formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">M i H Z v V S W Z D G s L W 7 m o g U J 6 S 0 j E d O a S W K 8 T K 5 Y Z p x F m k s x b 7 c H M g O W m G C 2 q l 0 A Z R G V i / J / x o e h O T D 3 1 i P z m Q q j p J n r T M A c Z 8 T E K c I T Q u t x e i m L 6 g C W S / p L 5 a t y M N j e 3 i Y T K Y Q P x a 0 8 O o 9 Y k U a U Q x 0 4 D s Y g P z W N s U N m z O c J N 4 I A l C K m y W C a s H m T X M D p S Y W q / G U x 6 T z 0 o t p B y u K w t X s x z b 0 s L h q j 5 4 1 Y H N O y O K 1 u P Y 8 n p I h A 6 b w s x m j 2 I u C V k M V p X X 2 / t f u j w L K h 9 r i 6 1 T q J 1 G y W k C A V z N / 8 J c V 0 Z 2 o b d 7 p T 1 g 4 q g 5 i D y 8 g s 0 v q u f N i 8 Y L o D j r L s x N H F v 8 T R B c Z F P F 4 K A g Z + 2 B 4 w u K 7 j V h W t 6 5 E m Y E W 1 u l A T o L J 0 K Q A Y z o Q n / p I f G P p h 8 x f o M A + 4 B B G 0 U x e B x X d M I g b b Y p + 3 o 4 B t 8 U z 5 i K f Q i J Y f J u O z M 6 p 0 U U w 1 W + i i e i 5 / n Q I q m 6 3 z 4 P h q C i / r O u P U K F G c X r X D a Z 7 k p N a i S e m 9 C K v t c m O o A P 8 o r t e 1 y E X k W e Q h Y h Y x R K F F I S J l k U K 0 s K j t h c C i A F F u U Y 7 o z q I 7 R N I i i e j G o h t E i U V t l 2 Y W Z Y h O L T p F d G v R L a K 5 R X N E I m Y B y l g / o Q 8 O n m 5 9 1 V P Z 6 R N h K P w N L d u 3 s f s Y d m j R I a I T i 0 5 W b S y Z w 2 8 G g T 5 h k i 9 Q 8 7 q V K t l t E 1 m h 0 Z X 3 X X c d 1 1 2 / 9 Z b K h V R j K b A h a c 5 n z F h 2 q 5 t M R Z O m X y + g R b F X L 3 B x r 7 v 4 d S t D F 7 d S v O z i l 4 i P u / g Y 8 V k X n y E + 6 u K j V u Y u P k E 8 6 e I J 4 v M u P k d 8 2 c W X / z H B W p 7 O 1 1 Y l 7 j P F t C L C J / C T 7 c L 3 5 D d 1 + r j O d d 1 i j P U R n V v 0 A t E L V A D R m U X v E b 3 H N w v</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>t U A z r f m v c X j y 4 e b A y 3 B + V F 0 B h s D 3 a G T 7 7 / F s m G U 1 / j i 4 e 9 L y d T 4 W U x S 7 Q X U a X e D g e p f p d T q b k X s W J t k i m W U u + S B i x 3 h b j U 1 F U F q a 5 N k k r h M 2 W W R K O v r z I a c b 0 g E B I x 1 c m k s f J F o l u Z b g Q u V 1 A 5 J T H V I V G L 2 B X R U p b B N g m y r q l M h A 5 5 E n Q C E + 4 x X 1 K v G d 4 T M T i 1 H Z b 4 Q p L h N 4 / 7 h G l v u 5 M b c 0 8 K o 2 d h c y 0 R g a R p u O h K E B f 3 4 d o k X M N m P Q K D T z s B H t e s K C M C K b K U w H N Z n + 7 O y p G 5 N y 9 M o M + D T N 4 S z G i i B a y 8 i o D V r 5 s O S d j V 1 X p X o y g Q k u s Q F l 1</head><formula xml:id="formula_6">A J D 6 q 1 V H F b Y E N K 5 e r Q y Y k u 5 X H k i y G D c X l K r Q g I b 1 m J G J a M 0 m M j 8 k V m 4 u z S H M p Z k 0 1 I D N g i Q l m q 7 o D U B Z R C W r 8 r / A w N E f k 1 k 7 k Y q r C K C k X O h W w w C k x U Y r w h N B q l E 7 C v D x w x d r a 5</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>u Y m G U s h f J j E a q A X E c v T i P K k M E 1 u D P J D X f I + m T K f J 9 z s G 6 A U M U 3 W J g m b 1 c k 5 n I l U q N J f 5 O P W Q y e q G a T I 9 x u 7 E 1 P f i / y s N j r e i M U x L f L j 8 t b x e E K K C A R d F P k I z U 4 E H P Q s T q v Z d x u 7 O w p s G + Y e l b d K J 5 G a o g g J U s H 6 z V + S T / o T 2 5 m T f l E 5 q A x i D i 7 T x S K t 7 s q H I g W T P j i K o h V H 5 / 8 S R + c Y F / F 4 K Q g Y + K E 8 Y H B d x a 2 a t J q P 1 A E r Z q s m q g N U l i 4 F A M O V 8 M R f 8 g N D P x R / j g 7 z g F s Q Q b N 0 E V h 8 w y R i s C 3 2 e T M K 2 B Z P l Y 9 4 A o 1 o + X 4 y O j m h S u f 5 R L O 5 z s v n 4 q c J o K I u n Q e n V F N 4 B V c Z x 0 a J / P i i G U 7 z Z E E q L e q U z i u u L J c b w w z w j + J + X Y t c R J 5 F H i J m E U M U W h Q i U h Y p R H O L m l 4 I L A o Q L S x a I L q x 6 A a R t E g i u r L o C l F i U d O l m U U Z o m O L j h F d W 3 S N a G b R D J G I W Y A y V k / o g 4 O n G 1 / 5 V L T 6 R B g K f w P L d m 3 s L o b t W 7 S P 6 M i i o 1 W F J T P 4 V S D Q J 0 z y O W p e t V I p u 2 0 i K z S 6 F l 3 X T c t 1 0 2 2 9 p e l C q n E q s C F p x q f M W L b U d a a i S d 2 v Z 9 C i 2 K t n u L k X b f y i k a G N G y m e t / F z x I d t f I j 4 p I 1 P E B + 0 8 U E j c x s f I R 6 3 8 R j x a R u f I j 5 v 4 / P / W G A l T + s b q h R 3 S z G t i P</head><formula xml:id="formula_7">A J / D K 7 8 K X 4 q E o f V b m u m 4 9 w f k S n F j 1 D 9 A w V Q H R i 0 R t E b / D N A t W t v 2 f q + Y D U 6 z X W q F G 0 6 2 h p 2 n U 0 q u 5 1 H X v Y G c 1 L a d + 1 4 r j t W h + 2 c V P U g z Z u 5 t l t Y 3 O c V</formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">V 1 X / 4 2 A V Q 2 W + f B 8 d U U H t Z 1 x q l R o j i 9 b o f T P M l J r U W T 0 n s Q V t v l x l A B / l B c r 2 u R i 8 i z y E P E L G K I Q o t C R M o i h W h u U d s L g U U B o t y i H N G 9 R f e I p E U S 0 a 1 F t 4 g S i 9 o u z S z K E J 1 a d I r o z q I 7 R D O L Z o h E z A K U s b 5 D H x w 8 3 f q q u 7 L T J 8 J Q + A 4 s 2 7 O x e x h 2 Y N E B o h O L T l Z t L J n B b w a B P m G S z 1 H z u p U q 2 W 0 T W a H R l f d d 9 x 3 X f b / 1 l s q F V G M p s C F p x q f M W H a r m 0 x F k 6 Z f L 6 B F s V c v c H G v u / h 1 K 0 M X t 1 I c d v E h 4 u M u P k Z 8 1 s V n i I + 6 + K i V u Y t P E I + 7 e I z 4 v I v P E V 9 2 8 e V / T L C W p / O 2 V Y n 7 T D G t i P A J / G S 7 8 F b 5 T Z 0 + q n N d t x h h f U T n F r 1 C 9 A o V Q H R m 0 T t E 7 / D J A r v b v P I 0 9 Y A 0 8 z X W q F W 0 7 +</formula><formula xml:id="formula_9">X I R e R Z 5 i J h F D F F o U Y h I W a Q Q z S 1 q e y G w K E C U W 5 Q j u r P o D p G 0 S C K 6 s e g G U W J R 2 6 W Z R R m i U 4 t O E d 1 a d I t o Z t E M k Y h Z g D L W T + i D g 6 d b X / V U d v p E G A p / A 8 v 2 b e w + h h 1 a d I j o x K K T V R t L Z v C b Q a B P m O R z 1 L x u p U p 2 2 0 R W a H T l f d d d x 3 X X b 7 2 l c i H V W</formula><formula xml:id="formula_10">v Z 6 u T H 3 p D B a l j b X E h F I m o Z 5 X 4 K 4 M x u u Y c E e g Q L T X p D H d T t a I E W W E k D V F v U X W B X g 3 r y s Q 3 0 e Z H J B O S O O F r A E G w M L 2 T K N k r C b m 6 2 + X F E g J N c h z L 8 0 o f i s V o e V i 2 I b Z q e t Q y Y k W 0 h l S R b D 2 u J m L l q Q k N 4 y E j G t m S T G y + S K Z c Z Z p L k U s 3 Z 7 I D N g i Q l m q 9 o F U B Z R O S / / Z 3 w Y m g O z s B 6 Z T 1 U Y J c 1 c p w L m O C U m T h G e E F q P 0 0 u Z V w e w X N J f K l + V a 2 s 7 O z t k L I X w o b i V R + c R K 9 K I c q g D x 8 E Y 5 K e m M X b J l P k 8 4 U Y Q g F L E N F m b J G z W J B d w e l K h K n 9 Z j D s P v a h 2 k L I 4 b O 1 e T H M v i 4 v G 6 H k j F s e 0 L E 6 r W 8 / j C S k i U D o v i x G a v Q h 4 J W R x W l f f b + 3 + K L B s q D 2 q b r V O I j W b J S R I B f M 3 f 0 k x 2 Z 3 Y x p 3 s l r W D y i D m 4 D I y i 7 S + K x 8 2 L 5 j s g q M s O 3 F 0 / i 9 x d I 5 x E Y + X g o C B H 7 Y H D K 7 r u F V F 6 3 q k C V h R r S 7 U B K g s X Q o A h j P h i b / k B 4 Z + 2 P w 5 O s w D L k E E 7 d R F Y P E d k 4 j B t t</formula><formula xml:id="formula_11">X I R e R Z 5 i J h F D F F o U Y h I W a Q Q z S 1 q e y G w K E C U W 5 Q j u r P o D p G 0 S C K 6 s e g G U W J R 2 6 W Z R R m i U 4 t O E d 1 a d I t o Z t E M k Y h Z g D L W T + i D g 6 d b X / V U d v p E G A p / A 8 v 2 b e w + h h 1 a d I j o x K K T V R t L Z v C b Q a B P m O R z 1 L x u p U p 2 2 0 R W a H T l f d d d x 3 X X b 7 2 l c i H V W A p s S J r x K T O W</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Representing Video As a Conditional Neural Field</head><p>CURE represents a video segment between two observed frames as a continuous vectorvalued function (see the visual illustration in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Fig. 2)</ref>. The input to the function is the spatial pixel location x = (x, y) ? R 2 , the relative time of the desired frame 0 ? t ? 1, and an associated local feature code ? x,t = {? (x?1,y?1,t) , . . . , ? (x+1,y+1,t) } of the 3 ? 3 region centered at x. The output of the function is the single RGB value c = (r, g, b) ? R 3 at x in the predicted frame at time t. Here, ? (u,w,? ) denotes the latent code associated with location (u, w) and time ? , and we selected a 3 ? 3 sub-region in order to impose pixel smoothness. The formulation in CURE does not need any information on the camera pose, simplifying its use. Additionally, the continuous formulation enables CURE to synthesize any frame given by the relative time t (see <ref type="figure">Fig. 7</ref>).</p><p>CURE uses a neural network M ? : (x, t, ? x,t ) ? c to approximate the coordinate-tofunction mapping, where the ? denotes the network weights. The network contains 7 fully-connected layers with 256 neurons. Two skip connections are included in the second and fourth layers to concatenate the input vectors with the intermediate results. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_22">Fig. 4(c)</ref> shows the architectural details of CURE. It is worth mentioning that as discussed in Sec. 4.3 the exclusion of the spatiotemporal coordinates from CURE leads to suboptimal empirical performance. CURE is trained over multiple videos for learning a general representation of videos. This is achieved by using the neighboring frames to generate the local feature codes. In the experiments, we trained CURE over a standard video interpolation dataset containing frame triplets.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>d C Z g A X O i I l S h C e E V q N 0 E h b l g S t W V t b X 1 8 l Y C u H D J F Y D v Y x Y n k a U J 4 V p c m O Q H + q S 9 8 m M + T z h Z t 8 A p Y h p s j J N 2 L x O z u F M p E K V / i I f t x 4 6 U c 0 g R b 7 X 2 J 2 Y + l 7 k J 7 X R 8 U Y s j m m R H 5 W 3 j s c T U k Q g 6 L L I R 2 h 2 I u C g Z 3 F a z b 7 T 2 N 1 R Y N s w 9 6 i 8 V T q J 1 B R F S J A K 1 m / + k n z a n 9 r O n P a L y k F l E H N w m S 4 W a X V X P h Q p m P b B U R S t O L p 4 T x x d Y F z E 4 2 t B w M A P 5 Q G D 6 y r u p k m r + U g d c M N s 1 U R 1 g M r S a w H A c C U 8 8 a / 5 g a E f i r 9 A h 3 n A L Y i g W b o I L L 5 k E j H Y F v u 8 G Q V s i 2 f K R z y F R r R 8 L x k d H 1 O l 8 3 y q 2 U L n 5 X P x 8 x R Q U Z f O g 1 O q K b y C q 4 w j o 0 R + d N o M p 3 m y J J U W d U r n F V e W y 4 1 h B v h H c b + u R S 4 i z y I P E b O I I Q o t C h E p i x S i h U V N L w Q W B Y i W F i 0 R X V p 0 i U h a J B G d W 3 S O K L G o 6 d L M o g z R k U V H i C 4 s u k A 0 t 2 i O S M Q s Q B m r J / T B w d O N r 3 w q W n 0 i D I W / g W U 7 N n Y H w / Y s 2 k N 0 a N H h T Y U l c / h V I N A n T P I F a l 6 1 U i m 7 b S I r N L q W X d d l y 3 X Z b b 1 r 0 4 V U 4 1 R g Q 9 K c z 5 i x b K n r T E W T u l 9 P o E W x V 0 9 w c y / b + G U j Q x s 3 U j x v 4 + e I D 9 r 4 A P F x G x 8 j 3 m / j / U b m N j 5 E P G 7 j M e I X b f w C 8 a S N J / + x w E q e 1 j d U K e 6 G Y l o R 4 R P 4 Z X b h S / F B l T 6 q c l 0 3 H + H 8 i F 5 Y 9 A z R M 1 Q A 0 b F F b x G 9 x T c L V L f + n q n n A 1 K v 1 1 i j R t G u o 6 V p 1 9 G o u t t 1 7 G J n N C + l P d e K 4 7 Z r f d D G T V H</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Flow Estimation</head><p>Warped Feature Maps      </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feature Maps Input Frames</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>&lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 9 Q k W d e C H z 7 e v V g / d l V 8 Q Y g 7 O y i 4 = " &gt; A A A M L n i c j Z b d b t x E F M f d 8 t V m + W h B X H E z S h S p S C H s R g i u k J p s 2 i R S F C 1 p 0 l Z l S z T 2 j u 1 R 7 B l n Z p z d j e V H 4 B Z e g 6 d B 4 g J x y 2 N w x v Y c 2 9 m A s J T 4 + H f O m Y / / O e O 1 n y V c m + H w j 3 v 3 3 3 n 3 v f c / e P B w b f D h R x 9 / 8 u j x p y + 1 z F X A z g O Z S P X a p 5 o l X L B z w 0 3 C X m e K 0 d R P 2 C v / c m z 9 r 6 6 Z 0 l y K M 7 P M 2 N u U R o K H P K A G 0 A s V + R e P N o b b w + o i q 8 a o M T a 8 5 p p c P B 5 8 P p 3 J I E + Z M E F C t f 5 x N M z M 2 4 I q w 4 O E l W v T X L O M B p c 0 Y o U v 5 a W h v i 5 J f W 2 S T M m Q a b s g m n x 1 l d O E m y W B k I T p X i Z N d S i F 6 W T 6 C b h 8 S d W M p N T E R C 9 T X y Y r W R a 7 J M i 6 p k p I E 3 M R 9 Q I F D 1 i o a N A O H 8 g U n M Y N S 0 K p y O j r n S 3 C T L D d y 0 1 5 o K R V s 3 S 5 j s h I 0 S x e 9 i V I y 4 d w b R J u Y L M B g c F n v Y C A G 1 Z W E Z G S e U b g u a p O f 2 f V y D x Y l D Y w 5 F G u b g l m N T E S V l 5 H w O r X b X 8 I d n W 1 3 t c o i a T i J o Z F l x C J j / r u q P K 2 w J Z V y z U x k 4 r d y m M i T 2 F D a b U K I 0 l M r x l J m D F M E e t j 6 o 7 N p X l i u J L z t h q Q G T F h g 9 l d 3 Q E o T 6 g C N f 5 X e B z b A 3 J r J 2 o 5 0 3 E i q o X O J C x w R m y U J l w Q W o / S S 1 h U x 6 1 c W 9 v c 3 C Q T J W U I k z g N z D J h R Z Z Q L k r b 5 N Y g 3 z c l 3 y I z F n L B 7 b 4 B K p l S s T Y V b N 4 k F 3 A m M q k r f 1 l M O g + 9 q H a Q s t h v 7 V 5 M c y + L s 8 b o e R O W p r Q s j q t b z x N I J R M Q d F k W Y z R 7 E X D Q 8 z S r Z 9 9 t 7 f 4 o s G 2 Y e 1 z d a p 1 k Z o s i F U g F 6 7 d / o p h u T V 1 n T r f K 2 k F V l H J w 2 S 6 W W X 3 X I R Q p m m 6 B o y w 7 c X T x L 3 F 0 g X E J T 1 e C g I E f y g M G N 3 X c X Z P W 8 5 E m 4 I 7 Z 6 o m a A J 1 n K w H A c C V c h C t + Y O i H 4 i / Q Y R 9 w C z J q l y 4 j h 2 + Y Q g y 2 w y F v R w H b 4 Z k O E U + h E R 3 f F + O T E 6 p N U U w N W 5 i i e i 5 / m g I q m 9 I F c E o N h V d w n X F s l S i O L 9 r h D B d L U m v R p P R e c V W 5 / B R m g H 8 U 9 + s 7 5 C M K H A o Q M Y c Y o t i h G J F 2 S C N a O N T 2 Q u R Q h G j p 0 B L R j U M 3 i J R D C t G V Q 1 e I h E N t l + Y O 5 Y i O H T p G d O 3 Q N a K 5 Q 3 N E M m U R y l g / o Q 8 O n m l 9 1 V P Z 6 R N p K f w N H d t 1 s b s Y t u / Q P q I j h 4 7 u K i y Z w 6 8 C g T 5 h i i 9 Q 8 7 q V K t l d E z m h 0 b X s u 2 4 6 r p t + 6 6 1 M F 1 O D U 4 E N S X M + Y 9 Z y p W 4 y N R V N v 5 5 B i 2 K v n u H m X n T x i 1 a G L m 6 l e N 7 F z x E f d v E h 4 p M u P k F 8 0 M U H r c x d f I R 4 0 s U T x K d d f I r 4 v I v P / 2 O B t T y d b 6 h K 3 C e a G U 1 k S O C X 2 Y f v x C / r 9 H G d 6 / v F G O d H d O r Q M 0 T P U A F E J w 6 9 Q f Q G 3 y x Q 3 e Z 7 p p k P S L N e a 4 1 b R f u O j q Z 9 R 6 v q X t + x h 5 3 R v p T 2 f S e O 3 6 3 1 Y R e 3 R T 3 o 4 n a e 3 S 6 2 x w k + p E e 3 P 5 t X j</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Q s h f C h u J V H 5 x E r 0 o h y q A P H w R h w F u v G C V T 5 v O E G 0 E A S h H T Z G W S s F m T X M D p S Y W q / G U x 7 j z 0 o t p B y u K w t X s x z b 0 s L h q j 5 4 1 Y H N O y O K 1 u P Y 8 n p I h A 6 b w s R m j I u C V k M V p X X / t f u j w L K h 9 q i 6 1 T q J 1 G y W k C A V z N / 8 J c V k d I b d 7 J b 1 g 4 q g 5 i D y 8 g s 0 v q u f N i 8 Y L I L j r L s x N H 5 v 8 T R O c Z F P F 4 I A g Z + B 4 w u K 7 j l h W t 6 5 E m Y E m 1 u l A T o L J 0 I Q A Y z o Q n / o I f G P p h 8 + f o M A + 4 B B G 0 U x e B x X d M I g b b Y p + 3 o 4 B t 8 V T 5 i C f Q i J Y f J q O z M 6 p 0 U U w 0 m + u i e i 5 / m w A q m 6 3 z 4 P h q C i / r O u P U K F G c X r X D a Z 7 k p N a i S e m 9 C K v t c m O o A P 8 o r t e 1 y E X k W e Q h Y h Y x R K F F I S J l k U I 0 t 6 j t h c C i A F F u U Y 7 o z q I 7 R N I i i e j G o h t E i U V t l Y W Z Y h O L T p F d G v R L a K Z R T N E I m Y B y l g / o Q 8 O n m 5 9 1 V P Z 6 R N h K P w N L N u 3 s f s Y d m j R I a I T i 0 6 W b S y Z w W 8 G g T 5 h k s 9 R 8 7 q V K t l t E 1 m h 0 Z X 3 X X c d 1 1 / 9 R b K h V R j K b A h a c a n z F h q 5 t M R Z O m X y + g R b F X L 3 B x r 7 r 4 V S t D F 7 d S v O z i l 4 i P u / g Y 8 V k X n y E + 6 u K j V u Y u P k E 8 7 u I x 4 v M u P k d 8 c W X / z H B W p 7 O 1 1 Y l 7 o 5 i W h H h E / j J d u E T 8 0 m d P q p z X b c Y Y X 1 E 5 x a 9 Q P Q C F U B 0 Z t E 7 R O / w z Q K 7 3 z y N P W A N P M 1 1 q h V t O / o a N p 3 t K o e 9 B 0 H B n t S + n Q t e K</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I t G d T D c C l y u o n J G Y 6 p C o P H Z F t J R l s E 2 C r B s q E 6 F D n g S 9 w I R 7 z J f U a 4 f 3 R A x O b Y c l v p B k 9 M P T H c K 0 t 9 v L j b k n h d G y t L m W i E D S N M z 7 E s S d 2 X A N C / Y I F J j 1 g j y u 2 9 E C K b K U A K q 2 q L / A q g D 3 F m U d 6 v M g k 3 e U M + J o A U u w M b C Q T d M o C b u + 3 u z L F Q V C c h 3 C / E s T i s 9 q d V h 5 V 2 z D 7 L R 1 y I R k d 1 J Z k s W w t r i Z i x Y k p D e M R E x r J o n x M r l i m X E W a S 7 F v N 0 e y A x Y Y o L Z q n Y B l E V U L s r / G R + G 5 s D c W Y / M Z y q M k m a u M w F z n B E T p w h P C K 3 H 6 a U s q g N Y L u k v l a / K w W B 7 e 5 t M p B A + F L f y 6 D x i R R p R D n X g O B i D / N w 0 x g 6 Z M Z 8 n 3 A g C U I q Y J o N p w u Z N c g G n J x W q 8 p f F p P P Q i 2 o H K Y u D 1 u 7 F N P e y O G + M n j d i c U z L 4 q S 6 9 T y e k C I C p f O y G K P Z i 4 B X Q h a n d f W 9 1 u 6 P A s u G 2 u P q V u s k U r N Z Q o J U M H / z l x T T n a l t 3 O l O W T u o D G I O L i O z S O u 7 8 m H z g u k O O M q y E 0 c X / x J H F x g X 8 X g p C B j 4 Y X v A 4 L q O W 1 W 0 r k e a g B X V 6 k J N g M r S p Q B g O B O e + E t + Y O i H z V + g w z z g E k T Q T l 0 E F t 8 y i R h s i 3 3 e j g K 2 x T P l I 5 5 C I 1 p + k I x P T 6 n S R T H V b K G L 6 r n 8 O A V U N l v n w f H V F F 7 W d c a J U a I 4 u W y H 0 z z J S a 1 F k 9 J 7 E V b b 5 c Z Q A f 5 R X K 9 r k Y v I s 8 h D x C x i i E K L Q k T K I o V o Y V H b C 4 F F A a L c o h z R r U W 3 i K R F E t G 1 R d e I E o v a L s 0 s y h C d W H S C 6 M a i G 0 R z i + a I R M w C l L F +</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I t &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 5 V y 4 D O W Q U m X 3 s Z O L v B o w N F U t t T k = " &gt; A A A M Z 3 i c j Z Z t b 9 0 0 F M e z 8 T T a w j q Q E B J v T K t K Q y r l 3 m m C V 4 i 1 t 1 t b q V S X r t 2 m k V E 5 u U 5 i N Y l T 2 7 k P j f J N e A v f i Y / A t + A 4 i U + S 3 g s i</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>q k d T 7 S O K z I V i d q H F S e L T k A w 5 n w N F i y A 0 M 7 b P 4 c D a a D S x B h O 3 U R W n z L J G J o W x z w d h R o W z x R A W I X C t H y w 3 R 0 d k a V L g p X s 7 k u q n 7 5 m w u o b L b O h + O r K X y s 6 4 h T o 0 R x e t U O p 3 m 6 I L U W T U j v Q 1 h t l 5 d A B v h H c b 2 e R R 4 i 3 y I f E b O I I Y o s i h A p i x S i u U V t L Y Q W h Y g W F i 0 Q 3 V p 0 i 0 h a J B H d W H S D K L W o r d L c o h z R q U W n i K Y W T R H N L J o h E g k L U c</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Spatio-Temporal Encoding</head><p>Directly applying NF to video interpolation leads to poor results due to the lack of spatial and temporal consistency. <ref type="figure">Fig. 8</ref> illustrates the results obtained by the basic NeRF, which simply maps (x, y, t) to the corresponding RGB value. The motivation for spatio-temporal encoding is to provide additional prior information in both space and time to improve the neural representation performance.</p><p>We design STEM to generate the local feature codes ? t = {? <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">(1,1,t)</ref> , ..., ? (H,W,t) } from the two neighboring frames {I 0 , I 1 } of the desired frame I t . Here, H and W denote pixel width and height of the video. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_12">Fig. 3(b)</ref> illustrates the detailed architecture of STEM, which we denote as S ? : {I 0 , I 1 } ? ? t for convenience.</p><p>Feature Extraction. STEM first extracts two individual H ? W ? 64 feature maps {F 0 , F 1 } from the input frames by using a customized residual network (ResNet) R : I ? F ,</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">F 0 = R(I 0 ), F 1 = R(I 1 ).<label>(1)</label></formula><p>The architecture of R is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_22">Fig. 4(a)</ref>. Note that these feature maps are later used to form the latent feature map for frame I t via a two-step procedure: feature warping and fusion. Feature Warping. Feature warping aims to interpolate the latent feature maps associated with time t by warping {F 0 , F 1 }. This step ensures the temporal consistency between existing and predicted frames in the latent space. To improve the interpolation accuracy, STEM adopts the bilateral motion approximation technique <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[33]</ref> to generate four bilateral motion maps (fw: forward &amp; bw: backward) from the bidirectional optical flows ? 0?1 and ? 1?0 ,</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">? fw t?0 = (?t) ? ? 0?1 ,<label>(2a)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">? fw t?1 = (1 ? t) ? ? 0?1 , (2b) ? bw t?0 = t ? ? 1?0 ,<label>(2c)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_15">? bw t?1 = ?(1 ? t) ? ? 1?0 .<label>(2d)</label></formula><p>Here, ? 0?1 and ? 1?0 are estimated by an off-the-shelf differentiable optical flow estimator. In our case, RAFT <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[48]</ref> is used for flow estimation. STEM used the spatial transform network <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[11]</ref> to warp the feature maps. In particular, we warp a target feature map F tar into a reference feature F ref by using the motion map from the reference to target</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">F ref (x) = F tar (x + ? ref?tar (x))<label>(3)</label></formula><p>By applying <ref type="formula" target="#formula_16">(3)</ref> and <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> to {F 0 , F 1 }, we can obtain four warped feature maps via cross combination</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">F bw 0?t (x) = F 0 (x + ? bw t?0 (x)),<label>(4a)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_18">F bw 1?t (x) = F 1 (x + ? bw t?1 (x)),<label>(4b)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_19">F fw 0?t (x) = F 0 (x + ? fw t?0 (x)),<label>(4c)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_20">F fw 1?t (x) = F 1 (x + ? fw t?1 (x)),<label>(4d)</label></formula><p>where a single warped feature map has the spatial dimension of H ? W ? 64. In feature warping, STEM adopted bilinear interpolation to handle off-the-grid pixels. Feature Fusion. To output the final local feature codes for I t , a feature fusion step is then employed to fuse the warped feature maps into a single H ? W ? 64 feature map,</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">? t = U(F concat )<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">F concat := F fw 0?t ? F fw 1?t ? F bw 0?t ? F bw 1?t .</formula><p>Here, ? denotes feature concatenation along the channel dimension, and U represents the fusion network. In STEM, we implemented a customized U-Net as U, which is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_22">Fig 4(b)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Training of CURE</head><p>We jointly optimize the parameters of STEM and the coordinate-based neural network by minimizing the mean squared error (MSE) for each pixel location</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">L(?, ?) = M ? (x, t, ? x,t ) ? I t (x) 2 2</formula><p>where ? t = S ? (I 0 , I 1 ).</p><p>The vector ? includes the weights of the feature extraction network R, feature fusion network U, and the optical flow estimator RAFT. We initialize RAFT with the default pre-trained weights, and set the RAFT iteration number to 50. We trained CURE on the training dataset Vimeo90K <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[51]</ref>. We performed data augmentation by vertically and horizontally flipping the video frames. CURE is trained by taking the start and end frames as input and predicting the middle frame at t = 0.5. Once trained, CURE can continuously interpolate frames at any t ? (0, 1) (see <ref type="figure">Fig. 7</ref>). We used Adam <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[13]</ref> optimizer to optimize all network parameters for 70 epochs. We implemented a diminishing learning rate which decreases by 0.95 at every epoch. The training was performed on a machine equipped with an AMD Ryzen Threadripper 3960X 24-Core Processor and 2 NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3090 GPUs. It took roughly 3 weeks to train the model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>UCF101:</head><p>The UCF101 <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[45]</ref> dataset contains realistic action videos collected from YouTube. We used a subset collected by <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref> for evaluation. The subset contains 379 triplets with 256 ? 256 resolution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SNU-FILM:</head><p>The dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7]</ref> contains 1, 240 triplets extracted from different videos with up to 1280 ? 720 resolution. The triplets are categorized to easy, medium, hard, and extreme, based on the motion strength between frames.</p><p>Xiph4K: The dataset contains eight randomly-selected 4K videos downloaded from the Xiph website 1 . For each video, we extracted the first fifty odd-numbered frames to form the testing triplets, all resized to 2048 ? 1080 pixels.</p><p>Nvidia Dynamic Scene (ND Scene): ND Scene <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[52]</ref> is a video dataset that is commonly used for novel view synthesis. The dataset contains videos of eight scenes, recorded by a static camera rig with twelve GoPro cameras. We separate each video into triplets with a temporal sliding window of three frames.</p><p>X4K: The X4K dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[42]</ref> contains eight 4K videos with 33 frames. We used this dataset for testing continuous multi-frame interpolation, with all videos resized to 2048 ? 1080 pixels. In the test, we used the first and last frames as input frames to predict seven middle frames, that is, {I 4 , I 8 , I 12 , I 15 , I 20 , I 24 , I 28 }. Quantitative Metrics: We use peak-signal-to-noise ratio (PSNR) and structural similarity index (SSIM) to quantify the performance of all methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Performance Evaluation</head><p>Comparison with video interpolation methods. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> summarizes the results of comparing CURE against several SOTA algorithms. The results are obtained by running the published code with the pre-trained weights. The average PSNR and SSIM values obtained by each algorithm on the considered datasets are presented. Note how CURE outperforms all SOTA methods in terms of the PSNR/SSIM values averaged over all datasets. For example, CURE outperforms ABME, which is the latest SOTA method, on most datasets and tied its performance (i.e. -0.1 dB in PSNR or -0.001 in SSIM) on the rest.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_23">Fig. 5</ref> visually compares CURE to several representative SOTA methods on an example from Vimeo90K. We highlight the visual differences by zooming in the yellow box and plotting the corresponding residual error map. In this comparison, SloMO, ToFlow, and BMBC reconstruct video frames with significant blurry and ghosting artifacts, failing to capture the shape of the airplane front (see yellow arrows). While RRIN and CAIN successfully recover the airplane front, they completely blur the mountain in the background (see green arrows). Note how CURE clearly reconstructs both the moving airplane as well as the background mountain with fine details. The qualitative visual improvements are also corroborated by the higher quantitative values and lower residual errors. <ref type="figure">Fig. 6</ref> provides a visual results on two videos from SNU-FILM (hard). These two examples were selected due to the fast motion of the recorded objects, which makes the frame interpolation challenging. ToFlow completely fails to reconstruct the bird's wingtip in the second video. Other algorithms, such as BMBC, RRIN, CAIN, and AMBE, produce blurry frames that smooth out the details on the feathers. CURE successfully handles the motion by reconstructing a sharp frame. Note the visual similarity between the frame synthesized by CURE and the groundtruth. Similar results can be observed in the comparison on the first video of a man skateboarding, where CURE significantly outperforms other algorithms. <ref type="figure">Fig. 7</ref> highlights CURE's ability to perform continuous interpolation on a challenging video from X4K. We include the result by XVFI as the baseline. Each figure plots both image and the corresponding residual error map with respect to the groundtruth. The visual differences on the textural details are highlighted in the green boxes. Note that both CURE and XVFI were only trained to predict the frame at t = 0.5 on the Vimeo90K dataset. CURE produces high-quality and accurate frames for every temporal location, significantly outperforming XVFI in terms of both visual quality and precision. Note how CURE recovers the vehicle license plate that is completely distorted by XVFI. Corresponding quantitative results are summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref>, corroborating the excellent performance of CURE.</p><p>Comparison with NF methods. We compared CURE with two different NF algorithms: (1) vanilla NF (V-NF) that directly learns a coordinate-based neural network to map (x, t) to the corresponding color pixel, and (2) NSFF <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref> that learns the dynamic scene in the video and applies view synthesis to generate new frames. Both algorithms need to re-optimize their weights for every test video/scene, while CURE learns a general video prior. We implemented V-NF by adopting the neural network architecture of NeRF and setting the positional encoding L to 10 and 2 for (x, y) and t, respectively. We trained V-NF by using the even-number frames. For NSFF, we downloaded the pre-trained models for testing. Note that these comparisons are provided for completeness only; the performance of these NF algorithms on video interpolation should not be interpreted as an indication of their performance on their original tasks. We evaluated the comparison on ND Scene. For each scene, we randomly selected one camera video from the videos captured by twelve cameras. We resized each video to accommodate the setup used by the pre-trained models of NSFF. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> summarizes the details and quantitative results on each test video. As illustrated, CURE significantly outperforms V-NF and NSFF in every test scenario, and the PSNR improvement is usually over 5 dB. <ref type="figure">Fig. 8</ref> presents a visual comparison of the truck video to better highlight the difference.Without any consistency constraint, V-NF faithfully recovers the general content in the frame, but loses the feature details and suffers strong gridding artifacts. For example,  <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>: Visual comparison between CURE and current SOTA methods on two examples from SNU-FILM (hard). We highlight the differences by zooming in the regions with the presence of strong motion (the man's waist and the bird's wingtip). Note how CURE outperforms the SOTA methods by removing distortions and enhancing sharpness.</p><p>the residual map highlights the missing edges in the interpolated frame in V-NF. On the other hand, NSFF generates a visually pleasing frame with faithful details. However, the problem of NSFF is that it predicts the wrong position of the moving truck, which significantly reduces the PSNR values. CURE avoids all these problems and interpolates a high-quality frame with both fine details and correct position of the truck. These results highlight the contribution of CURE to the research on NF-based video frame interpolation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Ablation Studies</head><p>We highlighted the key components of the proposed model by conducting several ablation experiments. We focus on showing the effectiveness of the coordinate-based neural representation by considering two baseline variants:  The first row shows the images, and the second row shows the corresponding residual error map. We highlighted the visual difference in the yellow box. CURE achieves substantially higher PSNR (about 17 dB) over NSFF.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CURE-w/o-Rep:</head><p>This method directly trains the STEM network as a frame interpolator by adding an additional head to predict the RGB images. We design CURE-w/o-Rep to show the importance of the NF module.  <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref>: Visual illustration of the importance of the various components of CURE. The green and yellow boxes highlight the improvements in terms of accuracy and sharpness due to the full CURE compared to its ablated variants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CURE-w/o-Crd:</head><p>This method simplifies CURE by removing the input of the spatiotemporal coordinate (x, t). We design CURE-w/o-Crd to show the importance of the coordinate indexing for synthesizing the desired RGB values. <ref type="figure">Fig. 9</ref> visually compares CURE with its two baseline variants on an example from SNU (hard). Without neural representation, CURE-w/o-Rep predicts the wrong location of the bird's wingtip shown in the green box, losing enough representation power to properly represent the video. On the other hand, CURE-w/o-Crd produces a blurry image that loses the texture details by missing the exact spatiotemporal coordinate. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref> summarizes the numerical values on all the considered datasets. The results clearly show that CURE achieves the best results by jointly leveraging STEM and coordinate-based representation. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>This work proposes a novel temporal video frame interpolation algorithm, CURE, which is based on the recent class of techniques known as neural fields (NF). The key idea of CURE is to represent video segment between two observed frames as a continuous vector-valued function of the spatiotemporal coordinates, which is parameterized by a fully-connected coordinate-based neural network. Unlike the traditional NF variants, CURE enforces spacetime consistency in the synthesized frames by conditioning its NF on the information from the neighboring frames. This conditioning enables CURE to learn a prior across different videos. Experimental evaluations clearly show that the CURE outperforms the state-of-theart methods on five benchmark datasets. The comparisons with the traditional NF methods and with the ablated variants of CURE highlight the synergistic effect of various components of the full CURE.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>&lt;</head><label></label><figDesc>l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 9 Q k W d e C H z 7 e v V g / d l V 8 Q Y g 7 O y i 4 = " &gt; A A A M L n i c j Z b d b t x E F M f d 8 t V m + W h B X H E z S h S p S C H s R g i u k J p s 2 i R S F C 1 p 0 l Z l S z T 2 j u 1 R 7 B l n Z p z d j e V H 4 B Z e g 6 d B 4 g J x y 2 N w x v Y c 2 9 m A s J T 4 + H f O m Y / / O e O 1 n y V c m + H w j 3 v 3 3 3 n 3 v f c / e P B w b f D h R x 9 / 8 u j x p y + 1 z F X A z g O Z S P X a p 5 o l X L B z w 0 3 C X m e K 0 d R P 2 C v / c m z 9 r 6 6 Z 0 l y K M 7 P M 2 N u U R o K H P K A G 0 A s V + R e P N o b b w + o i q 8 a o M T a 8 5 p p c P B 5 8 P p 3 J I E + Z M E F C t f 5 x N M z M 2 4 I q w 4 O E l W v T X L O M B p c 0 Y o U v 5 a W h v i 5 J f W 2 S T M m Q a b s g m n x 1 l d O E m y W B k I T p X i Z N d S i F 6 W T 6 C b h 8 S d W M p N T E R C 9 T X y Y r W R a 7 J M i 6 p k p I E 3 M R 9 Q I F D 1 i o a N A O H 8 g U n M Y N S 0 K p y O j r n S 3 C T L D d y 0 1 5 o K R V s 3 S 5 j s h I 0 S x e 9 i V I y 4 d w b R J u Y L M B g c F n v Y C A G 1 Z W E Z G S e U b g u a p O f 2 f V y D x Y l D Y w 5 F G u b g l m N T E S V l 5 H w O r X b X 8 I d n W 1 3 t c o i a T i J o Z F l x C J j / r u q P K 2 w J Z V y z U x k 4 r d y m M i T 2 F D a b U K I 0 l M r x l J m D F M E e t j 6 o 7 N p X l i u J L z t h q Q G T F h g 9 l d 3 Q E o T 6 g C N f 5 X e B z b A 3 J r J 2 o 5 0 3 E i q o X O J C x w R m y U J l w Q W o / S S 1 h U x 6 1 c W 9 v c 3 C Q T J W U I k z g N z D J h R Z Z Q L k r b 5 N Y g 3 z c l 3 y I z F n L B 7 b 4 B K p l S s T Y V b N 4 k F 3 A m M q k r f 1 l M O g + 9 q H a Q s t h v 7 V 5 M c y + L s 8 b o e R O W p r Q s j q t b z x N I J R M Q d F k W Y z R 7 E X D Q 8 z S r Z 9 9 t 7 f 4 o s G 2 Y e 1 z d a p 1 k Z o s i F U g F 6 7 d / o p h u T V 1 n T r f K 2 k F V l H J w 2 S 6 W W X 3 X I R Q p m m 6 B o y w 7 c X T x L 3 F 0 g X E J T 1 e C g I E f y g M G N 3 X c X Z P W 8 5 E m 4 I 7 Z 6 o m a A J 1 n K w H A c C V c h C t + Y O i H 4 i / Q Y R 9 w C z J q l y 4 j h 2 + Y Q g y 2 w y F v R w H b 4 Z k O E U + h E R 3 f F + O T E 6 p N U U w N W 5 i i e i 5 / m g I q m 9 I F c E o N h V d w n X F s l S i O L 9 r h D B d L U m v R p P R e c V W 5 / B R m g H 8 U 9 + s 7 5</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a K 5 Q 3 N E M m U R y l g / o Q 8 O n m l 9 1 V P Z 6 R N p K f w N H d t 1 s b s Y t u / Q P q I j h 4 7 u K i y Z w 6 8 C g T 5 h i i 9 Q 8 7 q V K t l d E z m h 0 b X s u 2 4 6 r p t + 6 6 1 M F 1 O D U 4 E N S X M + Y 9 Z y p W 4 y N R V N v 5 5 B i 2 K v n u H m X n T x i 1 a G L m 6 l e N 7 F z x E f d v E h 4 p M u P k F 8 0 M U H r c x d f I R 4 0 s U T x K d d f I r 4 v I v P / 2 O B t T y d b 6 h K 3 C e a G U 1 k S O C X 2 Y f v x C / r 9 H G d 6 / v F G O d H d O r Q M 0 T P U A F E J w 6 9 Q f Q G 3 y x Q 3 e Z 7 p p k P S L N e a 4 1 b R f u O j q Z 9 R 6 v q X t + x h 5 3 R v p T 2 f S e O 3 6 3 1 Y R e 3 R T 3 o 4 n a e 3 S 6 2 x w k + p E e 3 P 5 t X j Z c 7 2 6 N v t 7 / 5 Y W f j 6 V 7 z S f 3 A + 8 J b 9 5 5 4 I + 8 7 7 6 l 3 6 E 2 8 c y / w I u 9 n 7 x f v 1 8 F v g 9 8 H f w 7 + q k P v 3 2 t y P v N 6 1 + D v f w A 2 i 3 m 3 &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; rgb &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " e W C D Q y c V M M 6 m F K x J 1 m w R / V D p b 7 Q = " &gt; A A A M a X i c j Z b f T 9 x G E M e d 9 F c K t I X 0 p W p f V i A k I l F 6 F 0 X t U 9 X A k Q A S Q l c C S Z R c i t a + t b 3 C 9 p r d N X f G 8 r / S 1 / Z f 6 t / Q f 6 K z t n d s c 9 e q l s D j z 8 z s 7 H 5 3 1 m c 3 j b j S g 8 F f D x 5 + 9 P E n n 3 7 2 6 P O V 1 b U v v v x q f e P x a y U y 6 b F L T 0 R C v n W p Y h F P 2 K X m O m J v U 8 l o 7 E b s j X s 9 M v 4 3 t 0 w q L p I L n a f s Q 0 y D h P v c o x r Q 1 f r j S U x 1 6 P r F v C Q / k 5 3 5 b v 7 k a n 1 r s D e o L r J o D B t j y 2 m u 8 d X G 6 i + T q f C y m C X a i 6 h S 7 4 e D V H 8 o q N T c i 1 i 5 M s k U S 6 l 3 T Q N W u E J c a + q q k t T X N k m l 8 J k y M 6 T R 9 z c Z j b j O C Y R E T P U y a a x 8 k e h O p h u B y x V U T o l Z B V F 5 7 I p o I c t g m w R Z t 1 Q m Q o c 8 C X q B C f e Y L 6 n X D u + J G J z a D k t 8 I c n w h 6 e 7 h G l v r 5 c b c 0 8 K I 2 9 p c y 0 R g a R p m P c l i D u z 4 R o W 7 B E o M O 0 F e V y 3 o w V S Z C k B V O 1 a f 4 F V A e 7 N y z r U 5 0 E m 7 y l n x N E C l m B j Y C G b p n c S d n O z 2 Z c r C o T k O o T 5 l y Y U n 9 X y s P K + 2 I b Z a e u Q C c n u p b I k i 2 F t c T M X L U h I b x m J m N Z M E u N l c s k y 4 y z S X I p Z u z 2 Q G b D E B L N l 7 Q I o i 6 i c l / 8 z P g z N G b q 3 H p l P V R g l z V y n A u Y 4 J S Z O E Z 4 Q W o / T S 5 l X Z 7 J c 0 F 8 q X 5 U r K 9 v b 2 2 Q s h f C h u J V H 5 x E r 0 o h y q A P H w R h w F u v G 2 C V T 5 v O E G 0 E A S h H T Z G W S s F m T X M D p S Y W q / G U x 7 j z 0 o t p B y u K w t X s x z b 0 s L h q j 5 4 1 Y H N O y O K 1 u P Y 8 n p I h A 6 b w s R m j 2 I u C V k M V p X X 2 / t f u j w L K h 9 q i 6 1 T q J 1 G y W k C A V z N / 8 J c V k d 2 I b d 7 J b 1 g 4 q g 5 i D y 8 g s 0 v q u f N i 8 Y L I L j r L s x N H 5 v 8 T R O c Z F P F 4 I A g Z + 2 B 4 w u K 7 j l h W t 6 5 E m Y E m 1 u l A T o L J 0 I Q A Y z o Q n / o I f G P p h 8 + f o M A + 4 B B G 0 U x e B x X d M I g b b Y p + 3 o 4 B t 8 V T 5 i C f Q i J Y f J q O z M 6 p 0 U U w 0 m + u i e i 5 / m w A q m 6 3 z 4 P h q C i / r O u P U K F G c X r X D a Z 7 k p N a i S e m 9 C K v t c m O o A P 8 o r t e 1 y E X</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a N p 3 t K o e 9 B 0 H 2 B n t S + n Q t e K 4 3 b 0 + 7 u J 2 U 4 + 6 u K 2 z 3 8 X m O M E n 9 / D + B / a i 8 f r p 3 v D H v W e / P t t 6 f t B 8 f D 9 y v n M 2 n R 1 n 6 P z k P H e O n b F z 6 X j O 3 P n d + c P 5 c / X v t Y 2 1 b 9 a + r U M f P m h y v n Z 6 1 9 r W P y I M i Z k = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; x = (x, y) &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " p D u z R j e d E F 6 0 p N s 4 l n A N 6 Z 9 P O 2 Y = " &gt; A A A M V n i c j Z Z R b 9 x E E M f d Q m m 5 B E j h k Z d V o k h F C u G u q u A J 0 e T S J p G i 6 J o m b V W u j d a + t b 2 K 7 X V 2 1 7 l z L H 8 C X u G 7 w Z d B z N r e s Z 0 7 E J Y S j 3 8 z s 7 P 7 3 1 m f 3 T T i S g + H f 9 2 7 / 8 m n D z 5 7 + O j z w d r 6 F 1 9 + t f H 4 6 z d K Z N J j F 5 6 I h H z n U s U i n r A L z X X E 3 q W S 0 d i N 2 F v 3 a m z 8 b 2 + Y V F w k 5 z p P 2 Y e Y B g n 3 u U c 1 o F f 6 c m N r u D u s L r J s j B p j y 2 m u y e X j t V + m M + F l M U u 0 F 1 G l f h 0 N U / 2 h o F J z L 2 L l Y J o p l l L v i g a s c I W 4 0 t R V J a m v b Z J K 4 T N l p k O j 7 6 8 z G n G d E w i J m O p l 0 l j 5 I t G d T D c C l y u o n J G Y 6 p C o P H Z F t J R l s E 2 C r B s q E 6 F D n g S 9 w I R 7 z J f U a 4 f 3 R A x O b Y c l v p B k 9 M P T H c K 0 t 9 v L j b k n h d G y t L m W i E D S N M z 7 E s S d 2 X A N C / Y I F J j 1 g j y u 2 9 E C K b K U A K q 2 q L / A q g D 3 F m U d 6 v M g k 3 e U M + J o A U u w M b C Q T d M o C b u + 3 u z L F Q V C c h 3 C / E s T i s 9 q d V h 5 V 2 z D 7 L R 1 y I R k d 1 J Z k s W w t r i Z i x Y k p D e M R E x r J o n x M r l i m X E W a S 7 F v N 0 e y A x Y Y o L Z q n Y B l E V U L s r / G R + G 5 s D c W Y / M Z y q M k m a u M w F z n B E T p w h P C K 3 H 6 a U s q g N Y L u k v l a / K w W B 7 e 5 t M p B A + F L f y 6 D x i R R p R D n X g O B i D / N w 0 x g 6 Z M Z 8 n 3 A g C U I q Y J o N p w u Z N c g G n J x W q 8 p f F p P P Q i 2 o H K Y u D 1 u 7 F N P e y O G + M n j d i c U z L 4 q S 6 9 T y e k C I C p f O y G K P Z i 4 B X Q h a n d f W 9 1 u 6 P A s u G 2 u P q V u s k U r N Z Q o J U M H / z l x T T n a l t 3 O l O W T u o D G I O L i O z S O u 7 8 m H z g u k O O M q y E 0 c X / x J H F x g X 8 X g p C B j 4 Y X v A 4 L q O W 1 W 0 r k e a g B X V 6 k J N g M r S p Q B g O B O e + E t + Y O i H z V + g w z z g E k T Q T l 0 E F t 8 y i R h s i 3 3 e j g K 2 x T P l I 5 5 C I 1 p + k I x P T 6 n S R T H V b K G L 6 r n 8 O A V U N l v n w f H V F F 7 W d c a J U a I 4 u W y H 0 z z J S a 1 F k 9</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>o v a L s 0 s y h C d W H S C 6 M a i G 0 R z i + a I R M w C l L F + Q h 8 c P N 3 6 q q e y 0 y f C U P g b W r Z n Y / c w 7 M C i A 0 T H F h 2 v 2 l g y h 9 8 M A n 3 C J F + g 5 n U r V b L b J r J C o y v v u 2 4 7 r t t + 6 y 2 V C 6 n G U m B D 0 p z P m L H s V j e Z i i Z N v 5 5 D i 2 K v n u P i X n f x 6 1 a G L m 6 l e N n F L x E f d f E R 4 t M u P k V 8 2 M W H r c x d f I x 4 0 s U T x G d d f I b 4 o o s v / m O C t T y d r 6 1 K 3 C e K a U W E T + A n 2 4 X v y e / q 9 H G d 6 7 r F G O s j O r P o B a I X q A C i U 4 v e I 3 q P b x b Y 3 e a T p 6 k H p J m v s c a t o n 1 H R 9 O + o 1 V 1 v + / Y x 8 5 o X 0 o H r h X H 7 e 7 1 U R e 3 m 3 r Y x W 2 d v S 4 2 x w k + u U d 3 P 7 C X j T d P d 0 c / 7 j 5 7 9 W z r + X 7 z 8 f 3 I + d b Z d J 4 4 I + c n 5 7 l z 5 E y c C 8 d z m P O b 8 7 v z x 9 q f a 3 + v P 1 h / W I f e v 9 f k f O P 0 r v W N f w D 7 p o Q I &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; t &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 1 6 O G a 7 r 2 g a B h C B Q y K b t E z Y J c 1 J g = " &gt; A A A M W H i c j Z b f b 9 s 2 E M f V 7 k f b J N v a 7 n E v R I I A H Z B l d l F s T 8 O a O G 0 S I A i 8 N G m L z l 1 A y Z R E R B I V k o r t C P o T 9 r r 9 b d t f s 6 M k n q j Y G y Y g 0 e l z d z z y y 6 M s P 0 + 4 0 o P B X / f u f / L p Z 5 8 / e P h o b X 3 j i y + / e v z k 6 V s l C h m w i 0 A k Q r 7 3 q W I J z 9 i F 5 j p h 7 3 P J a O o n 7 J 1 / N T L + d z d M K i 6 y c 7 3 I 2 c e U R h k P e U A 1 o D f H l / r y 8 d Z g d 1 B f Z N k Y t s a W 1 1 7 j y y f r P 0 + m I i h S l u k g o U r 9 O h z k + m N J p e Z B w q q 1 S a F Y T o M r G r H S F + J K U 1 9 V p L m 2 S S 5 F y J S Z E E 2 + u y 5 o w v W C Q E j C V C + T p i o U m X Y y / Q R c v q B y S l K q Y 6 I W q S + S p S y D b R J k 3 V C Z C R 3 z L O o F Z j x g o a R B N 3 w g U n B q O y w J h S T D 7 5 / v E K a D 3 V 5 u y g M p j J q V z b V E R J L m 8 a I v Q e r M h m t Y c E C g w L Q X F H D d j R Z J U e Q E U L 1 J / Q X W B X g w r 5 r Q k E e F v K O c E U c L W I K N g Y V s m l b J 2 P X 1 Z l + u J B K S 6 x j m X 5 l Q f F a r w 6 q 7 Y h t m p 6 1 j J i S 7 k 8 q y I o W 1 p e 1 c t C A x v W E k Y V o z S Y y X y R X L T I t E c y l m 3 f Z A Z s Q y E 8 x W t Q u g I q F y X v 3 P + D g 2 R + b O e u R i q u I k a + c 6 F T D H K T F x i v C M 0 G a c X s q 8 P o L V k v 5 S h a p a W 9 v e 3 i Z j K U Q I x a 0 8 e p G w M k 8 o h z p w H I x B f m o b Y 4 d M W c g z b g Q B K E V K s 7 V J x m Z t c g m n J x e q 9 l f l 2 H n o R X W D V O V B Z / d i 2 n t V n r d G z 5 u w N K V V e V L f e p 5 A S J G A 0 o u q H K H Z i 4 B X Q p H m T f W 9 z u 6 P A s u G 2 q P 6 1 u g k c r N Z Q o J U M H / z l 5 W T n Y l t 3 M l O 1 T i o j F I O L i O z y J u 7 C m H z o s k O O K r K i a P z f 4 m j c 4 x L e L o U B A z 8 s D 1 g c N 3 E r S r a 1 C N t w I p q T a E 2 Q B X 5 U g A w n A n P w i U / M P T D 5 s / R Y R 5 w C S L q p i 4 i i 2 + Z R A y 2 x S H v R g H b 4 q k K E U + g E S 0 / y E a n p 1 T p s p x o N t d l / V z 9 N g F U t V s X w P H V F F 7 W T c a J U a I 8 u e y G 0 z x b k E a L N q X 3 I q y 3 y 0 + h A v y j u F 7 f I h 9 R Y F G A i F n E E M U W x Y i U R Q r R 3 K K u F y K L I k Q L i x a I b i 2 6 R S Q t k o i u L b p G l F n U d W l h U Y H o x K I T R D c W 3 S C a W T R D J F I W o Y z N E / r g 4 O n O V z 9 V T p 8 I Q + F v Y N m e j d 3 D s A O L D h A d W 3 S 8 a m P J D H 4 z C P Q J k 3 y O m j e t V M t u m 8 g K j a 5 F 3 3 X r u G 7 7 r b d U L q Y a S 4 E N S T M + Z c a y W 9 1 m K p q 1 / X o O L Y q 9 e o 6 L e + P i N 5 0 M L u 6 k e O 3 i 1 4 i P X H y E + N T F p 4 g P X X z Y y e z i Y 8 R j F 4 8 R n 7 n 4 D P G F i y / + Y 4 K N P M 7 X V i 3 u M 8 W 0 I i I k 8 J P t w x f l t 0 3 6 q M n 1 / X K E 9 R G d W f Q K 0 S t U A N G p R R 8 Q f c A 3 C + x u + 8 n T 1 g P S z t d Y o 0 7 R v s P R t O / o V N 3 v O / a x M 7 q X 0 o F v x f H d v T 5 y c b e p h y 7 u 6 u y 5 2 B w n + O Q e 3 v 3 A X j b e P t 8 d / r D 7 4 p c X W y / 3 2 4 / v h 9 4 3 3 q b 3 z B t 6 P 3 o v v S N v 7 F 1 4 g R d 5 v 3 t / e H + u / 7 3 h b T z Y e N S E 3 r / X 5 n z t 9 a 6 N p / 8 A D b q D x Q = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; I t &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 5 V y 4D O W Q U m X 3 s Z O L v B o w N F U t t T k = " &gt; A A A M Z 3 i c j Z Z t b 9 0 0 F M e z 8 T T a w j q Q E B J v T K t K Q y r l 3 m m C V 4 i 1 t 1 t b q V S X r t 2 m k V E 5 u U 5 i N Y l T 2 7 k P j f J N e A v f i Y / A t + A 4 i U + S 3 g s i U h v 7 d 8 7 x s f 8 + z r W X x V z p w e C v e / f f e / + D D z 9 6 8 P H a + s Y n n z 7 c f P T Z K y V y 6 b N L X 8 R C v v G o Y j F P 2 a X m O m Z v M s l o 4 s X s t X c 9 M v b X U y Y V F + m F X m T s X U L D l A fc p x r Q 1 e a m m 1 A d + T Q u f i 6 v 3 E z x q 8 3 t w d 6 g e s h y Y 9 g 0 t p 3 m G V 8 9 W v / J n Q g / T 1 i q / Z g q 9 e t w k O l 3 B Z W a + z E r 1 9 x c s Y z 6 1 z R k h S f E t a a e K k n 9 7 J B M i o A p M z 8 a f 3 u T 0 5 j r B Q G X m K l e J E 1 U I F L d i f R i M H m C y g k x a y B q k X g i X o o y 2 A Z B 1 J T K V O i I p 2 H P M e U + C y T 12 + F 9 k Y B R 2 2 F J I C Q Z f v d k l z D t 7 / V i E + 5 L Y c Q t b a w l I p Q 0 i x Z 9 C Z L O b L i G B f s E E k x 6 T j 7 X 7 W i h F H l G A F V 7 1 l 9 g l Y D 7 8 7 J 2 D X i Y y z v K G X G 0 g C V Y H 1 j I l q m c l N 3 c b P X l i k M h u Y 5 g / q V x x b 5 a 7 V b e F ds w O 2 0 d M S H Z n V C W 5 g m s L W n m o g W J 6 J S R m G n N J D F W J l c s M 8 l j z a W Y t d s D k S F L j T N b V S 6 A 8 p j K e f k / / a P I n K A 7 6 5 G L i Y r i t J n r R M A c J 8 T 4 K c J T Q u t x e i H z 6 k S W S / p L F a h y b W 1 n Z 4 e M p R A B J L f y 6 E X M i i y m H P L A c T A N 8 m N T G L t k w g K e c i M I Q C k S m q 6 5 K Z s 1 w Q W c n k y o y l 4 W 4 0 6 n 5 9 U O U h a H b b v n 0 7 z L 4 q J p 9 K w x S x J a F q f V q 2 f x h R Q x K L 0 o i x E 2 e x 7 w S c i T r M 6 + 3 7 b 7 o 8 C y I f e o e t U 6 i c x s l p A g F c z f / K W F u + v a w n V 3 y 9 p A Z Z h w M B m Z R V a / V Q C b F 7 q 7 Y C j L j h + d / 4 s f n a N f z J M l J 2 B g h + 2 B B t e 1 3 6 q k d T 7 S O K z I V i d q H F S e L T k A w 5 n w N F i y A 0 M 7 b P 4 c D a a D S x B h O 3 U R W n z L J G J o W x z w d h R o W z x R A W I X C t H y w 3 R 0 d k a V L g p X s 7 k u q n 7 5 m w u o b L b O h + O r K X y s 6 4 h T o 0 R x e t U O p 3 m 6 I L U W T U j v Q 1 h t l 5 d A B v h H c b 2 e R R 4 i 3 y I f E b O I I Y o s i h A p i x S i u U V t L Y Q W h Y g W F i 0 Q 3 V p 0 i 0 h a J B H d W H S D K L W o r d L c o h z R q U W n i K Y W T R H N L J o h E g k L U c a 6 h z Y 4 e L q 1 V b 2 y U y f C U P g b W L Z v f f f R 7 d C i Q 0 Q n F p 2 s 2 l g y g 9 8 M A n X C J J + j 5 n U p V b L b I r J C o 2 n R N 9 1 2 T L f 9 0 l t K F 1 G N q a A N Q T M + Y a Z l t 7 q J V D R t 6 v U C S h R r 9 Q I X 9 7 K L X 7 Y y d H E r x Y s u f o H 4 u I u P E Z 9 1 8 R n i o y 4 + a m X u 4 h P E 4 y 4 e I z 7 v 4 n P E l 1 1 8 + R 8 T r O X p 3 L Y q c R 8 r p h U R A Y G f b A 8 u m N / U 4 a M 6 1 v O K E e Z H d G 7 R c 0 T P U Q F E Z x a 9 R f Q W v y y w u 8 2 V p 8 l n r q 4 F X m J H r a J 9 Q 0 f T v q F V 9 a B v O M D K a D 9 K h 5 4 V x + v u 9 X E X t 5 t 6 1 M V t n v 0 u N s c J r t z D u x f s 5 c a r J 3 v D 7 / e e / v J 0 + 9 l B c / l + 4 H z l b D m P n a H z g / P M O X b G z q X j O 1 P n d + c P 5 8 / 1 v z c e b n y x 8 W X t e v 9 e E / O 5 0 3 s 2 v v 4 H 4 K a J 3 g = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; M &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " Y u z w Y 7 w h C P + Q o D y 7 6 K 5 Y 7 F P y Q R g = " &gt; A A A M V n i c j Z Z R b 9 x E E M f d Q m m 5 B E j h k Z d V o k h F C u E u Q v C E a H J p k 0 h R d E 2 T t i p X o r V v b a 9 i e 5 3 d d e 4 c y 5 + A V / h u 8 G U Q s 7 Z 3 b O c O h K X E 4 9 / M 7 O z + d 9 Z n N 4 2 4 0 s P h X w 8 e f v T x o 0 8 e P / l 0 s L b + 2 e d f b D z 9 8 o 0 S m f T Y p S c i I d + 5 V L G I J + x S c x 2 x d 6 l k N H Y j 9 t a 9 H h v / 2 1 s m F R f J h c 5 T 9 i G m Q c J 9 7 l E N 6 J W 8 2 t g a 7 g 6 r i y w b o 8 b Y c p p r c v V 0 7 e f p T H h Z z B L t R V S p X 0 b D V H 8 o q N T c i 1 g 5 m G a K p d S 7 p g E r X C G u N X V V S e p r m 6 R S + E y Z 6 d D o 2 5 u M R l z n B E I i p n q Z N F a + S H Q n 0 4 3 A 5 Q o q Z y S m O i Q q j 1 0 R L W U Z b J M g 6 5 b K R O i Q J 0 E v M O E e 8 y X 1 2 u E 9 E Y N T 2 2 G J L y Q Z f b e 3 Q 5 j 2 d n u 5 M f e k M F q W N t c S E U i a h n l f g r g z G 6 5 h w R 6 B A r N e k M d 1 O 1 o g R Z Y S Q N U W 9 R d Y F e D e o q x D f R 5 k 8 p 5 y R h w t Y A k 2 B h a y a R o l Y T c 3 m 3 2 5 o k B I r k O Y f 2 l C 8 V m t D i v v i 2 2 Y n b Y O m Z D s X i p L s h j W F j d z 0 Y K E 9 J a R i G n N J D F e J l c s M 8 4 i z a W Y t 9 s D m Q F L T D B b 1 S 6 A s o j K R f k / 4 8 P Q H J h 7 6 5 H 5 T I V R 0 s x 1 J m C O M 2 L i F O E J o f U 4 v Z R F d Q D L J f 2 l 8 l U 5 G G x v b 5 O J F M K H 4 l Y e n U e s S C P K o Q 4 c B 2 O Q n 5 r G 2 C E z 5 v O E G 0 E A S h H T Z D B N 2 L x J L u D 0 p E J V / r K Y d B 5 6 U e 0 g Z X H Y 2 r 2 Y 5 l 4 W F 4 3 R 8 0 Y s j m l Z n F a 3 n s c T U k S g d F 4 W Y z R 7 E f B K y O K 0 r r 7 f 2 v 1 R Y N l Q e 1 z d a p 1 E a j Z L S J A K 5 m / + k m K 6 M 7 W N O 9 0 p a w e V Q c z B Z W Q W a X 1 X P m x e M N 0 B R 1 l 2 4 u j i X + L o A u M i H i 8 F A Q M / b A 8 Y X N d x q 4 r W 9 U g T s K J a X a g J U F m 6 F A A M Z 8 I T f 8 k P D P 2 w + Q t 0 m A d c g g j a q Y v A 4 j s m E Y N t s c / b U c C 2 e K Z 8 x F N o R M s P k / H Z G V W 6 K K a a L X R R P Z e / T g G V z d Z 5 c H w 1 h Z d 1 n X F q l C h O r 9 r h N E 9 y U m v R p P R e h N V 2 u T F U g H 8 U 1 + t a 5 C L y L P I Q M Y s Y o t C i E J G y S C F a W N T 2 Q m B R g C i 3 K E d 0 Z 9 E d I m m R R H R j 0 Q 2 i x K K 2 S z O L M k S n F p 0 i u r X o F t H c o j k i E b M A Z a y f 0 A c H T 7 e + 6 q n s 9 I k w F P 6 G l u 3 b 2 H 0 M O 7 T o E N G J R S e r N p b M 4 T e D Q J 8 w y R e o e d 1 K l e y 2 i a z Q 6 M r 7 r r u O 6 6 7 f e k v l Q q q x F N i Q N O c z Z i y 7 1 U 2 m o k n T r x f Q o t i r F 7 i 4 1 1 3 8 u p W h i 1 s p X n b x S 8 T H X X y M + K y L z x A f d f F R K 3 M X n y C e d P E E 8 X k X n y O + 7 O L L / 5 h g L U / n a 6 s S 9 5 l i W h H h E / j J d u F 7 8 p s 6 f V z n u m 4 x x v q I z i 1 6 g e g F K o D o z K L 3 i N 7 j m w V 2 t / n k a e o B a e Z r r H G r a N / R 0 b T v a F U 9 6 D s O s D P a l 9 K h a 8 V x u 3 t 9 3 M X t p h 5 1 c V t n v 4 v N c Y J P 7 t H 9 D + x l 4 8 3 e 7 u i H 3 e 9 f 7 W 0 9 P 2 g + v p 8 4 X z u b z j N n 5 P z o P H e O n Y l z 6 X g O c 3 5 z f n f + W P t z 7 e / 1 R + u P 6 9 C H D 5 q c r 5 z e t b 7 x D + M i h A Q = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; r &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " Q v v 7 t d t 2 U V Q C 1 e n x k L e 3 t C s e E f E = " &gt; A A A M V n i c j Z Z R b 9 x E E M f d Q m m 5 B E j h k Z d V o k h F C u E u Q v C E a H J p k 0 h R d E 2 T t i p X o r V v b a 9 i e 5 3 d d e 4 c y 5 + A V / h u 8 G U Q s 7 Z 3 b O c O h K X E 4 9 / M 7 O z + d 9 Z n N 4 2 4 0 s P h X w 8 e f v T x o 0 8 e P / l 0 s L b + 2 e d f b D z 9 8 o 0 S m f T Y p S c i I d + 5 V L G I J + x S c x 2 x d 6 l k N H Y j 9 t a 9 H h v / 2 1 s m F R f J h c 5 T 9 i G m Q c J 9 7 l E N 6 F V w t b E 1 3 B 1 W F 1 k 2 R o 2 x 5 T T X 5 O r p 2 s / T m f C y m C X a i 6 h S v 4 y G q f 5 Q U K m 5 F 7 F y M M 0 U S 6 l 3 T Q N W u E J c a + q q k t T X N k m l 8 J k y 0 6 H R t z c Z j b j O C Y R E T P U y a a x 8 k e h O p h u B y x V U z k h M d U h U H r s i W s o y 2 C Z B 1 i 2 V i d A h T 4 J e Y M I 9 5 k v q t c N 7 I g a n t s M S X 0 g y + m 5 v h z D t 7 f Z y Y + 5 J Y b Q s b a 4 l I p A 0 D f O + B H F n N l z D g j 0 C B W a 9 I I / r d r R A i i w l g K o t 6 i + w K s C 9 R V m H + j z I 5 D 3 l j D h a w B J s D C x k 0 z R K w m 5 u N v t y R Y G Q X I c w / 9 K E 4 r N a H V b e F 9 s w O 2 0 d M i H Z v V S W Z D G s L W 7 m o g U J 6 S 0 j E d O a S W K 8 T K 5 Y Z p x F m k s x b 7 c H M g O W m G C 2 q l 0 A Z R G V i / J / x o e h O T D 3 1 i P z m Q q j p J n r T M A c Z 8 T E K c I T Q u t x e i m L 6 g C W S / p L 5 a t y M N j e 3 i Y T K Y Q P x a 0 8 O o 9 Y k U a U Q x 0 4 D s Y g P z W N s U N m z O c J N 4 I A l C K m y W C a s H m T X M D p S Y W q / G U x 6 T z 0 o t p B y u K w t X s x z b 0 s L h q j 5 4 1 Y H N O y O K 1 u P Y 8 n p I h A 6 b w s x m j 2 I u C V k M V p X X 2 / t f u j w L K h 9 r i 6 1 T q J 1 G y W k C A V z N / 8 J c V 0 Z 2 o b d 7 p T 1 g 4 q g 5 i D y 8 g s 0 v q u f N i 8 Y L o D j r L s x N H F v 8 T R B c Z F P F 4 K A g Z + 2 B 4 w u K 7 j V h W t 6 5 E m Y E W 1 u l A T o L J 0 K Q A Y z o Q n / p I f G P p h 8 x f o M A + 4 B B G 0 U x e B x X d M I g b b Y p + 3 o 4 B t 8 U z 5 i K f Q i J Y f J u O z M 6 p 0 U U w 1 W + i i e i 5 / n Q I q m 6 3 z 4 P h q C i / r O u P U K F G c X r X D a Z 7 k p N a i S e m 9 C K v t c m O o A P 8 o r t e 1 y E X k W e Q h Y h Y x R K F F I S J l k U K 0 s K j t h c C i A F F u U Y 7 o z q I 7 R N I i i e j G o h t E i U V t l 2 Y W Z Y h O L T p F d G v R L a K 5 R X N E I m Y B y l g / o Q 8 O n m 5 9 1 V P Z 6 R N h K P w N L d u 3 s f s Y d m j R I a I T i 0 5 W b S y Z w 2 8 G g T 5 h k i 9 Q 8 7</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>s b v P J 0 9 Q D 0 s z X W O N W 0 b 6 j o 2 n f 0 a p 6 0 H c c Y G e 0 L 6 V D 1 4 r j d v f 6 u I v b T T 3 q 4 r b O f h e b 4 w S f 3 K P 7 H 9 j L x p u 9 3 d E P u 9 + / 2 t t 6 f t B 8 f D 9 x v n Y 2 n W f O y P n R e e 4 c O x P n 0 v E c 5 v z m / O 7 8 s f b n 2 t / r j 9 Y f 1 6 E P H z Q 5 X z m 9 a 3 3 j H 1 + 8 g / k = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; g &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " R U X L 6 L z W g B z 1 X w o F 3 9 P p 2 n s M u j 4</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a 9 i e 5 3 d d e 4 c y 5 + A V / h u 8 G U Q s 7 Z 3 b O c O h K X E 4 9 / M 7 O z + d 9 Z n N 4 2 4 0 s P h X w 8 e f v T x o 0 8 e P / l 0 s L b + 2 e d f b D z 9 8 o 0 S m f T Y p S c i I d + 5 V L G I J + x S c x 2 x d 6 l k N H Y j 9 t a 9 H h v / 2 1 s m F R f J h c 5 T 9 i G m Q c J 9 7 l E N 6 J V 7 t b E 1 3 B 1 W F 1 k 2 R o 2 x 5 T T X 5 O r p 2 s / T m f C y m C X a i 6 h S v 4 y G q f 5 Q U K m 5 F 7 F y M M 0 U S 6 l 3 T Q N W u E J c a + q q k t T X N k m l 8 J k y 0 6 H R t z c Z j b j O C Y R E T P U y a a x 8 k e h O p h u B y x V U z k h M d U h U H r s i W s o y 2 C Z B 1 i 2 V i d A h T 4 J e Y M I 9 5 k v q t c N 7 I g a n t s M S X 0 g y + m 5 v h z D t 7 f Z y Y + 5 J Y b Q s b a 4 l I p A 0 D f O + B H F n N l z D g j 0 C B W a 9 I I / r d r R A i i w l g K o t 6 i + w K s C 9 R V m H + j z I 5 D 3 l j D h a w B J s D C x k 0 z R K w m 5 u N v t y R Y G Q X I c w / 9 K E 4 r N a H V b e F 9 s w O 2 0 d</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>s b v P J 0 9 Q D 0 s z X W O N W 0 b 6 j o 2 n f 0 a p 6 0 H c c Y G e 0 L 6 V D 1 4 r j d v f 6 u I v b T T 3 q 4 r b O f h e b 4 w S f 3 K P 7 H 9 j L x p u 9 3 d E P u 9 + / 2 t t 6 f t B 8 f D 9 x v n Y 2 n W f O y P n R e e 4 c O x P n 0 v E c 5 v z m / O 7 8 s f b n 2 t / r j 9 Y f 1 6 E P H z Q 5 X z m 9 a 3 3 j H y Q C g / Q = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; b &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " A Z g E i Z 6 m Y Z R X O x u w D I r Z O o F x 8 M g = " &gt; A A A M M H i c j Z b N b t t G E M e Z 9 C u x + p G 0 6 K m X h Q 0 D D q C 6 U m o 0 6 K F A b D m x D R i G 6 t h J k C g 1 l t S S X J j k 0 r t L S z L B Z + i 1 f Y 0 + T X s q e u 1 T d J b k D k l L L U r A 5 v A 3 M / v x n 1 m K b h p x p Q e D P + 7 c f e / 9 D z 7 8 6 N 7 9 t d 7 H n 3 z 6 2 Y O H n 7 9 U I p M e O / d E J O R r l y o W 8 Y S d a 6 4 j 9 j q V j M Z u x F 6 5 l y P j f 3 X N p O I i O d O L l L 2 L a Z B w n 3</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>1 &lt;</head><label>1</label><figDesc>n 5 I L x k v H 2 8 P v 9 v e + X F n 4 + l e / U l 9 z / n K W X e 2 n K H z x H n q H D p j<ref type="bibr" target="#b5">5</ref> 9 z x H O 7 8 7 P z i / N r 7 r f d 7 7 8 / e X 1 X o 3 T t 1 z h d O 5 + r 9 / Q 8 f 2 H o a &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; (x, y) + l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " r U Y u 9 X P T 2 0 d P x s R A o z W r o 3 n 7 i b I = " &gt; A A A M X H i c j Z f f b 9 x E E M f d U q A k A V q Q e O F l l S h S E S H c V R U 8 I Z p c m h 9 S F B 1 p 0 l T l S r T 2 r e 1 V b K + z u 8 6 d Y / m P 4 B X + M l 7 4 W 5 i 1 v W P 7 7 k C c d P H 4 M z M 7 u 9 + d 9 T l u G n G l B 4 O / H j z 8 4 N G H H 3 3 8 + J O 1 9 Y 1 P P / v 8 y d M v 3 i i R S Y 9 d e i I S 8 q 1 L F Y t 4 w i 4 1 1 x F 7 m 0 p G Y z d i V + 7 N y P i v 7 p h U X C Q X O k / Z + 5 g G C f e 5 R z W g q 8 P r Q n 8 7 L K + f b A 1 2 B 9 W H L B v D x t h y m s / 4 + u n 6 z 5 O p 8 L K Y J d q L q F K / D g e p f l 9 Q q b k X s X J t k i m W U u + G B q x w h b j R 1 F U l q T / b J J X C Z 8 p M i k b f 3 W Y 0 4 j o n E B I x 1 c u k s f J F o j u Z b g Q u V 1 A 5 J T H V I V F 5 7 I p o K c t g m w R Z d 1 Q m Q o c 8 C X q B C f e Y L 6 n X D u + J G J z a D k t 8 I c n w + + c 7 h G l v t 5 c b c 0 8 K o 2 h p c y 0 R g a R p m P c l i D u z 4 R o W 7 B E o M O 0 F e V y 3 o w V S Z C k B V G 1 U f 4 F V A e 7 N y z r U 5 0 E m F 5 Q z 4 m g B S 7 A x s J B N 0 y 4 J u 7 3 d 7 M s V B U J y H c L 8 S x O K 9 2 p 1 W L k o t m F 2 2 j p k Q r K F V J Z k M a w t b u a i B Q n p H S M R 0 5 p J Y r x M r l h m n E W a S z F r t w c y A 5 a Y Y L a q X Q B l E Z X z 8 n / G h 6 E 5 N g v r k f l U h V H S z H U q Y I 5 T Y u I U 4 Q m h 9 T i 9 l H l 1 D M s l / a X y V b m 2 t r 2 9 T c Z S C B + K W 3 l 0 H r E i j S i H O n A c j E F + a h p j h 0 y Z z x N u B A E o R U y T t U n C Z k 1 y A a c n F a r y l 8 W 4 c 9 O L a g c p i 4 P W 7 s U 0 1 7 K 4 a I y e N 2 J x T M v i t L r 0 P J 6 Q I g K l 8 7 I Y o d m L g E d C F q d 1 9 b 3 W 7 o 8 C y 4 b a o + p S 6 y R S s 1 l C g l Q w f / N N i s n O x D b u Z K e s H V Q G M Q e X k V m k 9 V X 5 s H n B Z A c c Z d m J o / N / i a N z j I t 4 v B Q E D P y w P W B w X c e t K l r X I 0 3 A i m p 1 o S Z A Z e l S A D C c C U / 8 J T 8 w 9 M P m z 9 F h b n A J I m i n L g K L 7 5 l E D L b F P m 9 H A d v i q f I R T 6 A R L T 9 I R m d n V O m i m G g 2 1 0</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>h o 2 n e 0 q u 7 3 H f v Y G e 1 D 6 c C 1 4 r j d v T 7 u 4 n Z T j 7 q 4 r b P X x e Y 4 w S v 3 c P E F e 9 l 4 8 3 x 3 + M P u i 1 9 e b L 3 c b 1 6 + H z t f O 5 v O M 2 f o / O i 8 d I 6 d s X P p e M 6 N 8 7 v z h / P n + t 8 b j z b g v 4 Q 6 9 O G D J u d L p / f Z + O o f i / 2 F P g = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>F</head><label></label><figDesc>t+1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 7 J 9 4 i B 0 Y L i 1 y r M M W i Y 1 9 m g m 6 r B E = " &gt; A A A M X H i c j Z d R b 9 x E E M f d U q A k A V q Q e O F l l S h S E S H c V R U 8 I Z p c 2 i R S F B 1 p 0 l b l S r T 2 r e 1 V 1 l 5 n d 5 2 7 i + U P w S t 8 M l 7 4 L M z a 3 r G d O x A n X T z + z c z O 7 n 9 n f Y 6 f C a 7 N Y P D X v f s f P P j w o 4 8 f f r K 2 v v H p Z 5 8 / e v z F a y 1 z F b C L Q A q p 3 v p U M 8 F T d m G 4 E e x t p h h N f M H e + F c j 6 3 9 z w 5 T m M j 0 3 i 4 y 9 T 2 i U 8 p A H 1 A B 6 c 3 x Z m G + H 5 e W j r c H u o P q Q Z W P Y G F t e 8 x l f P l 7 / e T K V Q Z 6 w 1 A S C a v 3 r c J C Z 9 w V V h g e C l W u T X L O M B l c 0 Y o U v 5 Z W h v i 5 J / d k m m Z I h 0 3 Z S V H x 3 n V P B z Y J A i G C 6 l 0 k T H c r U d D J 9 A S 5 f U j U l C T U x 0 Y v E l 2 I p y 2 K X B F k 3 V K X S x D y N e o E p D 1 i o a N A O H 8 g E n M Y N S 0 K p y P D 7 p z u E m W C 3 l 5 v w Q E m r a O l y H Z G R o l m 8 6 E u Q d G b D D S w 4 I F B g 2 g s K u G l H i 5 T M M w K o 2 q j + A q s C P J i X d W j I o 1 z d U c 6 K Y y Q s w c X A Q j Z t u 6 T s + n q z L 5 e I p O I m h v m X N h T v 9 e q w 8 q 7 Y l r l p m 5 h J x e 6 k s j R P Y G 1 J M x c j S U x v G B H M G K a I 9 T K 1 Y p l J L g x X c t Z u D 2 R G L L X B b F W 7 A M o F V f P y f 8 b H s T 0 2 d 9 a j F l M d i 7 S Z 6 1 T C H K f E x m n C U 0 L r c X o p 8 + o Y l k v 6 K x 3 q c m 1 t e 3 u b j J W U I R R 3 8p i F Y E U m K I c 6 c B y s Q X 5 q G m O H T F n I U 2 4 F A a h k Q t O 1 S c p m T X I B p y e T u v K X x b h z 0 4 t q B y m L g 9 b u x T T X s j h v j J 5 X s C S h Z X F S X X q e Q C o p Q O l F W Y z Q 7 E X A I y F P s r r 6 X m v 3 R 4 F l Q + 1 R d a l 1 k p n d L K l A Kp i / / a b F Z G f i G n e y U 9 Y O q q K E g 8 v K L L P 6 q k P Y v G i y A 4 6 y 7 M T R + b / E 0 T n G C Z 4 s B Q E D P 2 w P G N z U c a u K 1 v V I E 7 C i W l 2 o C d B 5 t h Q A D G f C 0 3 D J D w z 9 s P l z d N g b X I K M 2 q n L y O F b p h C D 7 X D I 2 1 H A d n i q Q 8 Q T a E T H D 9 L R 6 S n V p i g m h s 1 N U d 2 X v 0 0 A l c 3 W B X B 8 D Y W H d Z 1 x Y p U o T i 7 b 4 Q x P F 6 T W ok n p P Q i r 7 f I T q A B / K K 7 X d 8 h H F D g U I G I O M U S x Q z E i 7 Z B G N H e o 7 Y X I o Q j R w q E F o l u H b h E p h x S i a 4 e u E a U O t V 2 a O 5 Q j O n H o B N G N Q z e I Z g 7 N E M m E R S h j f Y c + O H i m 9 V V 3 Z a d P p K X w H T i 2 5 2 L 3 M O z A o Q N E x w 4 d r 9 p Y M o P f D A J 9 w h S f o + Z 1 K 1 W y u y Z y Q q N r 0 X f d d l y 3 / d Z b K h d T g 6 X A h q Q Z n z J r u a 1 u M j V N m 3 4 9 h x b F X j 3 H x b 3 q 4 l e t D F 3 c S v G y i 1 8 i P u r i I 8 S n X X y K + L C L D 1 u Z u / g Y 8 b i L x 4 j P u v g M 8 U U X X / z H B G t 5 O m 9 b l b h P N D O a y J D A T 7 Y P b 5 X f 1 O m j O t f 3 i x H W R 3 T m 0 A t E L 1 A B R K c O v U P 0 D p 8 s s L v N K 0 9 T D 0 g z X 2 u N W k X 7 j o 6 m f U e r 6 n 7 f s Y + d 0 T 6 U D n w n j t / d 6 6 M u b j f 1 s I v b O n t d b I 8 T v H I P 7 7 5 g L x u v n + 4 O f 9 h 9 9 s u z r e f 7 z c v 3 Q + 9 r b 9 N 7 4 g 2 9 H 7 3 n 3 p E 3 9 i 6 8 w L v y f v f + 8 P 5 c / 3 v j w Q b 8 l 1 C H 3 r / X 5 H z p 9 T 4 b X / 0 D r + W F Q Q = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " o m d V L K 9 l c N Q w F u 2 H x j 1 Q R v 1 w N p U = " &gt; A A A M V n i c j Z Z R b 9 x E E M f d Q m l J A q T w y M s q U a Q i h X B X K n h C N L m 0 S a Q o u q Z J W 5 U r 0 d q 3 t l e x v c 7 u O n e O 5 U / A K 3 w 3 + D K I W d s 7 t u 8 O h K X E 4 9 / M 7 O z + d 9 Z n N 4 2 4 0 o P B X / f u f / T x g 0 8 e P v p 0 b X 3 j s 8 + / 2 H z 8 5 R s l M u m x S 0 9 E Q r 5 z q W I R T 9 i l 5 j p i 7 1 L J a O x G 7 K 1 7 P T L + t 7 d M K i 6 S C 5 2 n 7 E N M g 4 T 7 3 K M a 0 K v v r z a 3 B 3 u D 6 i L L x r A x t p 3 m G l 8 9 X v 9 5 M h V e F r N E e x F V 6 p f h I N U f C i o 1 9 y J W r k 0 y x V L q X d O A F a 4 Q 1 5 q 6 q i T 1 t U N S K X y m z H R o 9 O 1 N R i O u c w I h E V O 9 T B o r X y S 6 k + l G 4 H I F l V M S U x 0 S l c e u i J a y D L Z J k H V L Z S J 0 y J O g F 5 h w j / m S e u 3 w n o j B q e 2 w x B e S D L 9 7 u k u Y 9 v Z 6 u T H 3 p D B a l j b X E h F I m o Z 5 X 4 K 4 M x u u Y c E e g Q L T X p D H d T t a I E W W E k D V F v U X W B X g 3 r y s Q 3 0 e Z H J B O S O O F r A E G w M L 2 T K N k r C b m 6 2 + X F E g J N c h z L 8 0 o f i s V o e V i 2 I b Z q e t Q y Y k W 0 h l S R b D 2 u J m L l q Q k N 4 y E j G t m S T G y + S K Z c Z Z p L k U s 3 Z 7 I D N g i Q l m q 9 o F U B Z R O S / / Z 3 w Y m g O z s B 6 Z T 1 U Y J c 1 c p w L m O C U m T h G e E F q P 0 0 u Z V w e w X N J f K l + V a 2 s 7 O z t k L I X w o b i V R + c R K 9 K I c q g D x 8 E Y 5 K e m M X b J l P k 8 4 U Y Q g F L E N F m b J G z W J B d w e l K h K n 9 Z j D s P v a h 2 k L I 4 b O 1 e T H M v i 4 v G 6 H k j F s e 0 L E 6 r W 8 / j C S k i U D o v i x G a v Q h 4 J W R x W l f f b + 3 + K L B s q D 2 q b r V O I j W b J S R I B f M 3 f 0 k x 2 Z 3 Y x p 3 s l r W D y i D m 4 D I y i 7 S + K x 8 2 L 5 j s g q M s O 3 F 0 / i 9 x d I 5 x E Y + X g o C B H 7 Y H D K 7 r u F V F 6 3 q k C V h R r S 7 U B K g s X Q o A h j P h i b / k B 4 Z + 2 P w 5 O s w D L k E E 7 d R F Y P E d k 4 j B t t j n 7 S h g W z x V P u I J N K L l h 8 n o 7 I w q X R Q T z e a 6 q J 7 L X y e A y m b r P D i + m s L L u s 4 4 N U o U p 1 f t c J o n O a m 1 a F J 6 L 8 J q u 9 w Y K s A / i u t 1 L</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>A p s S J r x K T O W 3 e o m U 9 G k 6 d c L a F H s 1 Q t c 3 O s u f t 3 K 0 M W t F C + 7 + C X i 4 y 4 + R n z W x W e I j 7 r 4 q J W 5 i 0 8 Q j 7 t 4 j P i 8 i 8 8 R X 3 b x 5 X 9 M s J a n 8 7 V V i f t E M a 2 I 8 A n 8 Z L v w P f l N n T 6 q c 1 2 3 G G F 9 R O c W v U D 0 A h V A d G b R e 0 T v 8 c 0 C u 9 t 8 8 j T 1 g D T z N d a o V b T v 6 G j a d 7 S q H v Q d B 9 g Z 7 U v p 0 L X i u N 2 9 P u 7 i d l O P u r i t s 9 / F 5 j j B J / d w 8 Q N 7 2 X j z d G / 4 w 9 6 z V 8 + 2 n x 8 0 H 9 + P n K + d L e e J M 3 R + d J 4 7 x 8 7 Y u X Q 8 h z m / O b 8 7 f 6 z / u f 7 3 x o O N h 3 X o / X t N z l d O 7 9 r Y / A f z B 4 P H &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; 3 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " o m d V L K 9 l c N Q w F u 2 H x j 1 Q R v 1 w N p U = " &gt; A A A M V n i c j Z Z R b 9 x E E M f d Q m l J A q T w y M s q U a Q i h X B X K n h C N L m 0 S a Q o u q Z J W 5 U r 0 d q 3 t l e x v c 7 u O n e O 5 U / A K 3 w 3 + D K I W d s 7 t u 8 O h K X E 4 9 / M 7 O z + d 9 Z n N 4 2 4 0 o P B X / f u f / T x g 0 8 e P v p 0 b X 3 j s 8 + / 2 H z 8 5 R s l M u m x S 0 9 E Q r 5 z q W I R T 9 i l 5 j p i 7 1 L J a O x G 7 K 1 7 P T L + t 7 d M K i 6 S C 5 2 n 7 E N M g 4 T 7 3 K M a 0 K v v r z a 3 B 3 u D 6 i L L x r A x t p 3 m G l 8 9 X v 9 5 M h V e F r N E e x F V 6 p f h I N U f C i o 1 9 y J W r k 0 y x V L q X d O A F a 4 Q 1 5 q 6 q i T 1 t U N S K X y m z H R o 9 O 1 N R i O u c w I h E V O 9 T B o r X y S 6 k + l G 4 H I F l V M S U x 0 S l c e u i J a y D L Z J k H V L Z S J 0 y J O g F 5 h w j / m S e u 3 w n o j B q e 2 w x B e S D L 9 7 u k u Y 9</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>j n 7 S h g W z x V P u I J N K L l h 8 n o 7 I w q X R Q T z e a 6 q J 7 L X y e A y m b r P D i + m s L L u s 4 4 N U o U p 1 f t c J o n O a m 1 a F J 6 L 8 J q u 9 w Y K s A / i u t 1 L</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>3 &lt;</head><label>3</label><figDesc>3 e o m U 9 G k 6 d c L a F H s 1 Q t c 3 O s u f t 3 K 0 M W t F C + 7 + C X i 4 y 4 + R n z W x W e I j 7 r 4 q J W 5 i 0 8 Q j 7 t 4 j P i 8 i 8 8 R X 3 b x 5 X 9 M s J a n 8 7 V V i f t E M a 2 I 8 A n 8 Z L v w P f l N n T 6 q c 1 2 3 G G F 9 R O c W v U D 0 A h V A d G b R e 0 T v 8 c 0 C u 9 t 8 8 j T 1 g D T z N d a o V b T v 6 G j a d 7 S q H v Q d B 9 g Z 7 U v p 0 L X i u N 2 9 P u 7 i d l O P u r i t s 9 / F 5 j j B J / d w 8 Q N 7 2 X j z d G / 4 w 9 6 z V 8 + 2 n x 8 0 H 9 + P n K + d L e e J M 3 R + d J 4 7 x 8 7 Y u X Q 8 h z m / O b 8 7 f 6 z / u f 7 3 x o O N h 3 X o / X t N z l d O 7 9 r Y / A f z B 4 P H &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " E e g + a H I B Y o m 4 7 / B N 2 n Q g w P Y y G 5 I = " &gt; A A A M a X i c j Z b f T 9 x G E M e d 9 F c K t I X 0 p W p f V i C k V K L 0 L o r a p 6 q B I w E k h K 4 E k i h 1 e l r 7 1 v Y K 2 2 t 2 1 9 w d l v + V v r b / U v + G / h O d t b 1 j m 7 t W t Q R e f 2 Z m Z / c 7 s z 5 7 W c y V H g z + e v D w g w 8 / + v i T R 5 + u r W 9 8 9 v k X m 1 u P X y u R S 5 9 d + S I W 8 q 1 H F Y t 5 y q 4 0 1 z F 7 m 0 l G E y 9 m b 7 z r k b G / u W V S c Z F e 6 k X G 3 i c 0 T H n A f a o B T T Y f F 6 4 n 4 q l a J H B z 5 7 y c 6 M n m z m B / U F 1 k e T B s B j t O c 4 0 n W + s / u 1 P h 5 w l L t R 9 T p X 4 d D j L 9 v q B S c z 9 m 5 Z q b K 5 Z R / 5 q G r P C E u N b U U y W p r 1 2 S S R E w Z V Z I 4 + 9 u c h p z v S D g E j P V i 6 S J C k S q O 5 F e D C Z P U D k l C d U R q X e x F G W w D Y K o W y p T o S O e h j 3 H l P s s k N R v p / d F A k Z t p y W B k G T 4 / d M 9 w r S / 3 4 t N u C + F k b e 0 s Z a I U N I s W v Q l S D q r 4 R o 2 7 B N T h J 6 T z 3 U 7 W y h F n h F A V d X 6 G 6 w S c H 9 e 1 q 4 B D 3 N 5 T z k j j h a w B e s D G 9 k 2 v Z O y m 5 v t v l x x K C T X E a y / N K 7 4 r F a 7 l f f F N s w u W 0 d M S H Y v l K V 5 A n t L m r V o Q S J 6 y 0 j M t G a S G C u T K 7 a Z 5 L H m U s z a 8 k B k y F L j z F a 1 C 6 A 8 p n J e / k / / K D J n 6 N 5 + 5 G K q o j h t 1 j o V s M Y p M X 6 K 8 J T Q e p 5 e y L w 6 k + W S / l I F q l x b 2 9 3 d J W M p R A D J r T x 6 E b M i i y m H P H A c z I D 8 1 D T G H p m y g K f c C A J Q i o S m a 2 7 K Z k 1 w A a c n E 6 q y l 8 W 4 8 9 D z a i c p i 6 N 2 3 P N p 7 m V x 2 Q x 6 1 p g l C S 2 L s + r W s / h C i h i U X p T F C I c 9 D 3 g l 5 E l W Z z 9 o x / 1 Z Y N u Q e 1 T d a p 1 E Z o o l J E g F 6 z d / a e H u u b Z x 3 b 2 y N l A Z J h x M R m a R 1 X c V Q P F C d w 8 M Z d n x o / N / 8 a N z 9 I t 5 s u Q E D O x Q H h h w X f u t S l r n I 4 3 D i m x 1 o s Z B 5 d m S A z B c C U + D J T s w t E P x 5 2 g w D 7 g F E b Z L F 6 H F d 0 w i h r H F A W 9 n g b H F U x U g d q E R L T 9 K R + f n V O m i c D W b 6 6 J 6 L n 9 z A Z V N 6 X w 4 v p r C y 7 q O O D N K F G e T d j r N 0 w W p t W h C e i / C q l x e A h n g H 8 X 9 e h Z 5 i H y L f E T M I o Y o s i h C p C x S i O Y W t b 0 Q W h Q i W l i 0 Q H R n 0 R 0 i a Z F E d G P R D a L U o r Z L c 4 t y R G c W n S G 6 t e g W 0 c y i G S K R s B B l r J / Q B g d P t 7 b q q e z 0 i T A U / g a W H V j f A 3 Q 7 s u g I 0 a l F p 6 s K S 2 b w m 0 G g T 5 j k c 9 S 8 b q V K d t t E V m g 0 L f q m u 4 7 p r t 9 6 S + k i q j E V j C F o x q f M j G y p m 0 h F 0 6 Z f L 6 F F s V c v c X O v u v h V K 0 M X t 1 K 8 7 O K X i E + 6 + A T x e R e f I z 7 u 4 u N W 5 i 4 + R T z u 4 j H i i y 6 + Q H z V x V f / s c B a n s 7 X V i X u E 8 W 0 I i I g 8 J P t w S f m t 3 X 4 q I 7 1 v G K E + R F d W P Q C 0 Q t U A N G 5 R e 8 Q v c M 3 C 1 S 3 + e R p 8 g F p 1 m t G o 1 b R v q G j a d / Q q n r Y N x x i Z 7 Q v p S P P i u N 1 a 3 3 S x W 1 R j 7 u 4 z X P Q x e Y 4 w S f 3 8 P 4 H 9 v L g 9 d P 9 4 Q / 7 z 3 5 5 t v P 8 s P n 4 f u R 8 4 2 w 7 T 5 y h 8 6 P z 3 D l x x s 6 V 4 z t z 5 3 f n D + f P 9 b 8 3 t j a + 2 v i 6 d n 3 4 o I n 5 0 u l d G z v / A G 0 t i w s = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; ? t &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " + Q f A n y M r w u M M n A T B + e 7 N L P + C i 7 M = " &gt; A A A M d n i c j Z b f b 9 x E E M f d 8 q s k A V J 4 R I J V o o g i H e G u q u A J 0 e T S J p G i 6 E i T t m p d o r V v b a 9 i e 5 3 d d e 4 u l h / 5 a 3 i F P 4 b / h E d m b e / Y z h 0 I S 4 n X n 5 n Z 2 f 3 O r M 9 e F n O l h 8 O / 7 t 1 / 7 / 0 P P v z o w c d r 6 x u f f P r Z 5 s P P X y q R S 5 9 d + C I W 8 r V H F Y t 5 y i 4 0 1 z F 7 n U l G E y 9 m r 7 y r s b G / u m F S c Z G e 6 0 X G 3 i U 0 T H n A f a o B X W 5 + X b i e i K d q k c D N n f P y s n A T q i M v K O b l Q J e X m 9 v D 3 W F 1 k e X B q B l s O 8 0 1 u X y 4 / r M 7 F X 6 e s F T 7 M V X q 7 W i Y 6 X c F l Z r 7 M S v X 3 F y x j P p X N G S F J 8 S V p p 4 q S X 3 t k E y K g C m z X B p / d 5 3 T m O s F A Z e Y q V 4 k T V Q g U t 2 J 9 G I w e Y L K K T E b I P W W l q I M t k E Q d U N l K n T E 0 7 D n m H K f B Z L 6 7 f S + S M C o 7 b Q k E J K M v n 8 8 I E z 7 u 7 3 Y h P t S G K 1 L G 2 u J C C X N o k V f g q S z G q 5 h w z 4 x F e k 5 + V y 3 s 4 V S 5 B k B V J W w v 8 E q A f f n Z e 0 a 8 D C X d 5 Q z 4 m g B W 7 A + s J E t 0 0 g p u 7 7 e 6 s s V h 0 J y H c H 6 S + O K z 2 q 1 W 3 l X b M P s s n X E h G R 3 Q l m a J 7 C 3 p F m L F i S i N 4 z E T G s m i b E y u W K b S R 5 r L s W s L Q 9 E h i w 1 z m x V u w D K Y y r n 5 f / 0 j y J z o O 7 s R y 6 m K o r T Z q 1 T A W u c E u O n C E 8 J r e f p h c y r A 1 o u 6 S 9 V o M q 1 t Z 2 d H T K R Q g S Q 3 M q j F z E r s p h y y A P H w Q z I T 0 1 j D M i U B T z l R h C A U i Q 0 X X N T N m u C C z g 9 m V C V v S w m n Y e e V z t J W R y 0 4 5 5 P c y + L 8 2 b Q s 8 Y s S W h Z n F S 3 n s U X U s S g 9 K I s x j j s e c A r I U + y O v t e O + 7 P A t u G 3 O P q V u s k M l M s I U E q W L / 5 S w t 3 4 N r G d Q d l b a A y T H h a v 8 R E V t 9 V A M U L 3 Q E Y y r L j R + f / 4 k f n 6 B f z Z M k J G N i h P D D g u v Z b l b T O R x q H F d n q R I 2 D y r M l B 2 C 4 E p 4 G S 3 Z g a I f i z 9 F g H n A L I m y X L k K L b 5 l E D G O L A 9 7 O A m O L p y p A 7 E I j W n 6 Q j k 9 P q d J F 4 W o 2 1 0 X 1 X P 7 q A i q b 0 v l w f D W F l 3 U d c W K U K E 4 u 2 + k 0 T x e k 1 q I J 6 b 0 I q 3 J 5 C W S A f x T 3 6 1 n k I f I t 8 h E x i x i i y K I I k b J I I Z p b 1 P Z C a F G I a G H R A t G t R b e I p E U S 0 b V F 1 4 h S i 9 o u z S 3 K E Z 1 Y d I L o x q I b R D O L Z o h E w k K U s X 5 C G x w 8 3 d q q p 7 L T J 8 J Q + B t a t m d 9 9 9 D t w K I D R M c W H a 8 q L J n B b w a B P m G S z 1 H z u p U q 2 W 0 T W a H R t O i b b j u m 2 3 7 r L a W L q M Z U M I a g G Z 8 y M 7 K l b i I V T Z t + P Y c W x V 4 9 x 8 2 9 6 O I X r Q x d 3 E r x v I u f I z 7 q 4 i P E p 1 1 8 i v i w i w 9 b m b v 4 G P G k i y e I z 7 r 4 D P F F F 1 / 8 x w J r e T p f W 5 W 4 j x T T i o i A w E + 2 B 9 + b 3 9 b h 4 + Z r 0 i v G m B / R m U X P E D 1 D B R C d W v Q G 0 R t 8 s 0 B 1 m 0 + e J h + Q Z r 1 m N G 4 V 7 R s 6 m v Y N r a r 7 f c M + d k b 7 U j r w r D h e t 9 Z H X d w W 9 b C L 2 z x 7 X W y O E 3 x y j + 5 + Y C 8 P X j 7 e H f 2 w + + S X J 9 t P 9 5 u P 7 w f O l 8 6 W 8 8 g Z O T 8 6 T 5 0 j Z + J c O L 7 z m / O 7 8 4 f z 5 / r f G 1 9 t 7 G x 8 U 7 v e v 9 f E f O H 0 r o 3 h P 6 v E k O 8 = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; ? x,t</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>CURE represents a video segment as a continuous vector-valued function, which maps (x, t, ? x,t ) to a single RGB color. The vector ? x,t is the local feature code associated with the 3 ? 3 region centered at x for the desired frame t.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>&lt;</head><label></label><figDesc>l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " E V t A K f J b i X W / P C v 0 r u l G 9 7 Y X 0 z E = " &gt; A A A M M H i c j Z b N b t t G E M e Z 9 C u x + p G 0 6 K m X h Q 0 D D q C 6 U h o 4 8 a F A b D m x D R i G m l h J k C o 1 l t S S X J j k 0 r t L S z L B Z + i 1 f Y 0 + T X s q e u 1 T d J b k D k n b K U r A 5 v A 3 M / v x n 1 m K b h p x p Q e D P 2 / d / u D D j z 7 + 5 M 7 d l d 6 n n 3 3 + x b 3 7 X 7 5 S I p M e m 3 g i E v K N S x W L e M I m m u u I v U k l o 7 E b s d f u 2 c j 4 X 1 8 w q b h I T v Q y Z e 9 i G i T c 5 x 7 V g C Y b i / 7 y w e m 9 t e H m o L z I Y H N 7 e / v J 4 y d g D L a G W 9 8 / I t a 1 5 t T X + P R + 7 + v p T H h Z z B L t R V S p n 4 a D V L / L q d T c i 1 i x M s 0 U S 6 l 3 R g O W u 0 K c a e q q g l T X O k m l 8 J k y S 6 L R t + c Z j b h e E g i J m O p k 0 l j 5 I t G t T D c C l y u o n J G Y 6 p C o Z e y K 6 F q W w T Y J s i 6 o T I Q O e R J 0 A h P u M V 9 S r x n e E z E 4 t R 2 W + E K S 4 X c P + 4 R p b 7 O T G 3 N P C q N n Y X M t E Y G k a b j s S h A X d + F a J 1 z D Z j 0 C g 8 8 6 A R 7 X r C g j A i m y l M B z W Z / u z s q R u b c o T K D P g 0 x e E c x o o g W s v I q A 1 a + a D k n Y + f l q V 6 M o E J L r E B Z d Q C Q + q p u j i q s C G 1 Y u V 4 d M S H Y l j y V Z D B u K y 1 V o Q U J 6 w U j E t G a S G B + T N 2 w u z i L N p Z g 3 1 Y D M g C U m m N 3 U H Y C y i E p Q 4 3 + F h 6 E 5 I l d 2 I p c z F U Z J u</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3 2 7 i Z Z 6 e N z X F q f 0 i / 3 3 j 1 c H O 4 t T n 8 8 d H a 0 9 3 6 k / q O 8 4 2 z 6 m w 4 Q + e x 8 9 Q 5 c M b O x P E c 7 v z i / O r 8 1 v u 9 9 0 f v r 9 7 f V e j t W 3 X O V 0 7 n 6 v 3 z L y 5 E e k Q = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; (x, y)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Z c 7 2 6 N v t 7 / 5 Y W f j 6 V 7 z S f 3 A + 8 J b 9 5 5 4 I + 8 7 7 6 l 3 6 E 2 8 c y / w I u 9 n 7 x f v 1 8 F v g 9 8 H f w 7 + q k P v 3 2 t y P v N 6 1 + D v f w A 2 i 3 m 3 &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; rgb &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " e W C D Q y c V M M 6 m F K x J 1 m w R / V D p b 7 Q = " &gt; A A A M a X i c j Z b f T 9 x G E M e d 9 F c K t I X 0 p W p f V i A k I l F 6 F 0 X t U 9 X A k Q A S Q l c C S Z R c i t a + t b 3 C 9 p r d N X f G 8 r / S 1 / Z f 6 t / Q f 6 K z t n d s c 9 e q l s D j z 8 z s 7 H 5 3 1 m c 3 j b j S g 8 F f D x 5 + 9 P E n n 3 7 2 6 P O V 1 b U v v v x q f e P x a y U y 6 b F L T 0 R C v n W p Y h F P 2 K X m O m J v U 8 l o 7 E b s j X s 9 M v 4 3 t 0 w q L p I L n a f s Q 0 y D h P v c o x r Q 1 f r j S U x 1 6 P r F v C Q / k 5 3 5 b v 7 k a n 1 r s D e o L r J o D B t j y 2 m u 8 d X G 6 i + T q f C y m C X a i 6 h S 7 4 e D V H 8 o q N T c i 1 i 5 M s k U S 6 l 3 T Q N W u E J c a + q q k t T X N k m l 8 J k y M 6 T R 9 z c Z j b j O C Y R E T P U y a a x 8 k e h O p h u B y x V U T o l Z B V F 5 7 I p o I c t g m w R Z t 1 Q m Q o c 8 C X q B C f e Y L 6 n X D u + J G J z a D k t 8 I c n w h 6 e 7 h G l v r 5 c b c 0 8 K I 2 9 p c y 0 R g a R p m P c l i D u z 4 R o W 7 B E o M O 0 F e V y 3 o w V S Z C k B V O 1 a f 4 F V A e 7 N y z r U 5 0 E m 7 y l n x N E C l m B j Y C G b p n c S d n O z 2 Z c r C o T k O o T 5 l y Y U n 9 X y s P K + 2 I b Z a e u Q C c n u p b I k i 2 F t c T M X L U h I b x m J m N Z M E u N l c s k y 4 y z S X I p Z u z 2 Q G b D E B L N l 7 Q I o i 6 i c l / 8 z P g z N G b q 3 H p l P V R g l z V y n A u Y 4 J S Z O E Z 4 Q W o / T S 5 l X Z 7 J c 0 F 8 q X 5 U r K 9 v b 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>4 3 b 0 + 7 u J 2 U 4 + 6 u K 2 z 3 8 X m O M E n 9 / D + B / a i 8 f r p 3 v D H v W e / P t t 6 f t B 8 f D 9 y v n M 2 n R 1 n 6 P z k P H e O n b F z 6 X j O 3 P n d + c P 5 c / X v t Y 2 1 b 9 a + r U M f P m h y v n Z 6 1 9 r W P y I M i Z k = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; x = (x, y) &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " p D u z R j e d E F 6 0 p N s 4 l n A N 6 Z 9 P O 2 Y = " &gt; A A A M V n i c j Z Z R b 9 x E E M f d Q m m 5 B E j h k Z d V o k h F C u G u q u A J 0 e T S J p G i 6 J o m b V W u j d a + t b 2 K 7 X V 2 1 7 l z L H 8 C X u G 7 w Z d B z N r e s Z 0 7 E J Y S j 3 8 z s 7 P 7 3 1 m f 3 T T i S g + H f 9 2 7 / 8 m n D z 5 7 + O j z w d r 6 F 1 9 + t f H 4 6 z d K Z N J j F 5 6 I h H z n U s U i n r A L z X X E 3 q W S 0 d i N 2 F v 3 a m z 8 b 2 + Y V F w k 5 z p P 2 Y e Y B g n 3 u U c 1 o F f 6 c m N r u D u s L r J s j B p j y 2 m u y e X j t V + m M + F l M U u 0 F 1 G l f h 0 N U / 2 h o F J z L 2 L l Y J o p l l L v i g a s c I W 4 0 t R V J a m v b Z J K 4 T N l p k O j 7 6 8 z G n G d E w i J m O p l 0 l j 5</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Q h 8 c P N 3 6 q q e y 0 y f C U P g b W r Z n Y / c w 7 M C i A 0 T H F h 2 v 2 l g y h 9 8 M A n 3 C J F + g 5 n U r V b L b J r J C o y v v u 2 4 7 r t t + 6 y 2 V C 6 n G U m B D 0 p z P m L H s V j e Z i i Z N v 5 5 D i 2 K v n u P i X n f x 6 1 a G L m 6 l e N n F L x E f d f E R 4 t M u P k V 8 2 M W H r c x d f I x 4 0 s U T x G d d f I b 4 o o s v / m O C t T y d r 6 1 K 3 C e K a U W E T + A n 2 4 X v y e / q 9 H G d 6 7 r F G O s j O r P o B a I X q A C i U 4 v e I 3 q P b x b Y 3 e a T p 6 k H p J m v s c a t o n 1 H R 9 O + o 1 V 1 v + / Y x 8 5 o X 0 o H r h X H 7 e 7 1 U R e 3 m 3 r Y x W 2 d v S 4 2 x w k + u U d 3 P 7 C X j T d P d 0 c / 7 j 5 7 9 W z r + X 7 z 8 f 3 I + d b Z d J 4 4 I + c n 5 7 l z 5 E y c C 8 d z m P O b 8 7 v z x 9 q f a 3 + v P 1 h / W I f e v 9 f k f O P 0 r v W N f w D 7 p o Q I &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; t t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 1 6 O G a 7 r 2 g a B h C B Q y K b t E z Y J c 1 J g = " &gt; A A A M W H i c j Z b f b 9 s 2 E M f V 7 k f b J N v a 7 n E v R I I A H Z B l d l F s T 8 O a O G 0 S I A i 8 N G m L z l 1 A y Z R E R B I V k o r t C P o T 9 r r 9 b d t f s 6 M k n q j Y G y Y g 0 e l z d z z y y 6 M s P 0 + 4 0 o P B X / f u f / L p Z 5 8 / e P h o b X 3 j i y + / e v z k 6 V s l C h m w i 0 A k Q r 7 3 q W I J z 9 i F 5 j p h 7 3 P J a O o n 7 J 1 / N T L + d z d M K i 6 y c 7 3 I 2 c e U R h k P e U A 1 o D f H l / r y 8 d Z g d 1 B f Z N k Y t s a W 1 1 7 j y y f r P 0 + m I i h S l u k g o U r 9 O h z k + m N J p e Z B w q q 1 S a F Y T o M r G r H S F + J K U 1 9 V p L m 2 S S 5 F y J S Z E E 2 + u y 5 o w v W C Q E j C V C + T p i o U m X Y y / Q R c v q B y S l K q Y 6 I W q S + S p S y D b R J k 3 V C Z C R 3 z L O o F Z j x g o a R B N 3 w g U n B q O y w J h S T D 7 5 / v E K a D 3 V 5 u y g M p j J q V z b V E R J L m 8 a I v Q e r M h m t Y c E C g w L Q X F H D d j R Z J U e Q E U L 1 J / Q X W B X g w r 5 r Q k E e F v K O c E U c L W I K N g Y V s m l b J 2 P X 1 Z l + u J B K S 6 x j m X 5 l Q f F a r w 6 q 7 Y h t m p 6 1 j J i S 7 k 8 q y I o W 1 p e 1 c t C A x v W E k Y V o z S Y y X y R X L T I t E c y l m 3 f Z A Z s Q y E 8 x W t Q u g I q F y X v 3 P + D g 2 R + b O e u R i q u I k a + c 6 F T D H K T F x i v C M 0 G a c X s q 8 P o L V k v 5 S h a p a W 9 v e 3 i Z j K U Q I x a 0 8 e p G w M k 8 o h z p w H I x B f m o b Y 4 d M W c g z b g Q B K E V K s 7 V J x m Z t c g m n J x e q 9 l f l 2 H n o R X W D V O V B Z / d i 2 n t V n r d G z 5 u w N K V V e V L f e p 5 A S J G A 0 o u q H K H Z i 4 B X Q p H m T f W 9 z u 6 P A s u G 2 q P 6 1 u g k c r N Z Q o J U M H / z l 5 W T n Y l t 3 M l O 1 T i o j F I O L i O z y J u 7 C m H z o s k O O K r K i a P z f 4 m j c 4 x L e L o U B A z 8 s D 1 g c N 3 E r S r a 1 C N t w I p q T a E 2 Q B X 5 U g A w n A n P w i U / M P T D 5 s / R Y R 5 w C S L q p i 4 i i 2 + Z R A y 2 x S H v R g H b 4 q k K E U + g E S 0 / y E a n p 1 T p s p x o N t d l / V z 9 N g F U t V s X w P H V F F 7 W T c a J U a I 8 u e y G 0 z x b k E a L N q X 3 I q y 3 y 0 + h A v y j u F 7 f I h 9 R Y F G A i F n E E M U W x Y i U R Q r R 3 K K u F y K L I k Q L i x a I b i 2 6 R S Q t k o i u L b p G l F n U d W l h U Y H o x K I T R D c W 3 S C a W T R D J F I W o Y z N E / r g 4 O n O V z 9 V T p 8 I Q + F v Y N m e j d 3 D s A O L D h A d W 3 S 8 a m P J D H 4 z C P Q J k 3 y O m j e t V M t u m 8 g K j a 5 F 3 3 X r u G 7 7 r b d U L q Y a S 4 E N S T M + Z c a y W 9 1 m K p q 1 / X o O L Y q 9 e o 6 L e + P i N 5 0 M L u 6 k e O 3 i 1 4 i P X H y E + N T F p 4 g P X X z Y y e z i Y 8 R j F 4 8 R n 7 n 4 D P G F i y / + Y 4 K N P M 7 X V i 3 u M 8 W 0 I i I k 8 J P t w x f l t 0 3 6 q M n 1 / X K E 9 R G d W f Q K 0 S t U A N G p R R 8 Q f c A 3 C + x u + 8 n T 1 g P S z t d Y o 0 7 R v s P R t O / o V N 3 v O / a x M 7 q X 0 o F v x f H d v T 5 y c b e p h y 7 u 6 u y 5 2 B w n + O Q e 3 v 3 A X j b e P t 8 d / r D 7 4 p c X W y / 3 2 4 / v h 9 4 3 3 q b 3 z B t 6 P 3 o v v S N v 7 F 1 4 g R d 5 v 3 t / e H + u / 7 3 h b T z Y e N S E 3 r / X 5 n z t 9 a 6 N p / 8 A D b q D x Q = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>U h v 7 d 8 7 x s f 8 + z r W X x V z p w e C v e / f f e / + D D z 9 6 8 P H a + s Y n n z 7 c f P T Z K y V y 6 b N L X 8 R C v v G o Y j F P 2 a X m O m Z v M s l o 4 s X s t X c 9 M v b X U y Y V F + m F X m T s X U L D l A f c p x r Q 1 e a m m 1 A d + T Q u f i 6 v 3 E z x q 8 3 t w d 6 g e s h y Y 9 g 0 t p 3 m G V 8 9 W v / J n Q g / T 1 i q / Z g q 9 e t w k O l 3 B Z W a + z E r 1 9 x c s Y z 6 1 z R k h S f E t a a e K k n 9 7 J B M i o A p M z 8 a f 3 u T 0 5 j r B Q G X m K l e J E 1 U I F L d i f R i M H m C y g k x a y B q k X g i X o o y 2 A Z B 1 J T K V O i I p 2 H P M e U + C y T 1 2 + F 9 k Y B R 2 2 F J I C Q Z f v d k l z D t 7 / V i E + 5 L Y c Q t b a w l I p Q 0 i x Z 9 C Z L O b L i G B f s E E k x 6 T j 7 X 7 W i h F H l G A F V 7 1 l 9 g l Y D 7 8 7 J 2 D X i Y y z v K G X G 0 g C V Y H 1 j I l q m c l N 3 c b P X l i k M h u Y 5 g / q V x x b 5 a 7 V b e F d s w O 2 0 d M S H Z n V C W 5 g m s L W n m o g W J 6 J S R m G n N J D F W J l c s M 8 l j z a W Y t d s D k S F L j T N b V S 6 A 8 p j K e f k / / a P I n K A 7 6 5 G L i Y r i t J n r R M A c J 8 T 4 K c J T Q u t x e i H z 6 k S W S / p L F a h y b W 1 n Z 4 e M p R A B J L f y 6 E X M i i y m H P L A c T A N 8 m N T G L t k w g K e c i M I Q C k S m q 6 5 K Z s 1 w Q W c n k y o y l 4 W 4 0 6 n 5 9 U O U h a H b b v n 0 7 z L 4 q J p 9 K w x S x J a F q f V q 2 f x h R Q x K L 0 o i x E 2 e x 7 w S c i T r M 6 + 3 7 b 7 o 8 C y I f e o e t U 6 i c x s l p A g F c z f / K W F u + v a w n V 3 y 9 p A Z Z h w M B m Z R V a / V Q C b F 7 q 7 Y C j L j h + d / 4 s f n a N f z J M l J 2 B g h + 2 B B t e 1 3 6</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a 6 h z Y 4 e L q 1 V b 2 y U y f C U P g b W L Z v f f f R 7 d C i Q 0 Q n F p 2 s 2 l g y g 9 8 M A n X C J J + j 5 n U p V b L b I r J C o 2 n R N 9 1 2 T L f 9 0 l t K F 1 G N q a A N Q T M + Y a Z l t 7 q J V D R t 6 v U C S h R r 9 Q I X 9 7 K L X 7 Y y d H E r x Y s u f o H 4 u I u P E Z 9 1 8 R n i o y 4 + a m X u 4 h P E 4 y 4 e I z 7 v 4 n P E l 1 1 8 + R 8 T r O X p 3 L Y q c R 8 r p h U R A Y G f b A 8 u m N / U 4 a M 6 1 v O K E e Z H d G 7 R c 0 T P U Q F E Z x a 9 R f Q W v y y w u 8 2 V p 8 l n r q 4 F X m J H r a J 9 Q 0 f T v q F V 9 a B v O M D K a D 9 K h 5 4 V x + v u 9 X E X t 5 t 6 1 M V t n v 0 u N s c J r t z D u x f s 5 c a r J 3 v D 7 / e e / v J 0 + 9 l B c / l + 4 H z l b D m P n a H z g / P M O X b G z q X j O 1 P n d + c P 5 8 / 1 v z c e b n y x 8 W X t e v 9 e E / O 5 0 3 s 2 v v 4 H 4 K a J 3 g = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; M &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 1 m f d 8 b p J 5 5 w F w F + + T X k M 4 g z a 1 M M = " &gt; A A A M Y X i c j Z b f b 9 s 2 E M f V 7 l e b Z F v a P f a F S B C g A 7 z M L o r 1 q V g T p 0 0 C B I G X J m 3 R q Q s o m Z K I S K J C U r E d Q f / G X r d / a 8 / 7 R 3 a U x J M U e 8 M E J D p 9 7 o 5 H f n m U 5 W U x V 3 o 4 / O v e / c 8 + / + L L r x 4 8 X F v f + P q b b z c f P X 6 n R C 5 9 d u G L W M g P H l U s 5 i m 7 0 F z H 7 E M m G U 2 8 m L 3 3 r s b G / / 6 G S c V F e q 4 X G f u U 0 D D l A f e p B u S 6 x f H l c E C O L 0 d u e b m 5 P d w d V h d Z N k a N s e 0 0 1 + T y 0 f r P 7 l T 4 e c J S 7 c d U q V 9 H w 0 x / K q j U 3 I 9 Z u e b m i m X U v 6 I h K z w h r j T 1 V E n q a 4 d k U g R M m Z n R + I f r n M Z c L w i E x E z 1 M m m i A p H q T q Y X g 8 s T V E 5 J Q n V E 1 C L x R L y U Z b B N g q w b K l O h I 5 6 G v c C U + y y Q 1 G + H 9 0 U C T m 2 H J Y G Q Z P T j s w F h 2 t / t 5 S b c l 8 L I W t p c S 0 Q o a R Y t + h I k n d l w D Q v 2 C R S Y 9 o J 8 r t v R Q i n y j A C q d q u / w K o A 9 + d l H R r w M J d 3 l D P i a A F L s D G w k C 3 T M y m 7 v t 7 q y x W H Q n I d w f x L E 4 r P a n V Y e V d s w + y 0 d c S E Z H d S W Z o n s L a k m Y s W J K I 3 j M R M a y a J 8 T K 5 Y p l J H m s u x a z d H s g M W W q C 2 a p 2 A Z T H V M 7 L / x k f R e b s 3 F m P X E x V F K f N X K c C 5 j g l J k 4 R n h J a j 9 N L m V d n s V z S X 6 p A l W t r O z s 7 Z C K F C K C 4 l U c v Y l Z k M e V Q B 4 6 D M c j L p j E G Z M o C n n I j C E A p E p q u u S m b N c k F n J 5 M q M p f F p P O Q y + q H a Q s D l q 7 F 9 P c y + K 8 M X r e m C U J L Y u T 6 t b z + E K K G J R e l M U Y z V 4 E v B L y J K u r 7 7 V 2 f x R Y N t Q e V 7 d a J 5 G Z z R I S p I L 5 m 7+ 0 c A e u b V x 3 U N Y O K s O E g 8 v I L L L 6 r g L Y v N A d g K M s O 3 F 0 / i 9 x d I 5 x M U + W g o C B H 7 Y H D K 7 r u F V F 6 3 q k C V h R r S 7 U B K g 8 W w o A h j P h a b D k B 4 Z + 2 P w 5 O s w D L k G E 7 d R F a P E t k 4 j B t j j g 7 S h g W z x V A W I X G t H y g 3 R 8 e k q V L g p X s 7 k u q u f y N x d Q 2 W y d D 8 d X U 3 h Z 1 x k n R o n i 5 L I d T v N 0 Q W o t m p T e i 7 D a L i + B C v C P 4 n o 9 i z x E v k U + I m Y R Q x R Z F C F S F i l E c 4 v a X g g t C h E t L F o g u r X o F p G 0 S C K 6 t u g a U W p R 2 6 W 5 R T m i E 4 t O E N 1 Y d I N o Z t E M k U h Y i D L W T + i D g 6 d b X / V U d v p E G A p / Q 8 v 2 b O w e h h 1 Y d I D o 2 K L j V R t L Z v C b Q a B P m O R z 1 L x u p U p 2 2 0 R W a H Q t + q 7 b j u u 2 3 3 p L 5 S K q s R T Y k D T j U 2 Y s u 9 V N p q J p 0 6 / n 0 K L Y q + e 4 u L d d / L a V o Y t b K d 5 0 8 R v E R 1 1 8 h P i 0 i 0 8 R H 3 b x Y S t z F x 8 j n n T x B P F Z F 5 8 h v u j i i / + Y Y C 1 P 5 2 u r E v e p Y l o R E R D4 y f b g 0 / L 7 O n 1 c 5 3 p e M c b 6 i M 4 s e o 3 o N S q A 6 N S i j 4 g + 4 p s F d r f 5 5 G n q A W n m a 6 x x q 2 j f 0 d G 0 7 2 h V 3 e 8 7 9 r E z 2 p f S g W f F 8 b p 7 f d T F 7 a Y e d n F b Z 6 + L z X G C T + 7 R 3 Q / s Z e P d s 9 3 R T 7 v P f 3 m + / W q / + f h + 4 D x x t p y n z s h 5 4 b x y j p y J c + H 4 T u b 8 7 v z h / L n + 9 8 b D j c 2 N x 3 X o / X t N z n d O 7 9 p 4 8 g 9 1 S 4 a w &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; {I 0 , I 1 } &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " E o w w j j d P e k 9 T Q v 0 z M 8 r a Q v Y d l v Y = " &gt; A A A M W H i c j Z b f b 9 s 2 E M f V 7 k f b J N v a 7 n E v R I I A H Z B l d l F s T 8 O a O G 0 S I A i 8 N G m L z l 1 A y Z R E R B I V k o r t C P o T 9 r r 9 b d t f s 6 M k n q j Y G y Y g 0 e l z d z z y y 6 M s P 0 + 4 0 o P B X / f u f / L p Z 5 8 / e P h o b X 3 j i y + / e v z k 6 V s l C h m w i 0 A k Q r 7 3 q W I J z 9 i F 5 j p h 7 3 P J a O o n 7 J 1 / N T L + d z d M K i 6 y c 7 3 I 2 c e U R h k P e U A 1 o D f H l 4 P L x 1 u D 3 U F 9 k W V j 2 B p b X n u N L 5 + s / z y Z i q B I W a a D h C r 1 6 3 C Q 6 4 8 l l Z o H C a v W J o V i O Q 2 u a M R K X 4 g r T X 1 V k e b a J r k U I V N m Q j T 5 7 r q g C d c L A i E J U 7 1 M m q p Q Z N r J 9 B N w + Y L K K U m p j o l a p L 5 I l r I M t k m Q d U N l J n T M s 6 g X m P G A h Z I G 3 f C B S M G p 7 b A k F J I M v 3 + + Q 5 g O d n u 5 K Q + k M G p W N t c S E U m a x 4 u + B K k z G 6 5 h w Q G B A t N e U M B 1 N 1 o k R Z E T Q P U m 9 R d Y F + D B v G p C Q x 4 V 8 o 5 y R h w t Y A k 2 B h a y a V o l Y 9 f X m 3 2 5 k k h I r m O Y f 2 V C 8 V m t D q v u i m 2 Y n b a O m Z D s T i r L i h T W l r Z z 0 Y L E 9 I a R h G n N J D F e J l c s M y 0 S z a W Y d d s D m R H L T D B b 1 S 6 A i o T K e f U / 4 + P Y H J k 7 6 5 G L q Y q T r J 3 r V M A c p 8 T E K c I z Q p t x e i n z + g h W S / p L F a p q b W 1 7 e 5 u M p R A h F L f y 6 E X C y j y h H O r A c T A G + a l t j B 0 y Z S H P u B E E o B Q p z d Y m G Z u 1 y S W c n l y o 2 l + V Y + e h F 9 U N U p U H n d 2 L a e 9 V e d 4 a P W / C 0 p R W 5 U l 9 6 3 k C I U U C S i + q c o R m L w J e C U W a N 9 X 3 O r s / C i w b a o / q W 6 O T y M 1 m C Q l S w f z N X 1 Z O d i a 2 c S c 7 V e O g M k o 5 u I z M I m / u K o T N i y Y 7 4 K g q J 4 7 O / y W O z j E u 4 e l S E D D w w / a A w X U T t 6 p o U 4 + 0 A S u q N Y X a A F X k S w H A c C Y 8 C 5 f 8 w N A P m z 9 H h 3 n A J Y i o m 7 q I L L 5 l E j H Y F o e 8 G w V s i 6 c q R D y B R r T 8 I B u d n l K l y 3 K i 2 V y X 9 X P 1 2 w R Q 1 W 5 d A M d X U 3 h Z N x k n R o n y 5 L I b T v N s Q R o t 2 p T e i 7 D e L j + F C v C P 4 n p 9 i 3 x E g U U B I m Y R Q x R b F C N S F i l E c 4 u 6 X o g s i h A t L F o g u r X o F p G 0 S C K 6 t u g a U W Z R 1 6 W F R Q W i E 4 t O E N 1 Y d I N o Z t E M k U h Z h D I 2 T + i D g 6 c 7 X / 1 U O X 0 i D I W / g W V 7 N n Y P w w 4 s O k B 0 b N H x q o 0 l M / j N I N A n T P I 5 a t 6 0 U i 2 7 b S I r N L o W f d e t 4 7 r t t 9 5 S u Z h q L A U 2 J M 3 4 l B n L b n W b q W j W 9 u s 5 t C j 2 6 j k u 7 o 2 L 3 3 Q y u L i T 4 r W L X y M + c v E R 4 l M X n y I + d P F h J 7 O L j x G P X T x G f O b i M 8 Q X L r 7 4 j w k 2 8 j h f W 7 W 4 z x T T i o i Q w E + 2 D 1 + U 3 z b p o y b X 9 8 s R 1 k d 0 Z t E r R K 9 Q A U S n F n 1 A 9 A H f L L C 7 7 S d P W w 9 I O 1 9 j j T p F + w 5 H 0 7 6 j U 3 W / 7 9 j H z u h e S g e + F c d 3 9 / r I x d 2 m H r q 4 q 7 P n Y n O c 4 J N 7 e P c D e 9 l 4 + 3 x 3 + M P u i 1 9 e b L 3 c b z + + H 3 r f e J v e M 2 / o / e i 9 9 I 6 8 s X f h B V 7 k / e 7 9 4 f 2 5 / v e G t / F g 4 1 E T e v 9 e m / O 1 1 7 s 2 n v 4 D 4 T a D g Q = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; I 0 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " 5 J B 6 b x s t 8 j C R 7 m Y 7 8 r b 9 4 q v H G W c = " &gt; A A A M W H i c j Z b f b 9 s 2 E M f V 7 k f b J N v a 7 n E v R I I A H Z B l d l F s T 8 O a O G 0 S I A i 8 N G m L z l 1 A y Z R E R B I V k o r t C P o T 9 r r 9 b d t f s 6 M k n q j Y G y Y g 0 e l z d z z y y 6 M s P 0 + 4 0 o P B X / f u f / L p Z 5 8 / e P h o b X 3 j i y + / e v z k 6 V s l C h m w i 0 A k Q r 7 3 q W I J z 9 i F 5 j p h 7 3 P J a O o n 7 J 1 / N T L + d z d M K i 6 y c 7 3 I 2 c e U R h k P e U A 1 o D f H l 8 P L x 1 u D 3 U F 9 k W V j 2 B p b X n u N L 5 + s / z y Z i q B I W a a D h C r 1 6 3 C Q 6 4 8 l l Z o H C a v W J o V i O Q 2 u a M R K X 4 g r T X 1 V k e b a J r k U I V N m Q j T 5 7 r q g C d c L A i E J U 7 1 M m q p Q Z N r J 9 B N w + Y L K K U m p j o l a p L 5 I l r I M t k m Q d U N l J n T M s 6 g X m P G A h Z I G 3 f C B S M G p 7 b A k F J I M v 3 + + Q 5 g O d n u 5 K Q + k M G p W N t c S E U m a x 4 u + B K k z G 6 5 h w Q G B A t N e U M B 1 N 1 o k R Z E T Q P U m 9 R d Y F + D B v G p C Q x 4 V 8 o 5 y R h w t Y A k 2 B h a y a V o l Y 9 f X m 3 2 5 k k h I r m O Y f 2 V C 8 V m t D q v u i m 2 Y n b a O m Z D s T i r L i h T W l r Z z 0 Y L E 9 I a R h G n N J D F e J l c s M y 0 S z a W Y d d s D m R H L T D B b 1 S 6 A i o T K e f U / 4 + P Y H J k 7 6 5 G L q Y q T r J 3 r V M A c p 8 T E K c I z Q p t x e i n z + g h W S / p L F a p q b W 1 7 e 5 u M p R A h F L f y 6 E X C y j y h H O r A c T A G + a l t j B 0 y Z S H P u B E E o B Q p z d Y m G Z u 1 y S W c n l y o 2 l + V Y + e h F 9 U N U p U H n d 2 L a e 9 V e d 4 a P W / C 0 p R W 5 U l 9 6 3 k C I U U C S i + q c o R m L w J e C U W a N 9 X 3 O r s / C i w b a o / q W 6 O T y M 1 m C Q l S w f z N X 1 Z O d i a 2 c S c 7 V e O g M k o 5 u I z M I m / u K o T N i y Y 7 4 K g q J 4 7 O / y W O z j E u 4 e l S E D D w w / a A w X U T t 6 p o U 4 + 0 A S u q N Y X a A F X k S w H A c C Y 8 C 5 f 8 w N A P m z 9 H h 3 n A J Y i o m 7 q I L L 5 l E j H Y F o e 8 G w V s i 6 c q R D y B R r T 8 I B u d n l K l y 3 K i 2 V y X 9 X P 1 2 w R Q 1 W 5 d A M d X U 3 h Z N x k n R o n y 5 L I b T v N s Q R o t 2 p T e i 7 D e L j + F C v C P 4 n p 9 i 3 x E g U U B I m Y R Q x R b F C N S F i l E c 4 u 6 X o g s i h A t L F o g u r X o F p G 0 S C K 6 t u g a U W Z R 1 6 W F R Q W i E 4 t O E N 1 Y d I N o Z t E M k U h Z h D I 2 T + i D g 6 c 7 X / 1 U O X 0 i D I W / g W V 7 N n Y P w w 4 s O k B 0 b N H x q o 0 l M / j N I N A n T P I 5 a t 6 0 U i 2 7 b S I r N L o W f d e t 4 7 r t t 9 5 S u Z h q L A U 2 J M 3 4 l B n L b n W b q W j W 9 u s 5 t C j 2 6 j k u 7 o 2 L 3 3 Q y u L i T 4 r W L X y M + c v E R 4 l M X n y I + d P F h J 7 O L j x G P X T x G f O b i M 8 Q X L r 7 4 j w k 2 8 j h f W 7 W 4 z x T T i o i Q w E + 2 D 1 + U 3 z b p o y b X 9 8 s R 1 k d 0 Z t E r R K 9 Q A U S n F n 1 A 9 A H f L L C 7 7 S d P W w 9 I O 1 9 j j T p F + w 5 H 0 7 6 j U 3 W / 7 9 j H z u h e S g e + F c d 3 9 / r I x d 2 m H r q 4 q 7 P n Y n O c 4 J N 7 e P c D e 9 l 4 + 3 x 3 + M P u i 1 9 e b L 3 c b z + + H 3 r f e J v e M 2 / o / e i 9 9 I 6 8 s X f h B V 7 k / e 7 9 4 f 2 5 / v e G t / F g 4 1 E T e v 9 e m / O 1 1 7 s 2 n v 4 D 7 S i D g g = = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>I 1 &lt;Figure 3 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " J Q L z L m Z q 9 n V r d 1 Z F y y + O h H H x r 4 w = " &gt; A A A M a 3 i c j Z b d b t x E F M f d 8 l W S A C n l C r g Y J Y p U p B B 2 q w q u E E 0 2 b R I p i p Y 0 a a v W J R p 7 x / Y o t s e Z G W c / L L 8 L t / B G P A T v w B n b c 2 x n F 4 S l x M e / c 8 6 c m f + c 8 d r L Y q 7 0 Y P D X v f s f f P j R x 5 8 8 + H R t f e O z z 7 / Y f P j l K y V y 6 b N L X 8 R C v v G o Y j F P 2 a X m O m Z v M s l o 4 s X s t X c 9 M v 7 X t 0 w q L t I L P c / Y + 4 S G K Q + 4 T z W g q 8 2 v 3 C z i V 8 X A l T y M N J V S T I f l 1 e b 2 Y G 9 Q X W T Z G D b G t t N c 4 6 u H 6 7 + 4 E + H n C U u 1 H 1 O l 3 g 0 H m X 5 f U K m 5 H 7 N y z c 0 V y 6 h / T U N W e E J c a + q p k t T X D s m k C J g y c 6 T x 9 z c 5 j b m e E w i J m e p l 0 k Q F I t W d T C 8 G l y e o n J C E 6 o i o e e K J e C n L Y J s E W b d U p k J H P A 1 7 g S n 3 W S C p 3 w 7 v i w S c 2 g 5 L A i H J 8 I c n u 4 R p f 6 + X m 3 B f C i N w a X M t E a G k W T T v S 5 B 0 Z s M 1 L N g n U G D S C / K 5 b k c L p c g z A q j a t / 4 C q w L c n 5 V 1 a M D D X N 5 R z o i j B S z B x s B C t k z 3 p O z m Z q s v V x w K y X U E 8 y 9 N K D 6 r 1 W H l X b E N s 9 P W E R O S 3 U l l a Z 7 A 2 p J m L l q Q i N 4 y E j O t m S T G y + S K Z S Z 5 r D n 0 Z 7 s 9 k B m y 1 A S z V e 0 C K I + p n J X / M z 6 K z C m 6 s x 4 5 n 6 g o T p u 5 T g T M c U J M n C I 8 J b Q e p 5 c y q 0 5 l u a S / V I E q 1 9 Z 2 d n b I W A o R Q H E r j 5 7 H r M h i y q E O H A d j k J + b x t g l E x b w l B t B A E q R 0 H T N T d m 0 S S 7 g 9 G R C V f 6 y G H c e e l H t I G V x 2 N q 9 m O Z e F h e N 0 f P G L E l o W Z x W t 5 7 H F 1 L E o P S 8 L E Z o 9 i L g l Z A n W V 1 9 v 7 X 7 o 8 C y o f a o u t U 6 i c x s l p A g F c z f / K W F u + v a x n V 3 y 9 p B Z Z h w c B m Z R V b f V Q C b F 7 q 7 4 C j L T h y d / U s c n W F c z J O l I G D g h + 0 B g + s 6 b l X R u h 5 p A l Z U q w s 1 A S r P l g K A 4 U x 4 G i z 5 g a E f N n + G D v O A S x B h O 3 U R W r x g E j H Y F g e 8 H Q V s i y c q Q O x C I 1 p + m I 7 O z q j S R e F q N t N F 9 V z + 5 g I q m 6 3 z 4 f h q C i / r O u P U K F G c X r X D a Z 7 O S a 1 F k 9 J 7 E V b b 5 S V Q A f 5 R X K 9 n k Y f I t 8 h H x C x i i C K L I k T K I o V o Z l H b C 6 F F I a K 5 R X N E C 4 s W i K R F E t G N R T e I U o v a L s 0 t y h G d W n S K 6 N a i W 0 R T i 6 a I R M J C l L F + Q h 8 c P N 3 6 q q e y 0 y f C U P g b W L Z v Y / c x 7 N C i Q 0 Q n F p 2 s 2 l g y h d 8 M A n 3 C J J + h 5 n U r V b L b J r J C o 2 v e d y 0 6 r k W / 9 Z b K R V R j K b A h a c o n z F h 2 q 5 t M R d O m X y + g R b F X L 3 B x L 7 v 4 Z S t D F 7 d S v O j i F 4 i P u / g Y 8 V k X n y E + 6 u K j V u Y u P k E 8 7 u I x 4 v M u P k d 8 2 c W X / z H B W p 7 O 1 1 Y l 7 m P F t C I i I P C T 7 c F H 5 n d 1 + q j O 9 b x i h P U R n V v 0 H N F z V A D R m U V v E b 3 F N w v s b v P J 0 9 Q D 0 s z X W K N W 0 b 6 j o 2 n f 0 a p 6 0 H c c Y G e 0 L 6 V D z 4 r j d f f 6 u I v b T T 3 q 4 r b O f h e b 4 w S f 3 M O 7 H 9 j L x q s n e 8 M f 9 5 7 + + n T 7 2 U H z 8 f 3 A + c b Z c h 4 7 Q + c n 5 5 l z 7 I y d S 8 d 3 F s 7 v z h / O n + t / b z z a + H r j 2 z r 0 / r 0 m 5 5 H T u z Z 2 / g F G H I t + &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; 0!1 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " f x n d N Ij N N A m H t Q H E F S R w a H + S 1 Q Y = " &gt; A A A M a 3 i c j Z b d b t x E F M f d 8 l W S A C n l C r g Y J Y p U p B B 2 q w q u E E 0 2 b R I p i p Y 0 a a v W J R p 7 x / Y o t s e Z G W c / L L 8 L t / B G P A T v w B n b c 2 x n F 4 S l x M e / c 8 6 c m f + c 8 d r L Y q 7 0 Y P D X v f s f f P j R x 5 8 8 + H R t f e O z z 7 / Y f P j l K y V y 6 b N L X 8 R C v v G o Y j F P 2 a X m O m Z v M s l o 4 s X s t X c 9 M v 7 X t 0 w q L t I L P c / Y + 4 S G K Q + 4 T z W g q 8 2 v 3 C z i V 8 X Q l T y M N J V S T A f l 1 e b 2 Y G 9 Q X W T Z G D b G t t Nc 4 6 u H 6 7 + 4 E + H n C U u 1 H 1 O l 3 g 0 H m X 5 f U K m 5 H 7 N y z c 0 V y 6 h / T U N W e E J c a + q p k t T X D s m k C J g y c 6 T x 9 z c 5 j b m e E w i J m e p l 0 k Q F I t W d T C 8 G l y e o n J C E 6 o i o e e K J e C n L Y J s E W b d U p k J H P A 1 7 g S n 3 W S C p 3 w 7 v i w S c 2 g 5 L A i H J 8 I c n u 4 R p f 6 + X m 3 B f C i N w a X M t E a G k W T T v S 5 B 0 Z s M 1 L N g n U G D S C / K 5 b k c L p c g z A q j a t / 4 C q w L c n 5 V 1 a M D D X N 5 R z o i j B S z B x s B C t k z 3 p O z m Z q s v V x w K y X U E 8 y 9 N K D 6 r 1 W H l X b E N s 9 P W E R O S 3 U l l a Z 7 A 2 p J m L l q Q i N 4 y E j O t m S T G y + S K Z S Z 5 r D n 0 Z 7 s 9 k B m y 1 A S z V e 0 C K I + p n J X / M z 6 K z C m 6 s x 4 5 n 6 g o T p u 5 T g T M c U J M n C I 8 J b Q e p 5 c y q 0 5 l u a S / V I E q 1 9 Z 2 d nb I W A o R Q H E r j 5 7 H r M h i y q E O H A d j k J + b x t g l E x b w l B t B A E q R 0 H T N T d m 0 S S 7 g 9 G R C V f 6 y G H c e e l H t I G V x 2 N q 9 m O Z e F h e N 0 f P G L E l o W Z x W t 5 7 H F 1 L E o P S 8 L E Z o 9 i L g l Z A n W V 1 9 v 7 X 7 o 8 C y o f a o u t U 6 i c x s l p A g F c z f / K W F u + v a x n V 3 y 9 p B Z Z h w c B m Z R V b f V Q C b F 7 q 7 4 C j L T h y d / U s c n W F c z J O l I G D g h + 0 B g + s 6 b l X R u h 5 p A l Z U q w s 1 A S r P l g K A 4 U x 4 G i z 5 g a E f N n + G D v O A S x B h O 3 U R W r x g E j H Y F g e 8 H Q V s i y c q Q O x C I 1 p + m I 7 O z q j S R e F q N t N F 9 V z + 5 g I q m 6 3 z 4 f h q C i / r O u P U K F G c X r X D a Z 7 O S a 1 F k 9 J 7 E V b b 5 S V Q A f 5 R X K 9 n k Y f I t 8 h H x C x i i C K L I k T K I o V o Z l H b C 6 F F I a K 5 R X N E C 4 s W i K R F E t G N R T e I Uo v a L s 0 t y h G d W n S K 6 N a i W 0 R T i 6 a I R M J C l L F + Q h 8 c P N 3 6 q q e y 0 y f C U P g b W L Z v Y / c x 7 N C i Q 0 Q n F p 2 s 2 l g y h d 8 M A n 3 C J J + h 5 n U r V b L b J r J C o 2 v e d y 0 6 r k W / 9 Z b K R V R j K b A h a c o n z F h 2 q 5 t M R d O m X y + g R b F X L 3 B x L 7 v 4 Z S t D F 7 d S v O j i F 4 i P u / g Y 8 V k X n y E + 6 u K j V u Y u P k E 8 7 u I x 4 v M u P k d 8 2 c W X / z H B W p 7 O 1 1 Y l 7 m P F t C I i I P C T 7 c F H 5 n d 1 + q j O 9 b x i h P U R n V v 0 H N F z V A D R m U V v E b 3 F N w v s b v P J 0 9 Q D 0 s z X W K N W 0 b 6 j o 2 n f 0 a p 6 0 H c c Y G e 0 L 6 V D z 4 r j d f f 6 u I v b T T 3 q 4 r b O f h e b 4 w S f 3 M O 7 H 9 j L x q s n e 8 M f 9 5 7 + + n T 7 2 U H z 8 f 3 A + c b Z c h 4 7 Q + c n 5 5 l z 7 I y d S 8 d 3 F s 7 v z h / O n + t / b z z a + H r j 2 z r 0 / r 0 m 5 5 H T u z Z 2 / g F G K I t + &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; 1!0 &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " E e g + a H I B Y o m 4 7 / B N 2 n Q g w P Y y G 5 I = " &gt; A A A M a X i c j Z b f T 9 x G E M e d 9 F c K t I X 0 p W p f V i C k V K L 0 L o r a p 6 q B I w E k h K 4 E k i h 1 e l r 7 1 v Y K 2 2 t 2 1 9 w d l v + V v r b / U v + G / h O d t b 1 j m 7 t W t Q R e f 2 Z m Z / c 7 s z 5 7 W c y V H g z + e v D w g w 8 / + v i T R 5 + u r W 9 8 9 v k X m 1 u P X y u R S 5 9 d + S I W 8 q 1 H F Y t 5 y q 4 0 1 z F 7 m 0 l G E y 9 m b 7 z r k b G / u W V S c Z F e 6 k X G 3 i c 0 T H n A f a o B T T Y f F 6 4 n 4 q l a J H B z 5 7 y c 6 M n m z m B / U F 1 k e T B s B j t O c 4 0 n W + s / u 1 P h 5 w l L t R 9 T p X 4 d D j L 9 v q B S c z 9 m 5 Z q b K 5 Z R / 5 q G r P C E u N b U U y W p r 1 2 S S R E w Z V Z I 4 + 9 u c h p z v S D g E j P V i 6 S J C k S q O 5 F e D C Z P U D k l C d U R q X e x F G W w D Y K o W y p T o S O e h j 3 H l P s s k N R v p / d F A k Z t p y W B k G T 4 / d M 9 w r S / 3 4 t N u C + F k b e 0 s Z a I U N I s W v Q l S D q r 4 R o 2 7 B N T h J 6 T z 3 U 7 W y h F n h F A V d X 6 G 6 w S c H 9 e 1 q 4 B D 3 N 5 T z k j j h a w B e s D G 9 k 2 v Z O y m 5 v t v l x x K C T X E a y / N K 7 4 r F a 7 l f f F N s w u W 0 d M S H Y v l K V 5 A n t L m r V o Q S J 6 y 0 j M t G a S G C u T K 7 a Z 5 L H m U s z a 8 k B k y F L j z F a 1 C 6 A 8 p n J e / k / / K D J n 6 N 5 + 5 G K q o j h t 1 j o V s M Y p M X 6 K 8 J T Q e p 5 e y L w 6 k + W S / l I F q l x b 2 9 3 d J W M p R A D J r T x 6 E b M i i y m H P H A c z I D 8 1 D T G H p m y g K f c C A J Q i o S m a 2 7 K Z k 1 w A a c n E 6 q y l 8 W 4 8 9 D z a i c p i 6 N 2 3 P N p 7 m V x 2 Q x 6 1 p g l C S 2 L s + r W s / h C i h i U X p T F C I c 9 D 3 g l 5 E l W Z z 9 o x / 1 Z Y N u Q e 1 T d a p 1 E Z o o l J E g F 6 z d / a e H u u b Z x 3 b 2 y N l A Z J h x M R m a R 1 X c V Q P F C d w 8 M Z d n x o / N / 8 a N z 9 I t 5 s u Q E D O x Q H h h w X f u t S l r n I 4 3 D i m x 1 o s Z B 5 d m S A z B c C U + D J T s w t E P x 5 2 g w D 7 g F E b Z L F 6 H F d 0 w i h r H F A W 9 n g b H F U x U g d q E R L T 9 K R + f n V O m i c D W b 6 6 J 6 L n 9 z A Z V N 6 X w 4 v p r C y 7 q O O D N K F G e T d j r N 0 w W p t W h C e i / C q l x e A h n g H 8 X 9 e h Z 5 i H y L f E T M I o Y o s i h C p C x S i O Y W t b 0 Q W h Q i W l i 0 Q H R n 0 R 0 i a Z F E d G P R D a L U o r Z L c 4 t y R G c W n S G 6 t e g W 0 c y i G S K R s B B l r J / Q B g d P t 7 b q q e z 0 i T A U / g a W H V j f A 3 Q 7 s u g I 0 a l F p 6 s K S 2 b w m 0 G g T 5 j k c 9 S 8 b q V K d t t E V m g 0 L f q m u 4 7 p r t 9 6 S + k i q j E V j C F o x q f M j G y p m 0 h F 0 6 Z f L 6 F F s V c v c X O v u v h V K 0 M X t 1 K 8 7 O K X i E + 6 + A T x e R e f I z 7 u 4 u N W 5 i 4 + R T z u 4 j H i i y 6 + Q H z V x V f / s c B a n s 7 X V i X u E 8 W 0 I i I g 8 J P t w S f m t 3 X 4 q I 7 1 v G K E + R F d W P Q C 0 Q t U A N G 5 R e 8 Q v c M 3 C 1 S 3 + e R p 8 g F p 1 m t G o 1 b R v q G j a d / Q q n r Y N x x i Z 7 Q v p S P P i u N 1 a 3 3 S x W 1 R j 7 u 4 z X P Q x e Y 4 w S f 3 8 P 4 H 9 v L g 9 d P 9 4 Q / 7 z 3 5 5 t v P 8 s P n 4 f u R 8 4 2 w 7 T 5 y h 8 6 P z 3 D l x x s 6 V 4 z t z 5 3 f n D + f P 9 b 8 3 t j a + 2 v i 6 d n 3 4 o I n 5 0 u l d G z v / A G 0 t i w s = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; ? t &lt; l a t e x i t s h a 1 _ b a s e 6 4 = " + Q f A n y M r w u M M n A T B + e 7 N L P + C i 7 M = " &gt; A A A M d n i c j Z b f b 9 x E E M f d 8 q s k A V J 4 R I J V o o g i H e G u q u A J 0 e T S J p G i 6 E i T t m p d o r V v b a 9 i e 5 3 d d e 4 u l h / 5 a 3 i F P 4 b / h E d m b e / Y z h 0 I S 4 n X n 5 n Z 2 f 3 O r M 9 e F n O l h 8 O / 7 t 1 / 7 / 0 P P v z o w c d r 6 x u f f P r Z 5 s P P X y q R S 5 9 d + C I W 8 r V H F Y t 5 y i 4 0 1 z F 7 n U l G E y 9 m r 7 y r s b G / u m F S c Z G e 6 0 X G 3 i U 0 T H n A f a o B X W 5 + X b i e i K d q k c D N n f P y s n A T q i M v K O b l Q J e X m 9 v D 3 W F 1 k e X B q B l s O 8 0 1 u X y 4 / r M 7 F X 6 e s F T 7 M V X q 7 W i Y 6 X c F l Z r 7 M S v X 3 F y x j P p X N G S F J 8 S V p p 4 q S X 3 t k E y K g C m z X B p / d 5 3 T m O s F A Z e Y q V 4 k T V Q g U t 2 J 9 G I w e Y L K K T E b I P W W l q I M t k E Q d U N l K n T E 0 7 D n m H K f B Z L 6 7 f S + S M C o 7 b Q k E J K M v n 8 8 I E z 7 u 7 3 Y h P t S G K 1 L G 2 u J C C X N o k V f g q S z G q 5 h w z 4 x F e k 5 + V y 3 s 4 V S 5 B k B V J W w v 8 E q A f f n Z e 0 a 8 D C X d 5 Q z 4 m g B W 7 A + s J E t 0 0 g p u 7 7 e 6 s s V h 0 J y H c H 6 S + O K z 2 q 1 W 3 l X b M P s s n X E h G R 3 Q l m a J 7 C 3 p F m L F i S i N 4 z E T G s m i b E y u W K b S R 5 r L s W s L Q 9 E h i w 1 z m x V u w D K Y y r n 5 f / 0 j y J z o O 7 s R y 6 m K o r T Z q 1 T A W u c E u O n C E 8 J r e f p h c y r A 1 o u 6 S 9 V o M q 1 t Z 2 d H T K R Q g S Q 3 M q j F z E r s p h y y A P H w Q z I T 0 1 j D M i U B T z l R h C A U i Q 0 X X N T N m u C C z g 9 m V C V v S w m n Y e e V z t J W R y 0 4 5 5 P c y + L 8 2 b Q s 8 Y s S W h Z n F S 3 n s U X U s S g 9 K I s x j j s e c A r I U + y O v t e O + 7 P A t u G 3 O P q V u s k M l M s I U E q W L / 5 S w t 3 4 N r G d Q d l b a A y T H h a v 8 R E V t 9 V A M U L 3 Q E Y y r L j R + f / 4 k f n 6 B f z Z M k J G N i h P D D g u v Z b l b T O R x q H F d n q R I 2 D y r M l B 2 C 4 E p 4 G S 3 Z g a I f i z 9 F g H n A L I m y X L k K L b 5 l E D G O L A 9 7 O A m O L p y p A 7 E I j W n 6 Q j k 9 P q d J F 4 W o 2 1 0 X 1 X P 7 q A i q b 0 v l w f D W F l 3 U d c W K U K E 4 u 2 + k 0 T x e k 1 q I J 6 b 0 I q 3 J 5 C W S A f x T 3 6 1 n k I f I t 8 h E x i x i i y K I I k b J I I Z p b 1 P Z C a F G I a G H R A t G t R b e I p E U S 0 b V F 1 4 h S i 9 o u z S 3 K E Z 1 Y d I L o x q I b R D O L Z o h E w k K U s X 5 C G x w 8 3 d q q p 7 L T J 8 J Q + B t a t m d 9 9 9 D t w K I D R M c W H a 8 q L J n B b w a B P m G S z 1 H z u p U q 2 W 0 T W a H R t O i b b j u m 2 3 7 r L a W L q M Z U M I a g G Z 8 y M 7 K l b i I V T Z t + P Y c W x V 4 9 x 8 2 9 6 O I X r Q x d 3 E r x v I u f I z 7 q 4 i P E p 1 1 8 i v i w i w 9 b m b v 4 G P G k i y e I z 7 r 4 D P F F F 1 / 8 x w J r e T p f W 5 W 4 j x T T i o i A w E + 2 B 9 + b 3 9 b h 4 + Z r 0 i v G m B / R m U X P E D 1 D B R C d W v Q G 0 R t 8 s 0 B 1 m 0 + e J h + Q Z r 1 m N G 4 V 7 R s 6 m v Y N r a r 7 f c M + d k b 7 U j r w r D h e t 9 Z H X d w W 9 b C L 2 z x 7 X W y O E 3 x y j + 5 + Y C 8 P X j 7 e H f 2 w + + S X J 9 t P 9 5 u P 7 w f O l 8 6 W 8 8 g Z O T 8 6 T 5 0 j Z + J c O L 7 z m / O 7 8 4 f z 5 / r f G 1 9 t 7 G x 8 U 7 v e v 9 f E f O H 0 r o 3 h P 6 v E k O 8 = &lt; / l a t e x i t &gt; ? x,t (a) The overall architecture of CURE. (b) The spatiotemporal encoding module (STEM) that generates ? t for the predicted frame I t .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Visual illustration of the network architectures used in CURE.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Visual comparison between CURE and current SOTA methods on an example from Vimeo90K. The visual differences are highlight by the yellow boxes paired with the residual error maps. Note how CURE outperforms the SOTA methods in term of sharpness (see green arrows) and accuracy (yellow arrows).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head>Figure 7 :Figure 8 :</head><label>78</label><figDesc>Visual demonstration of the continuous interpolation by CURE on an example from the X4K dataset. Only two frames {I 0 , I 1 } are used for predicting several middle frames at temporal locations t ? {0.25, 0.5, 0.75}. Note the sharp textural details preserved by CURE, but lost in the results by XVFI. Visual comparison between CURE, vanilla-NeRF, and NSFF methods on ND Scene.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Avg. PSNR/SSIM values obtained on X4K.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Methods</cell><cell>X4K</cell></row><row><cell>SuperSloMo</cell><cell>19.58 / 0.7099</cell></row><row><cell>ToFlow</cell><cell>22.33/0.7259</cell></row><row><cell>BMBC</cell><cell>24.28 / 0.7777</cell></row><row><cell>XVFI</cell><cell>24.12/0.7566</cell></row><row><cell>CURE</cell><cell>30.05 / 0.8998</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Average PSNR/SSIM obtained by CURE and the current state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods on UCF101, Vimeo90K, and SNU-FILM, NDScene, and Xiph4K datasets. We use bold and underline to highlight the highest and second highest values, respectively. Note the superior results of CURE over SOTA methods.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>UCF 101</cell><cell>Vimeo 90K</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">SNU-FILM</cell><cell></cell><cell>ND Scene</cell><cell>Xiph4K</cell><cell>Average</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Easy</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Hard</cell><cell>Extreme</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>SepConv [31]</cell><cell>27.97</cell><cell>27.32</cell><cell>30.33</cell><cell>27.33</cell><cell>22.80</cell><cell>18.06</cell><cell>24.38</cell><cell>22.83</cell><cell>25.13</cell></row><row><cell>(ICCV17)</cell><cell>0.9401</cell><cell>0.9481</cell><cell>0.9661</cell><cell>0.9451</cell><cell>0.8794</cell><cell>0.7747</cell><cell>0.9294</cell><cell>0.9748</cell><cell>0.9072</cell></row><row><cell>ToFlow [51]</cell><cell>34.58</cell><cell>33.73</cell><cell>39.08</cell><cell>34.39</cell><cell>28.44</cell><cell>23.39</cell><cell>30.05</cell><cell>27.53</cell><cell>31.40</cell></row><row><cell>(IJCV19)</cell><cell>0.9667</cell><cell>0.9682</cell><cell>0.9890</cell><cell>0.9740</cell><cell>0.9180</cell><cell>0.8310</cell><cell>0.9466</cell><cell>0.9850</cell><cell>0.9361</cell></row><row><cell>BMBC [33]</cell><cell>35.16</cell><cell>35.01</cell><cell>39.90</cell><cell>35.31</cell><cell>29.33</cell><cell>23.92</cell><cell>36.01</cell><cell>28.03</cell><cell>32.83</cell></row><row><cell>(ECCV20)</cell><cell>0.9689</cell><cell>0.9764</cell><cell>0.9902</cell><cell>0.9774</cell><cell>0.9270</cell><cell>0.8432</cell><cell>0.9827</cell><cell>0.9131</cell><cell>0.9474</cell></row><row><cell>CAIN [7]</cell><cell>34.91</cell><cell>34.65</cell><cell>39.89</cell><cell>35.61</cell><cell>29.90</cell><cell>24.78</cell><cell>34.81</cell><cell>29.94</cell><cell>33.06</cell></row><row><cell>(AAAI20)</cell><cell>0.9690</cell><cell>0.9730</cell><cell>0.9900</cell><cell>0.9776</cell><cell>0.9292</cell><cell>0.8507</cell><cell>0.9789</cell><cell>0.9184</cell><cell>0.9484</cell></row><row><cell>RRIN [15]</cell><cell>34.93</cell><cell>35.22</cell><cell>39.31</cell><cell>35.23</cell><cell>29.79</cell><cell>24.59</cell><cell>33.89</cell><cell>29.30</cell><cell>32.78</cell></row><row><cell>(ICASSP20)</cell><cell>0.9496</cell><cell>0.9643</cell><cell>0.9897</cell><cell>0.9776</cell><cell>0.9301</cell><cell>0.8511</cell><cell>0.9750</cell><cell>0.9232</cell><cell>0.9451</cell></row><row><cell>AdaCoF [14]</cell><cell>34.90</cell><cell>34.47</cell><cell>39.80</cell><cell>35.05</cell><cell>29.46</cell><cell>24.31</cell><cell>35.75</cell><cell>28.57</cell><cell>32.79</cell></row><row><cell>(CVPR20)</cell><cell>0.9680</cell><cell>0.9730</cell><cell>0.9900</cell><cell>0.9754</cell><cell>0.9244</cell><cell>0.8439</cell><cell>0.9822</cell><cell>0.9093</cell><cell>0.9458</cell></row><row><cell>XVFI [42]</cell><cell>35.09</cell><cell>35.07</cell><cell>39.76</cell><cell>35.12</cell><cell>29.30</cell><cell>23.98</cell><cell>35.76</cell><cell>28.46</cell><cell>32.82</cell></row><row><cell>(ICCV21)</cell><cell>0.9685</cell><cell>0.9760</cell><cell>0.9991</cell><cell>0.9769</cell><cell>0.9245</cell><cell>0.8417</cell><cell>0.9819</cell><cell>0.9121</cell><cell>0.9476</cell></row><row><cell>ABME [34]</cell><cell>35.38</cell><cell>36.18</cell><cell>39.59</cell><cell>35.77</cell><cell>30.58</cell><cell>25.42</cell><cell>33.17</cell><cell>30.74</cell><cell>33.35</cell></row><row><cell>(ICCV21)</cell><cell>0.9698</cell><cell>0.9805</cell><cell>0.9901</cell><cell>0.9789</cell><cell>0.9364</cell><cell>0.8639</cell><cell>0.9736</cell><cell>0.9366</cell><cell>0.9537</cell></row><row><cell>CURE</cell><cell>35.36 0.9705</cell><cell>35.73 0.9789</cell><cell>39.90 0.9910</cell><cell>35.94 0.9797</cell><cell>30.66 0.9373</cell><cell>25.44 0.8638</cell><cell>36.24 0.9839</cell><cell>30.94 0.9389</cell><cell>33.78 0.9555</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>27.93 / 0.9469</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>SloMo</cell><cell>ToFlow</cell><cell>BMBC</cell><cell>RRIN</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>27.63 / 0.9461</cell><cell>29.06 / 0.9568</cell><cell>32.05 / 0.9770</cell></row><row><cell>CAIN</cell><cell>ABME</cell><cell>CURE</cell><cell>Groundtruth</cell></row><row><cell>33.01 / 0.9791</cell><cell>34.65 / 0.9829</cell><cell>35.15 / 0.9859</cell><cell>PSNR / SSIM</cell></row><row><cell>SloMo</cell><cell>ToFlow</cell><cell>BMBC</cell><cell>RRIN</cell></row><row><cell>31.70 / 0.9743</cell><cell>27.17 / 0.9617</cell><cell>32.74 / 0.9837</cell><cell>33.27 / 0.9815</cell></row><row><cell>CAIN</cell><cell>ABME</cell><cell>CURE</cell><cell>Groundtruth</cell></row><row><cell>33.33 / 0.9800</cell><cell>33.54 / 0.9858</cell><cell>34.85 / 0.9867</cell><cell>PSNR / SSIM</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Quantitative (PSNR/SSIM) comparisons of different video representation algorithms on the ND Scene dataset. This table highlights that CURE provides better video representation by learning a general prior across videos.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Dataset</cell><cell cols="2">Camera Post Resolution</cell><cell></cell><cell>Algorithms</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>V-NF</cell><cell>NSFF [18]</cell><cell>CURE</cell></row><row><cell>Ballon1-2</cell><cell>1</cell><cell cols="3">540 ? 288 10.75/0.4582 24.58/0.8980 31.05/0.9742</cell></row><row><cell>Dynamic Face-2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell cols="3">547 ? 288 23.09/0.8317 27.13/0.9608 40.81/0.9930</cell></row><row><cell>Jumping</cell><cell>5</cell><cell cols="3">540 ? 288 26.07/0.8099 27.19/0.9281 31.23/0.9624</cell></row><row><cell>Playground</cell><cell>2</cell><cell cols="3">573 ? 288 22.45/0.7222 24.64/0.8912 36.15/0.9938</cell></row><row><cell>Skating-2</cell><cell>4</cell><cell cols="3">541 ? 288 28.44/0.8648 34.05/0.9782 39.67/0.9899</cell></row><row><cell>Truck-2</cell><cell>9</cell><cell cols="3">542 ? 288 28.37/0.8075 34.74/0.9751 39.78/0.9887</cell></row><row><cell>Umbrella</cell><cell>11</cell><cell cols="3">543 ? 288 23.91/0.5876 23.91/0.8441 39.66/0.9880</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>CURE w/o Rep</cell><cell cols="2">CURE w/o Crd</cell><cell>CURE</cell><cell>Groundtruth</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>36.94 / 0.9928</cell><cell cols="2">38.89 / 0.9928</cell><cell>39.91 / 0.9945</cell><cell>PSNR / SSIM</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Average PSNR/SSIM obtained by the full CURE and its ablated variants.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>UCF 101</cell><cell>Vimeo 90K</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">SNU-FILM</cell><cell></cell><cell>ND Scene</cell><cell>Xiph4K</cell><cell>Average</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Easy</cell><cell>Medium</cell><cell>Hard</cell><cell>Extreme</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CURE w/o</cell><cell>34.80</cell><cell>35.15</cell><cell>39.82</cell><cell>35.71</cell><cell>30.36</cell><cell>25.14</cell><cell>35.13</cell><cell>30.45</cell><cell>33.32</cell></row><row><cell>Rep</cell><cell>0.9682</cell><cell>0.9769</cell><cell>0.9903</cell><cell>0.9787</cell><cell>0.9350</cell><cell>0.8601</cell><cell>0.9802</cell><cell>0.9359</cell><cell>0.9530</cell></row><row><cell>CURE w/o</cell><cell>35.11</cell><cell>35.25</cell><cell>39.76</cell><cell>35.63</cell><cell>30.39</cell><cell>25.26</cell><cell>35.68</cell><cell>30.52</cell><cell>33.45</cell></row><row><cell>Crd</cell><cell>0.9689</cell><cell>0.9772</cell><cell>0.9900</cell><cell>0.9784</cell><cell>0.9350</cell><cell>0.8609</cell><cell>0.9816</cell><cell>0.9341</cell><cell>0.9531</cell></row><row><cell>CURE</cell><cell>35.36 0.9705</cell><cell>35.73 0.9789</cell><cell>39.90 0.9910</cell><cell>35.94 0.9797</cell><cell>30.66 0.9373</cell><cell>25.44 0.8638</cell><cell>36.24 0.9839</cell><cell>30.94 0.9389</cell><cell>33.78 0.9555</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">https://media.xiph.org/video/derf/.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>We numerically validated CURE on several standard video interpolation datasets. Our experiments include comparisons with the state-of-the-art (SOTA) methods and ablation studies highlighting the key components of the proposed architecture.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Datasets</head><p>We consider the following four datasets for numerical evaluation:</p><p>Vimeo90K: The Vimeo90K training dataset contains 51,312 frame triplets with 448?256 pixel resolution, and the validation dataset contains 3,782 triplets that we use for testing. We additionally increased the training data by extracting 91,701 triplets (i.e. {I 0 , I 2 , I 4 }) from the septulets dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>This work was supported by the NSF award CCF-2043134.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Feature Fuser (U-NET</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MEMC-Net: Motion estimation and motion compensation driven neural network for video interpolation and enhancement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="933" to="948" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High accuracy optical flow estimation based on a theory for warping</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Brox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bruhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Papenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Weickert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="36" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A method for motion adaptive frame rate up-conversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Castagno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Haavisto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ramponi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Transactions on circuits and Systems for Video Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="436" to="446" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NeRV: Neural representations for videos</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shrivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Large displacement optical flow from nearest neighbor fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2443" to="2450" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning implicit fields for generative shape modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5939" to="5948" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Channel attention is all you need for video frame interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10663" to="10671" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural radiance flow for 4D view synthesis and video processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14324" to="14334" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DeepStereo: Learning to predict new views from the world&apos;s imagery</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Neulander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Philbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Snavely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5515" to="5524" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">LiteFlowNet: A lightweight convolutional neural network for optical flow estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Loy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8981" to="8989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spatial transformer networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jaderberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Simonyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zisserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Super-SloMo: High quality estimation of multiple intermediate frames for video interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Jampani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Learned-Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kautz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9000" to="9008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adam: A method for stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kingma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">AdaCof: adaptive collaboration of flows for video frame interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5316" to="5325" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Video frame interpolation via residue refinement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2613" to="2617" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Slavcheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zollhoefer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lassner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lovegrove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Goesele</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Lv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2103.02597</idno>
		<title level="m">Neural 3D video synthesis</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Neural scene flow fields for space-time view synthesis of dynamic scenes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Niklaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Snavely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2011.13084</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural scene flow fields for space-time view synthesis of dynamic scenes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Niklaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Snavely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6498" to="6508" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">AutoInt: automatic integration for fast neural volume rendering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lindell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N P</forename><surname>Martel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wetzstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural sparse voxel fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Chua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Theobalt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15651" to="15663" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Zero-shot learning of continuous 3D refractive index maps from discrete intensity-only measurements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kamilov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2112.00002</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Video frame synthesis using deep voxel flow</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Yeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Agarwala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4463" to="4471" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning image matching by simply watching video</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kneip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Alvarez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="450" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Novel integration of frame rate up conversion and hevc coding based on rate-distortion optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Image Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="678" to="691" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NeRF in the wild: Neural radiance fields for unconstrained photo collections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Martin-Brualla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Radwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sajjadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Barron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dosovitskiy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Duckworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7210" to="7219" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Phasenet for video frame interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Djelouah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mcwilliams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sorkine-Hornung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Schroers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="498" to="507" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NeRF: Representing scenes as neural radiance fields for view synthesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mildenhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tancik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Barron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ramamoorthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="405" to="421" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context-aware synthesis for video frame interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Niklaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1701" to="1710" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Softmax splatting for video frame interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Niklaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5437" to="5446" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Video frame interpolation via adaptive convolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Niklaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="670" to="679" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Video frame interpolation via adaptive separable convolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Niklaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="270" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting adaptive convolutions for video frame interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Niklaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1099" to="1109" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BMBC: Bilateral motion estimation with bilateral cost volume for video interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="125" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asymmetric bilateral motion estimation for video frame interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14539" to="14548" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DeepSDF: Learning continuous signed distance functions for shape representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Florence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Straub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ri</forename><surname>Newcombe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lovegrove</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="174" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nerfies: Deformable neural radiance fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Sinha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Barron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bouaziz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Goldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Seitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Martin-Brualla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5865" to="5874" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural body: Implicit neural representations with structured latent codes for novel view synthesis of dynamic humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Shuai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Bao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of IEEE Conference Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>IEEE Conference Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optical flow estimation using a spatial pyramid network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ranjan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Black</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4161" to="4170" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised deep learning for optical flow estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">NeRP: implicit neural representation learning with prior embedding for sparsely sampled image reconstruction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pauly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2108.10991</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">2021</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>eess.IV</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Video frame interpolation via generalized deformable convolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Multimedia</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">XVFI: Extreme video frame interpolation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14489" to="14498" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implicit neural representations with periodic activation functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Sitzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Martel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bergman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lindell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wetzstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scene representation networks: Continuous 3d-structure-aware neural scene representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Sitzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zollhoefer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wetzstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ucf101: A dataset of 101 human actions classes from videos in the wild</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Soomro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Zamir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1212.0402</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coil: Coordinate-based internal learning for tomographic imaging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wohlberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kamilov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Comp. Imag</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="1" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spatio-temporal video interpolation and denoising using motion-assisted steering kernel (mask) regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Takeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Van Beek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Milanfar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Image Processing</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE International Conference on Image Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="637" to="640" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">RAFT: recurrent all-pairs field transforms for optical flow</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Teed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="402" to="419" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling and optimization of high frame rate video transmission over wireless networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yuen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2713" to="2726" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Space-time neural irradiance fields for free-viewpoint video</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Xian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9421" to="9431" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Video enhancement with taskoriented flow</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1106" to="1125" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Novel view synthesis of dynamic scenes with globally coherent depths from a monocular camera</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Gallo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kautz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5336" to="5345" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Riegler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Snavely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Koltun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2010.07492</idno>
		<title level="m">NeRF++: Analyzing and improving neural radiance fields</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">2020</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>cs.CV</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
