<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">TENET: Transformer Encoding Network for Effective Temporal Flow on Motion Prediction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuting</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Megvii Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hangning</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Megvii Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhigang</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>zhangzhigang@megvii.com2cfengag@connect.ust.hk4linhuadong</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Megvii Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huadong</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chaofei</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yizhi</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ann Arbor</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhenting</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Megvii Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">Harbin Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shiyu</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuefeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Megvii Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ziyao</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Megvii Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chi</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>zhangchi@megvii.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Megvii Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">TENET: Transformer Encoding Network for Effective Temporal Flow on Motion Prediction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2022-11-11T17:53+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This technical report presents an effective method for motion prediction in autonomous driving. We develop a Transformer-based method for input encoding and trajectory prediction. Besides, we propose the Temporal Flow Header to enhance the trajectory encoding. In the end, an efficient K-means ensemble method is used. Using our Transformer network and ensemble method, we win the first place of Argoverse 2 Motion Forecasting Challenge with the state-of-the-art brier-minFDE score of 1.90.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>This technical report aims to share details of our method. Our network is developed upon SceneTransformer <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, a Transformer-based <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> model. For agent trajectories, timewise and agent-wise self-attention is used to encode time sequence and spatial interaction information. Besides, crossattention is used to share map information with agent trajectories. Finally, we predict K trajectories and their corresponding scores from K learnable tokens. These learnable tokens get history trajectories and map information from mixed features of agent and map through cross-attention layer.</p><p>In general, we summarize the contribution of our proposed algorithm as follow:</p><p>? We propose Temporal Flow Header to enhance the flow of temporal information in the whole network.</p><p>? We propose a K-means method for the ensemble stage, and achieve state-of-the-art performance. <ref type="bibr">*</ref> The first three authors contribute equally to this work.</p><p>? For Transformer model, we propose an efficient strategy to reduce the input size in the training stage and increase the size in the testing stage to achieve faster training of the model while obtaining high accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Methodology</head><p>The overview of TENET is given in <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref>. The proposed motion prediction model consists of three modules: (1) Transformer-based <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> encoder that extracts spatially and temporally the feature of agent and map. (2) Attention decoder that utilizes learnable token <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> to query effective information from mixed features of agent and map after encoder. (3) Three output headers that are for regression, score, and enhancing temporal information interaction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Model</head><p>Encoder and Decoder We adopt efficient self-attention and cross-attention from SceneTransformer <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> to implement intra and inter information interaction of agent and map.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Self Att i (x) ? Att i (x, x, x), CrossAtt i,j (x1, x2) ? Att i,j (x1, x2, x2),</formula><p>where Self Att i (x) performs attention over axis i of the tensor x, mixing information along axis i while keeping information along other axes independent. It is the same for CrossAtt i,j (x1, x2). In decoder, we generate K learnable tokens as queries to learn prediction trajectory feature from mixed features of agent and map after encoder through cross-attention layer,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">x pt = Self Att K (CrossAtt K,M (x k , x m )),</formula><p>where x m is the mixed feature of agent and map, x k is learnable token, and x pt is prediction trajectory feature. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Transformer Backbone</head><p>Regression Header Score Header</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Temporal Flow Header</head><p>Inferenced History <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Overall architecture of the proposed model TENET.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">[ ! , " , # , $ , % , &amp; ] Scores K</formula><p>Regression Header We take a 2-layer MLP to decode the trajectory information from x pt in all timestamps (including history and future), including positions, orientation, and instant velocity in BEV coordinates. To eliminate the effect of long-range prediction error accumulation on a predicted trajectory, we use LSTM <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> to extract time-sequential information on target agent feature, and add it to post-MLP trajectory information. The final forecasted regression result is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">T raj pred = M LP (x pt ) + LST M (x pt ).</formula><p>Score Header To predict more reasonably, our model take map information into consideration. Hence, cross-attention layer is used to fuse map feature into x pt . Then we obtain a normalized score after feeding corresponding regression results into a 2-layer MLP and softmax,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">S pred = Sof tM ax(M LP (CrossAtt K,M (x pt , M ap))).</formula><p>Temporal Flow Header To enhance the flow of temporal information in TENET, we propose this header as an auxiliary task to realize a closed loop between history and future. Specifically, TENET regresses backward to get historical trajectories through using the prediction results, establishing temporal consistency on trajectory information. The below equation explains how we slice out future timestamps feature x f from x pt and devise a FPN (Feature Pyramid Networks) <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> module to obtain history trajectory h pred ,</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">h pred = M LP (F P N (x f )).</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Loss function</head><p>The loss function of the model consists of three parts.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">L=L reg + ? 1 L score + ? 2 L tf , where ? 1 = 0.3, ? 2 = 0.3.</formula><p>For L reg , in order to construct the connection between trajectories and scores, we use GMM (Gaussian Mixture Model) <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref> loss which ensures each trajectory has a reasonable score. We use all attributes of trajectory as ground truth label, including position, orientation, and instant velocity. In addition, both future and history timestamps are supervised, aiming to learn a motion pattern from history trajectory through Autoencoder <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">L reg = ? log K k=1 e log(si)? 1 2 T t=1 (A gt t ?Ai,t) 2 , where A i,t = [x i,t , y i,t , cos i,t , sin i,t , v i,t ], s i is the score of i th predicted trajectory.</formula><p>For L score , to make the positive trajectory (defined as the closest trajectory to ground truth) more confident, we adopt the max-margin loss: Where ? is the margin and we set it 0.15 in our loss function ands i is the score of positive prediction.</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">L score = 1 K?1 K i=1,i =i max(0, s i +? ?s i ),</formula><p>For L tf , we take the historical trajectory h gt as the ground truth for Temporal Flow Header middle-level supervision.</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">L tf = M SELoss(h pred , h gt )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Data Augmentation</head><p>Augmentation, which is essential for our model, can be divided into agent augmentation and training augmentation.</p><p>Firstly, we regard other agents as the target agent in agent augmentation. Owing to our transformer-based information interactor, the target agent and the other agents are the same during the training process. Therefore, in order to generate more kinds of conditions under one single scenario, we propose agent augmentation exchanging the identities between target agent and other agents for prediction model.</p><p>Besides, during training, four augmentation methods (translation, rotation, flipping, and resizing) are used to generate abundant scenarios. Augmentations are applied simultaneously in agent tensors, ground-truth tensors and road graph tensors. In translation augmentation, we first generate random distance within ?3m to 3m, and then translate the coordinates in the above three tensors, such as the coordinates of trajectories and centerlines etc. In rotation augmentation, we randomly rotate the coordinate system within [? ? 6 , ? 6 ]. In flip augmentation, we flip the coordinate system along the y axis with a certain probability during training process. In resize augmentation, the entire scene are scaled by a randomly selected constant within [0.8, 1.2].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Hard Mining</head><p>We use hard mining technique to improve the prediction of the model in difficult scenarios. Specifically, we train a proxy model with a randomly sampled training subset from the original training set, and let this proxy model perform inference on the remaining training set. Then, we mine those scenarios in which the proxy model performs poorly (scenarios with a large brier-minFDE) and increase the proportion of these scenarios in the training phase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5.">Multi-Trajectory Ensemble</head><p>Multi-modality is a central characteristic of the trajectory prediction task. Most methods avoid unimodal prediction output using the winner-takes-all (WTA) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, which is unstable due to network initialization. Inspired by DCMS <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>, we enhance the multi-modality of predicted trajectories by Multi-Trajectory Ensemble.</p><p>Specifically, we use models with different random seed initializations, different degrees of hard mining, and different training epochs to generate M sets of trajectories (each set contains K trajectories). Then, from the total M * K trajectories, we apply K-means algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> to generate K trajectory clusters. For each cluster, we average all trajectories in the cluster to generate the output trajectory, and use the sum of their scores as the score of that output trajectory. Finally, all K scores of trajectories will be linearly normalized. It turns out that summing over scores is better than averaging over scores, as summing tends to give higher scores to clusters with more trajectories. We use the endpoint distance as the distance metric when clustering. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2</ref> shows the visualization of Multi-Trajectory Ensemble. We also find out that the final result can be used as teacher during knowledge distillation to make single models achieve better precision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Dataset and Metrics</head><p>Dataset The Argoverse 2 Motion Forecasting Dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> contains 250000 11-second scenarios with a sampling rate of 10HZ. For the training and the validation sets, the first five seconds of each scenarios are used as input and the other six seconds are used as the ground truth for models to predict. For the test set, only the first five seconds are provided. Argoverse 2 Motion Forecasting Dataset provides rich map information and contains five different dynamic categories.  p corresponds to the probability of the best forecasted trajectory.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Implementation Details</head><p>We train our model for 200 epochs (around 96 hours) using eight 2080Ti GPUs. As for the input, we sample actors and lanes with distance less than 100 meters from the target agent. Using rotation and translation, each scene is normalized using the target agent as the center. Specifically, the most recent historical position of the target agent (at the 49 th frame) is taken as the origin, and the direction of the target agent historical trajectory is aligned with the positive axis of X. We use Adam <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> optimizer with an initial learning rate of 2.5e-4, which is decayed to 2.5e-5 at 170 epochs and to 2.5e-6 at 190 epochs. Agent dimension (denoted by A) is set to 32, and map dimension (denoted by M ) is set to 128 at training time. Since the model supports dynamic agent and map dimensional inputs, the dimensions increased to 64 and 256 respectively during testing. We use padding and clipping to align the dimensions. All transformer modules in TENET contain 128 hidden units.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Results</head><p>Argoverse 2 Motion Forecasting Competition. We evaluate TENET on Argoverse 2 Motion Forecasting Competition. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>, our method ranks 1 st on the final leaderboard. The official metric is brier-minFDE.</p><p>To demonstrate the effectiveness of Multi-Trajectory Ensemble, we compare the average performance of trajectories before ensemble and after ensemble on the Argoverse 2 Motion Forecasting test set. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>, Multi-Trajectory Ensemble integrates all trajectories and enhances the multi-modality and confidence of the prediction.</p><p>Besides, <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> shows that increasing the input size yields better prediction results. So we reduce the input size in the training phase and increase the size in the testing phase to accelerate training while maintaining predictive accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusions</head><p>This technical report presents an effective method for the motion prediction task. We develop an efficient Transformer-based network to predict trajectories, and we propose Temporal Flow Header to enhance the trajectories. Besides, we devise a training strategy to accelerate model training and a strong K-means based ensemble method. We conduct experiments on Argoverse 2 Motion Forecasting Dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> and achieve state-of-the-art performance. Finally, we hope this work will be a strong baseline in this motion prediction task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Metrics Argoverse 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Motion Forecasting Challenge chooses brier-minFDE (K=6) as the metrics. MinFDE(K) is the minimum displacement between K final positions and the ground truth final position. Similarly, brier-minFDE multiplies (1.0 ? p) 2 with the endpoint L2 distance, where</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Multi-Trajectory Ensemble Visualization. The top row shows the trajectories before ensemble and the bottom row shows the trajectories after ensemble. History trajectories are shown in blue, predicted trajectories are shown in red, ground truth trajectories are shown in green.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results on the test set of Argoverse 2 Motion Forecasting Dataset. Brier-minFDE is the official ranking metric.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Method &amp; Rank</cell><cell cols="5">minADE (K=6) minFDE (K=6) Miss Rate (K=6) brier-minADE (K=6) brier-minFDE (K=6)</cell></row><row><cell>TENET 1 st (Ours)</cell><cell>0.70</cell><cell>1.38</cell><cell>0.19</cell><cell>2.15</cell><cell>1.90</cell></row><row><cell>OPPred 2 nd</cell><cell>0.71</cell><cell>1.36</cell><cell>0.19</cell><cell>2.18</cell><cell>1.92</cell></row><row><cell>GANet 3 rd</cell><cell>0.73</cell><cell>1.36</cell><cell>0.17</cell><cell>2.26</cell><cell>1.98</cell></row><row><cell>Polkach 4 th</cell><cell>0.71</cell><cell>1.39</cell><cell>0.19</cell><cell>2.30</cell><cell>2.00</cell></row><row><cell>QCNet 5 th</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>1.58</cell><cell>0.24</cell><cell>2.41</cell><cell>2.14</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Ablation study results of modules on the Argoverse 2 test set.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="4">Method big input size MTE brier-minFDE (K=6)</cell></row><row><cell>TENET</cell><cell>? ?</cell><cell>?</cell><cell>2.03 2.01 1.90</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">End-toend object detection with transformers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolas</forename><surname>Carion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francisco</forename><surname>Massa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Synnaeve</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolas</forename><surname>Usunier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Kirillov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sergey</forename><surname>Zagoruyko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European conference on computer vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="229" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long short-term memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sepp</forename><surname>Hochreiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J?rgen</forename><surname>Schmidhuber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1735" to="1780" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adam: A method for stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Diederik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Kingma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1412.6980</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stochastic multiple choice learning for training diverse deep ensembles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Purushwalkam Shiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Prakash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Viresh</forename><surname>Cogswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Ranjan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dhruv</forename><surname>Crandall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Batra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feature pyramid networks for object detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsung-Yi</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Piotr</forename><surname>Doll?r</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ross</forename><surname>Girshick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaiming</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bharath</forename><surname>Hariharan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Serge</forename><surname>Belongie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2117" to="2125" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cheng-Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei-Chen</forename><surname>Liou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiun-Wei</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daw-Ran</forename><surname>Liou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Liou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Autoencoder for words. Neurocomputing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="96" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Some methods for classification and analysis of multivariate observations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Macqueen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the fifth Berkeley symposium on mathematical statistics and probability</title>
		<meeting>the fifth Berkeley symposium on mathematical statistics and probability<address><addrLine>Oakland, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="297" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiquan</forename><surname>Ngiam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Caine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Vasudevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhengdong</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao-Tien Lewis</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Ling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Roelofs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Bewley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenxi</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashish</forename><surname>Venugopal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Scene transformer: A unified multi-task model for behavior prediction and planning. arXiv e-prints</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page">2106</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gaussian mixture models. encyclopedia of biometrics 827-832</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Argoverse 2: Next generation datasets for self-driving perception and forecasting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tanmay</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Lambert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jagjeet</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Siddhesh</forename><surname>Khandelwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ratnesh</forename><surname>Bowen Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jhony</forename><surname>Hartnett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kaesemodel Pontes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On layer normalization in the transformer architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruibin</forename><surname>Xiong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunchang</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuxin</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huishuai</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanyan</forename><surname>Lan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liwei</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tieyan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>PMLR, 2020. 1</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10524" to="10533" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dcms: Motion forecasting with dual consistency and multi-pseudo-target supervision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maosheng</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiamiao</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xunnong</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tongyi</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qifeng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2204.05859</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2022</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
