<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Decomposable Attention Model for Natural Language Inference</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Decomposable Attention Model for Natural Language Inference</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Ankur P. Parikh Google New York, NY Oscar Täckström Google New York, NY Dipanjan Das Google New York, NY Jakob Uszkoreit Google Mountain View, CA</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2021-06-25T18:12+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We propose a simple neural architecture for natural language inference. Our approach uses attention to decompose the problem into subproblems that can be solved separately, thus making it trivially parallelizable. On the Stanford Natural Language Inference (SNLI) dataset, we obtain state-of-the-art results with almost an order of magnitude fewer parameters than previous work and without relying on any word-order information. Adding intra-sentence attention that takes a minimum amount of order into account yields further improvements.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Natural language inference (NLI) refers to the problem of determining entailment and contradiction relationships between a premise and a hypothesis. NLI is a central problem in language understanding <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Katz, 1972;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bos and Markert, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">van Benthem, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">MacCartney and Manning, 2009</ref>) and recently the large SNLI corpus of 570K sentence pairs was created for this task <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bowman et al., 2015)</ref>. We present a new model for NLI and leverage this corpus for comparison with prior work.</p><p>A large body of work based on neural networks for text similarity tasks including NLI has been published in recent years <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hu et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr">Rocktäschel et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Wang and Jiang, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Yin et al., 2016, inter alia)</ref>. The dominating trend in these models is to build complex, deep text representation models, for example, with convolutional networks <ref type="bibr">(LeCun et al., 1990, CNNs henceforth)</ref> or long short-term memory networks <ref type="bibr">(Hochreiter and Schmidhuber, 1997,</ref> LSTMs henceforth) with the goal of deeper sentence comprehension. While these approaches have yielded impressive results, they are often computationally very expensive, and result in models having millions of parameters (excluding embeddings).</p><p>Here, we take a different approach, arguing that for natural language inference it can often suffice to simply align bits of local text substructure and then aggregate this information. For example, consider the following sentences:</p><p>• Bob is in his room, but because of the thunder and lightning outside, he cannot sleep.</p><p>• Bob is awake.</p><p>• It is sunny outside.</p><p>The first sentence is complex in structure and it is challenging to construct a compact representation that expresses its entire meaning. However, it is fairly easy to conclude that the second sentence follows from the first one, by simply aligning Bob with Bob and cannot sleep with awake and recognizing that these are synonyms. Similarly, one can conclude that It is sunny outside contradicts the first sentence, by aligning thunder and lightning with sunny and recognizing that these are most likely incompatible.</p><p>We leverage this intuition to build a simpler and more lightweight approach to NLI within a neural framework; with considerably fewer parameters, our model outperforms more complex existing neural architectures. In contrast to existing approaches, our approach only relies on alignment and is fully computationally decomposable with respect to the input text. An overview of our approach is given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Given two sentences, where each word is repre-sented by an embedding vector, we first create a soft alignment matrix using neural attention <ref type="bibr">(Bahdanau et al., 2015)</ref>. We then use the (soft) alignment to decompose the task into subproblems that are solved separately. Finally, the results of these subproblems are merged to produce the final classification. In addition, we optionally apply intra-sentence attention <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Cheng et al., 2016)</ref> to endow the model with a richer encoding of substructures prior to the alignment step.</p><p>Asymptotically our approach does the same total work as a vanilla LSTM encoder, while being trivially parallelizable across sentence length, which can allow for considerable speedups in low-latency settings. Empirical results on the SNLI corpus show that our approach achieves state-of-the-art results, while using almost an order of magnitude fewer parameters compared to complex LSTM-based approaches.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Our method is motivated by the central role played by alignment in machine translation <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Koehn, 2009</ref>) and previous approaches to sentence similarity modeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Haghighi et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Das and Smith, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chang et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Fader et al., 2013)</ref>, natural language inference <ref type="bibr">(Marsi and Krahmer, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">MacCartney et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr">Hickl and Bensley, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr">MacCartney et al., 2008)</ref>, and semantic parsing <ref type="bibr">(Andreas et al., 2013)</ref>. The neural counterpart to alignment, attention <ref type="bibr">(Bahdanau et al., 2015)</ref>, which is a key part of our approach, was originally proposed and has been predominantly used in conjunction with LSTMs <ref type="bibr">(Rocktäschel et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Wang and Jiang, 2016)</ref> and to a lesser extent with CNNs <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Yin et al., 2016)</ref>. In contrast, our use of attention is purely based on word embeddings and our method essentially consists of feed-forward networks that operate largely independently of word order.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Approach</head><p>Let a = (a 1 , . . . , a a ) and b = (b 1 , . . . , b b ) be the two input sentences of length a and b , respectively. We assume that each a i , b j ∈ R d is a word embedding vector of dimension d and that each sentence is prepended with a "NULL" token. Our training data comes in the form of labeled pairs {a (n) , b (n) , y (n) } N n=1 , where y (n) = (y time, we receive a pair of sentences (a, b) and our goal is to predict the correct label y.</p><p>Input representation. Letā = (ā 1 , . . . ,ā a ) and b = (b 1 , . . . ,b b ) denote the input representation of each fragment that is fed to subsequent steps of the algorithm. The vanilla version of our model simply definesā := a andb := b. With this input representation, our model does not make use of word order. However, we discuss an extension using intrasentence attention in Section 3.4 that uses a minimal amount of sequence information.</p><p>The core model consists of the following three components (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>), which are trained jointly:</p><p>Attend. First, soft-align the elements ofā andb using a variant of neural attention <ref type="bibr">(Bahdanau et al., 2015)</ref> and decompose the problem into the comparison of aligned subphrases.</p><p>Compare. Second, separately compare each aligned subphrase to produce a set of vectors {v 1,i } a i=1 for a and {v 2,j } b j=1 for b. Each v 1,i is a nonlinear combination of a i and its (softly) aligned subphrase in b (and analogously for v 2,j ).</p><p>Aggregate. Finally, aggregate the sets {v 1,i } a i=1 and {v 2,j } b j=1 from the previous step and use the result to predict the labelŷ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Attend</head><p>We first obtain unnormalized attention weights e ij , computed by a function F , which decomposes as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">e ij := F (ā i ,b j ) := F (ā i ) T F (b j ) .<label>(1)</label></formula><p>This decomposition avoids the quadratic complexity that would be associated with separately applying F a × b times. Instead, only a + b applications of F are needed. We take F to be a feed-forward neural network with ReLU activations <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Glorot et al., 2011)</ref>.</p><p>These attention weights are normalized as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">β i := b j=1 exp(e ij ) b k=1 exp(e ik )b j , α j := a i=1 exp(e ij ) a k=1 exp(e kj )ā i .<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Here β i is the subphrase inb that is (softly) aligned toā i and vice versa for α j .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Compare</head><p>Next, we separately compare the aligned phrases</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">{(ā i , β i )} a i=1 and {(b j , α j )} b j=1 using a function G, which in this work is again a feed-forward network: v 1,i := G([ā i , β i ]) ∀i ∈ [1, . . . , a ] , v 2,j := G([b j , α j ]) ∀j ∈ [1, . . . , b ] .</formula><p>( <ref type="formula">3)</ref> where the brackets [·, ·] denote concatenation. Note that since there are only a linear number of terms in this case, we do not need to apply a decomposition as was done in the previous step. Thus G can jointly take into account bothā i , and β i .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Aggregate</head><p>We now have two sets of comparison vectors {v 1,i } a i=1 and {v 2,j } b j=1 . We first aggregate over each set by summation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">v 1 = a i=1 v 1,i , v 2 = b j=1 v 2,j .<label>(4)</label></formula><p>and feed the result through a final classifier H, that is a feed forward network followed by a linear layer:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">y = H([v 1 , v 2 ]) ,<label>(5)</label></formula><p>whereŷ ∈ R C represents the predicted (unnormalized) scores for each class and consequently the predicted class is given byŷ = argmax iŷ i . For training, we use multi-class cross-entropy loss with dropout regularization <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Srivastava et al., 2014)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">L(θ F , θ G , θ H ) = 1 N N n=1 C c=1 y (n) c log exp(ŷ c ) C c =1 exp(ŷ c )</formula><p>.</p><p>Here θ F , θ G , θ H denote the learnable parameters of the functions F, G and H, respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Intra-Sentence Attention (Optional)</head><p>In the above model, the input representations are simple word embeddings. However, we can augment this input representation with intra-sentence attention to encode compositional relationships between words within each sentence, as proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Cheng et al. (2016)</ref>. Similar to Eqs. 1 and 2, we define</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">f ij := F intra (a i ) T F intra (a j ) ,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where F intra is a feed-forward network. We then create the self-aligned phrases</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">a i := a j=1 exp(f ij + d i−j ) a k=1 exp(f ik + d i−k ) a j .<label>(7)</label></formula><p>The distance-sensitive bias terms d i−j ∈ R provides the model with a minimal amount of sequence information, while remaining parallelizable. These terms are bucketed such that all distances greater than 10 words share the same bias. The input representation for subsequent steps is then defined asā i := [a i , a i ] and analogouslyb i :</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">= [b i , b i ].</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Computational Complexity</head><p>We now discuss the asymptotic complexity of our approach and how it offers a higher degree of parallelism than LSTM-based approaches. Recall that d denotes embedding dimension and means sentence length. For simplicity we assume that all hidden dimensions are d and that the complexity of matrix(d × d)-vector(d × 1) multiplication is O(d 2 ).</p><p>A key assumption of our analysis is that &lt; d, which we believe is reasonable and is true of the SNLI dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bowman et al., 2015)</ref> where &lt; 80, whereas recent LSTM-based approaches have used d ≥ 300. This assumption allows us to bound the complexity of computing the 2 attention weights.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Vendrov et al., 2015)</ref> 98.8 81.4 15.0M 300D tree-based CNN encoders <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Mou et al., 2015)</ref> 83.3 82.1 3.5M 300D SPINN-PI encoders <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bowman et al., 2016)</ref> 89.2 83.2 3.7M</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Complexity of</head><p>100D LSTM with attention <ref type="bibr">(Rocktäschel et al., 2016)</ref> 85.3 83.5 252K 300D mLSTM <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Wang and Jiang, 2016)</ref> 92.0 86.1 1.9M 450D LSTMN with deep attention fusion <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Cheng et al., 2016)</ref> 88.5 86.3 3.4M</p><p>Our approach (vanilla) 89.5 86.3 382K Our approach with intra-sentence attention 90.5 86.8 582K   Thus the total complexity of the model is O( d 2 + 2 d), which is equal to that of an LSTM with attention. However, note that with the assumption that &lt; d, this becomes O( d 2 ) which is the same complexity as a regular LSTM. Moreover, unlike the LSTM, our approach has the advantage of being parallelizable over , which can be useful at test time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head><p>We evaluate our approach on the Stanford Natural Language Inference (SNLI) dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bowman et al., 2015)</ref>. Given a sentences pair (a, b), the task is to predict whether b is entailed by a, b contradicts a, or whether their relationship is neutral.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Implementation Details</head><p>The method was implemented in TensorFlow <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abadi et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Data preprocessing: Following Bowman et al. (2015), we remove examples labeled "-" (no gold label) from the dataset, which leaves 549,367 pairs for training, 9,842 for development, and 9,824 for testing. We use the tokenized sentences from the non-binary parse provided in the dataset and prepend each sentence with a "NULL" token. During training, each sentence was padded up to the maximum length of the batch for efficient training (the padding was explicitly masked out so as not to affect the objective/gradients). For efficient batching in TensorFlow, we semi-sorted the training data to first contain examples where both sentences had length less than 20, followed by those with length less than 50, and then the rest. This ensured that most training batches contained examples of similar length.</p><p>Embeddings: We use 300 dimensional GloVe embeddings <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Pennington et al., 2014)</ref> to represent words. Each embedding vector was normalized to have 2 norm of 1 and projected down to 200 dimensions, a number determined via hyperparameter tuning. Out-of-vocabulary (OOV) words are hashed to one of 100 random embeddings each initialized to mean 0 and standard deviation 1. All embeddings remain fixed during training, but the projection matrix is trained. All other parameter weights (hidden layers etc.) were initialized from random Gaussians with mean 0 and standard deviation 0.01.</p><p>Each hyperparameter setting was run on a single machine with 10 asynchronous gradient-update threads, using Adagrad <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Duchi et al., 2011)</ref> for optimization with the default initial accumulator value of 0.1. Dropout regularization <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Srivastava et al., 2014)</ref> was used for all ReLU layers, but not for the final linear layer. We additionally tuned the following hyperparameters and present their chosen values in   <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(4)</ref>, 1 dropout ratio (0.2) and learning rate (0.05-vanilla, 0.025-intra-attention). All settings were run for 50 million steps (each step indicates one batch) but model parameters were saved frequently as training progressed and we chose the model that did best on the development set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Results</head><p>Results in terms of 3-class accuracy are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>. Our vanilla approach achieves state-of-theart results with almost an order of magnitude fewer parameters than the LSTMN of <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Cheng et al. (2016)</ref>. Adding intra-sentence attention gives a considerable improvement of 0.5 percentage points over the existing state of the art. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> gives a breakdown of accuracy on the development set showing that most of our gains stem from neutral, while most losses come from contradiction pairs. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> shows some wins and losses. Examples A-C are cases where both variants of our approach are correct while both <ref type="bibr">SPINN-PI (Bowman et al., 2016)</ref> and the mLSTM <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Wang and Jiang, 2016)</ref> are incorrect. In the first two cases, both sentences contain phrases that are either identical or highly lexically related (e.g. "Two kids" and "ocean / beach") and our approach correctly favors neutral in these cases. In Example C, it is possible that relying on word-order may confuse SPINN-PI and the mLSTM due to how "fountain" is the object of a preposition in the first sentence but the subject of the second.</p><p>The second set of examples (D-F) are cases where 1 16 or 32 also work well and are a bit more stable. our vanilla approach is incorrect but mLSTM and SPINN-PI are correct. Example F requires sequential information and neither variant of our approach can predict the correct class. Examples D-E are interesting however, since they don't require word order information, yet intra-attention seems to help. We suspect this may be because the word embeddings are not fine-grained enough for the algorithm to conclude that "play/watch" is a contradiction, but intra-attention, by adding an extra layer of composition/nonlinearity to incorporate context, compensates for this. Finally, Examples G-I are cases that all methods get wrong. The first is actually representative of many examples in this category where there is one critical word that separates the two sentences (close vs open in this case) and goes unnoticed by the algorithms. Examples H requires inference about numbers and Example I needs sequence information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We presented a simple attention-based approach to natural language inference that is trivially parallelizable. The approach outperforms considerably more complex neural methods aiming for text understanding. Our results suggest that, at least for this task, pairwise comparisons are relatively more important than global sentence-level representations.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>CFigure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>) is an indicator vector encoding the label and C is the number of output classes. At test Pictoral overview of the approach, showing the Attend (left), Compare (center) and Aggregate (right) steps.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>F</head><label></label><figDesc>is evaluated O( ) times, giving a complexity of O( d 2 ). Each attention weight e ij requires one dot product, resulting in a complexity of O( 2 d).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>LSTMs. The complexity of an LSTM cell is O(d 2 ), resulting in a complexity of O( d 2 ) to encode the sentence. Adding attention as in Rocktäschel et al. (2016) increases this complexity to O( d 2 + 2 d). of our Approach. Application of a feed-forward network requires O(d 2 ) steps. Thus, the Compare and Aggregate steps have complexity O( d 2 ) and O(d 2 ) respectively. For the Attend step,</figDesc><table><row><cell>Lexicalized Classifier (Bowman et al., 2015) 300D LSTM RNN encoders (Bowman et al., 2016) Complexity Method 1024D pretrained GRU encoders</cell><cell>Train Acc Test Acc #Parameters 99.7 78.2 -83.9 80.6 3.0M</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Train/test accuracies on the SNLI dataset and number of parameters (excluding embeddings) for each approach.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Method</cell><cell>N</cell><cell>E</cell><cell>C</cell></row><row><cell>Bowman et al. (2016)</cell><cell cols="3">80.6 88.2 85.5</cell></row><row><cell>Wang and Jiang (2016)</cell><cell cols="3">81.6 91.6 87.4</cell></row><row><cell>Our approach (vanilla)</cell><cell cols="3">83.6 91.3 85.8</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Our approach w/ intra att. 83.7 92.1 86.7</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Breakdown of accuracy with respect to classes on SNLI development set. N=neutral, E=entailment, C=contradiction.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Example wins and losses compared to other approaches. DA (Decomposable Attention) refers to our approach while SPINN-PI and mLSTM are previously developed methods (seeTable 1).</figDesc><table><row><cell>parentheses: network size (2-layers, each with 200</cell></row><row><cell>neurons), batch size</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Slav Petrov, Tom Kwiatkowski, Yoon Kim, Erick Fonseca, Mark Neumann for useful discussion and Sam Bowman and Shuohang Wang for providing us their model outputs for error analysis.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TensorFlow: Large-scale machine learning on heterogeneous systems. Software available from tensorflow. org</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Abadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICLR</title>
		<editor>Andreas et al.2013] Jacob Andreas, Andreas Vlachos, and Stephen Clark</editor>
		<meeting>ICLR</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of ACL</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A large annotated corpus for learning natural language inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Markert2005] Johan</forename><surname>Bos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Bowman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>Bowman et al.2016</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HLT-NAACL</title>
		<meeting>HLT-NAACL<address><addrLine>Dan Goldwasser, Dan Roth</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of EMNLP</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long short-term memory-networks for machine reading</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paraphrase identification as probabilistic quasisynchronous recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Smith2009] Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP</title>
		<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive subgradient methods for online learning and stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Duchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2121" to="2159" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paraphrase-driven learning for open question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HLT-NAACL</title>
		<meeting>HLT-NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of AISTATS</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A discourse commitment-based framework for recognizing textual entailment</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<editor>and Bensley2007] Andrew Hickl and Jeremy Bensley</editor>
		<meeting>the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing. Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long short-term memory</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sepp Hochreiter and Jürgen Schmidhuber</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1735" to="1780" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convolutional neural network architectures for matching natural language sentences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Semantic theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerrold</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<publisher>Harper &amp; Row</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Handwritten digit recognition with a back-propagation network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lecun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IWCS</title>
		<editor>Bill MacCartney and Christopher D. Manning</editor>
		<meeting>the IWCS<address><addrLine>Trond</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Advances in NIPS. MacCartney et al.2006] Bill MacCartney</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A phrase-based alignment model for natural language inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>Grenager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL workshop on Empirical Modeling of Semantic Equivalence and Entailment</title>
		<meeting>the ACL workshop on Empirical Modeling of Semantic Equivalence and Entailment</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of EMNLP. [Marsi and Krahmer2005] Erwin Marsi and Emiel Krahmer</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language inference by tree-based convolution and heuristic matching</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>short papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GloVe: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Rocktäschel et al.2016] Tim Rocktäschel</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dropout: A simple way to prevent neural networks from overfitting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karl</forename><forename type="middle">Moritz</forename><surname>Grefenstette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomáš</forename><surname>Hermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phil</forename><surname>Kočiskỳ</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blunsom ; Nitish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Krizhevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>Srivastava et al.2014</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICLR</title>
		<meeting>ICLR</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1929" to="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Reasoning about entailment with neural attention</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Order-embeddings of images and language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johan</forename><surname>Van Benthem ; Ivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Vendrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kiros</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICLR</title>
		<meeting>ICLR</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>College Publications</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A brief history of natural logic</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning natural language inference with LSTM</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiang2016] Shuohang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ABCNN: Attentionbased convolutional neural network for modeling sentence pairs</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Transactions of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
