<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">An Integral Pose Regression System for the ECCV2018 PoseTrack Challenge</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Research</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chuankang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Zhejiang University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Research</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">An Integral Pose Regression System for the ECCV2018 PoseTrack Challenge</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2021-06-26T11:21+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>For the ECCV 2018 PoseTrack Challenge, we present a 3D human pose estimation system based mainly on the integral human pose regression method. We show a comprehensive ablation study to examine the key performance factors of the proposed system. Our system obtains 47mm MPJPE on the CHALL H80K test dataset, placing second in the ECCV2018 3D human pose estimation challenge. Code will be released to facilitate future work.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The ECCV2018 3D Human Pose Estimation Challenge evaluates proposed methods for estimating 3D key points of people from monocular RGB images. The challenge is based on the CHALL H80K subset of the popular Human3.6M <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2]</ref> benchmark. CHALL H80K contains 80K 3D human poses and corresponding images from 10 professional actors (6 male, 4 female) and 15 scenarios (discussion, smoking, taking photo, talking on the phone, etc.). Among them, 5 subjects (36K frames) are used for training, 2 subjects (20K frames) for validation and 4 subjects (24K frames) for testing. The images are captured in a controlled environment in which the subjects and background have a simple appearance. In CHALL H80K, only 3D pose ground-truth is provided, using the root (pelvis) joint as the origin, expressed in millimeters (mm). For evaluation, the mean per joint position error (MPJPE ) <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> metric is used.</p><p>Human pose estimation has been extensively studied <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref>. Recent years have seen significant progress on the problem due to advances in deep convolutional neural networks (CNNs). The best performing methods on 2D pose estimation are all detection-based <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. They generate a likelihood heat map for each joint and locate the joint as the point with the maximum likelihood in the map. Promising extensions of the heat map approach have been presented for 3D pose estimation <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Most recently, Sun et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> replaced the argmax post-processing with an integral formulation to tackle the quantization problem and enable end-to-end learning. This approach currently achieves the highest 3D pose estimation performance.</p><p>For the ECCV 2018 PoseTrack Challenge, we present a 3D human pose estimation system based mainly on the integral human pose regression [7] method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>arXiv:1809.06079v1 [cs.CV] 17 Sep 2018</head><p>Within the rules of the challenge, some external data is used in our system besides CHALL H80K. Specifically, 2D human pose data from MPII <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> and COCO <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> are used for both camera model estimation and 2D/3D mixed data training. COCO object bounding box data is used to train a person box detector for a two-stage top-down pose estimation paradigm similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref>. ImageNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref> classification data is employed for pre-training the backbone networks. No other external data is used. Our system obtains 47mm MPJPE on the CHALL H80K test dataset, placing second in the ECCV2018 3D human pose estimation challenge <ref type="bibr">[10]</ref>. Code 3 will be released to facilitate future work.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> provides an overview of our system. It contains three components. First, a person box detection component roughly localizes the person in the input RGB image. Second, a camera projection component is used to project 3D ground truth to the image coordinate system, as done in per-pixel/voxel classification based learning methods. These two components are used for data pre-processing. Third, the core CNN based learning component applies Integral Regression <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> to perform 3D human pose estimation.</p><p>Person Box Detection Instead of predicting the 3D key points from the original image directly, we follow a two-stage top-down paradigm similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref>.</p><p>First, a person box detector is used to roughly localize the person. Then, a normalized local image patch is generated by cropping the original image with the box and resizing it to a fixed image resolution. The normalized local image patches are used as the final inputs of the CNN model. Since much of the background area is detected and removed in this first stage, the accuracy of the following key point detection model can be greatly improved. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>, we obtain a 25.4% relative improvement (MPJPE decreases from 115.9mm to 86.5mm) by using the person box detector.</p><p>Camera Projection Model Following the detection based pose estimation paradigm, which is essentially a per pixel/voxel classification task, we first project the ground truth to the image coordinate system (in pixels). Since the CHALL H80K dataset provides the 3D ground truth only in mm, we assume a weak perspective camera projection model and then estimate the camera model parameters by matching the 2D projection of the 3D ground truth with a coarse 2D key points estimation result, which is obtained from a pre-trained 2D model using external 2D data (MPII).</p><p>At the testing phase, the camera model parameters are unknown. Hence, we are not able to recover the final 3D key points using camera back-projection. Instead, we scale the predicted 3D key points in pixels to conform to a particular average bone length to obtain the final prediction in mm. Different choices of bone length significantly affect the final performance, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. Not surprisingly, using the per-frame ground truth average bone length substantially outperforms using other average bone lengths, such as those computed from the validation or training sets. In real applications, it is possible for users to provide this personalized information to strengthen the system. In this challenge, however, bone length information is not given on the test dataset, which leaves us with using an average bone length estimated from a given dataset. In practice, we use Avg Train+Val bone length in all of our experiments.</p><p>Integral Regression Sun et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> recently presented a simple and effective integral regression method that unifies the heat map representation and joint regression approaches in a manner that preserves the merits of both. It replaces the non-differentiable argmax post-processing with the differentiable integral operation, thus allowing end-to-end training and producing continuous output to solve the quantization problem. Moreover, they generalize this approach to the 3D human pose estimation problem for the first time and achieve the state of the art result on the Human3.6M dataset.</p><p>We use the Integral Regression method to train our 3D human pose estimation model. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, several variants of Integral Regression are proposed and investigated according to different heat map loss types and joint loss types. In their experiments, L1 joint loss without heat map loss pre-training achieves the best performance for the 3D pose estimation problem. We adopt this variant in all of our experiments.</p><p>The 3D pose estimation performance can be significantly improved by adding abundant 2D pose data to the training <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr">11]</ref>. This is feasible because the integral formulation generates x, y, z predictions individually and maintains differentiability. In addition, our camera model estimation component projects 3D ground truth to the image coordinate system. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>, we get 28.1% relative improvement (MPJPE decreases from 86.5mm to 62.2mm) by using external MPII 2D pose data for mixed 2D/3D training.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head><p>Training ResNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[12]</ref> is adopted as the backbone network and is pre-trained on the ImageNet classification dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. A normal distribution with 1e-3 standard deviation is used to initialize the head network parameters as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> for integral regression. PyTorch <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[13]</ref> is used for implementation. Adam is employed for optimization. Data augmentation includes random translation (±2% of the image size), scale (±25%), rotation (±30 degrees) and flip. In all experiments, the base learning rate is 1e-4. It drops to 1e-6 when the loss on the validation set saturates. The training iterations proceed until performance on the validation set saturates. Four GPUs are utilized. The mini-batch size is 64, and batch-normalization <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[14]</ref> is used. For our ablation study, the CHALL H80K train and val datasets are used for training and evaluation, respectively. For the final challenge result on the CHALL H80K test dataset, both train and val datasets are used for training. Other training details are provided with the individual experiments. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows a comprehensive ablation study to examine the key performance factors of the proposed framework, including the two-stage paradigm using person box detection (25.4% relative improvement), and 2D and 3D mixed data training (28.1% relative improvement). Additionally, the effect of different training strategies including deeper backbone networks (1.6% relative improvement) and larger image resolution (4.4% relative improvement), together with testing strategies including flip testing (1.0% relative improvement) and model ensemble (2.8% relative improvement) are investigated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ablation Study</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Challenge Result</head><p>We use the best setting in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>, namely the last entry, to produce our final result on the CHALL H80K test dataset. Both train and val datasets are used for training. Our system obtains 47mm MPJPE, giving it second place in the ECCV2018 3D human pose estimation challenge [10]. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Overview of 3D pose estimation framework.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Effect of using different bone length at testing phase.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="5">Bone Length Type Per-frame Avg Val Avg Train Avg Train+Val</cell></row><row><cell>MPJPE(mm)</cell><cell>60.0</cell><cell>64.6</cell><cell>65.6</cell><cell>65.2</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Ablation study. All models are trained on CHALL H80K train dataset and evaluated on CHALL H80K val dataset.</figDesc><table><row><cell>description</cell><cell>box det. dataset</cell><cell cols="2">backbone patch size flip test ensemble MPJPE(mm)</cell></row><row><cell>original baseline</cell><cell>HM36</cell><cell>ResNet-50 -</cell><cell>115.9</cell></row><row><cell>+person box det.</cell><cell>HM36</cell><cell>ResNet-50 256*256</cell><cell>86.5 ↓25.4%</cell></row><row><cell>+MPII data</cell><cell>HM36+MPII</cell><cell>ResNet-50 256*256</cell><cell>62.2 ↓28.1%</cell></row><row><cell>+deeper</cell><cell>HM36+MPII</cell><cell>ResNet-152 256*256</cell><cell>61.2 ↓1.6%</cell></row><row><cell>+larger image</cell><cell>HM36+MPII</cell><cell>ResNet-152 288*384</cell><cell>58.5 ↓4.4%</cell></row><row><cell>+COCO data</cell><cell cols="2">HM36+MPII+COCO ResNet-152 288*384</cell><cell>57.5 ↓1.7%</cell></row><row><cell>+flip test</cell><cell cols="2">HM36+MPII+COCO ResNet-152 288*384</cell><cell>56.9 ↓1.0%</cell></row><row><cell>+model ensemble</cell><cell cols="2">HM36+MPII+COCO ResNet-152 288*384</cell><cell>55.3 ↓2.8%</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">https://github.com/JimmySuen/integral-human-pose</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent structured models for human pose estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ionescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sminchisescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computer Vision (ICCV), 2011 IEEE International Conference on</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2220" to="2227" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human3. 6m: Large scale datasets and predictive methods for 3d human sensing in natural environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ionescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Papava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Olaru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sminchisescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE transactions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1325" to="1339" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2d human pose estimation: New benchmark and state of the art analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Andriluka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Pishchulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Gehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schiele</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3686" to="3693" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Microsoft coco: Common objects in context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Belongie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hays</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Perona</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ramanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dollár</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Zitnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European conference on computer vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="740" to="755" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">: Mpii Leader</forename><surname>Board</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://human-pose.mpi-inf.mpg.de" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Coarse-to-fine volumetric prediction for single-image 3d human pose</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pavlakos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Derpanis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Daniilidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1611.07828</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1711.08229</idno>
		<title level="m">Integral human pose regression</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Towards accurate multi-person pose estimation in the wild</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Papandreou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kanazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Toshev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bregler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1701.01779</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Imagenet: A large-scale hierarchical image database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fei-Fei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://vision.imar.ro/human3.6m/ranking.php11" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="255" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep residual learning for image recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="770" to="778" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatic differentiation in pytorch</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Paszke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chintala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Chanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Devito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Desmaison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Antiga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ioffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Szegedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1502.03167</idno>
		<title level="m">Batch normalization: Accelerating deep network training by reducing internal covariate shift</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
