<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">AI-CARGO: A Data-Driven Air-Cargo Revenue Management System</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><forename type="middle">Giovanni</forename><surname>Rizzo</surname></persName>
							<email>strizzo@hbku.edu.qa</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Qatar Computing Research Institute (QCRI) Doha</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="QA">Qatar</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Lucas</surname></persName>
							<email>jlucas@hbku.edu.qa</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Qatar Computing Research Institute (QCRI) Doha</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="QA">Qatar</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zoi</forename><surname>Kaoudi</surname></persName>
							<email>zkaoudi@hbku.edu.qa</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Qatar Computing Research Institute (QCRI) Doha</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="QA">Qatar</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jorge-Arnulfo</forename><surname>Quiane-Ruiz</surname></persName>
							<email>jquianeruiz@hbku.edu.qa</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Qatar Computing Research Institute (QCRI) Doha</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="QA">Qatar</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjay</forename><surname>Chawla</surname></persName>
							<email>schawla@hbku.edu.qa</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Qatar Computing Research Institute (QCRI) Doha</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="QA">Qatar</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">AI-CARGO: A Data-Driven Air-Cargo Revenue Management System</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2021-06-25T19:44+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We propose AI-CARGO, a revenue management system for aircargo that combines machine learning prediction with decisionmaking using mathematical optimization methods. AI-CARGO addresses a problem that is unique to the air-cargo business, namely the wide discrepancy between the quantity (weight or volume) that a shipper will book and the actual received amount at departure time by the airline. The discrepancy results in sub-optimal and inefficient behavior by both the shipper and the airline resulting in overall loss of potential revenue for the airline. AI-CARGO also includes a data cleaning component to deal with the heterogeneous forms in which booking data is transmitted to the airline cargo system. AI-CARGO is deployed in the production environment of a large commercial airline company. We have validated the benefits of AI-CARGO using real and synthetic datasets. Especially, we have carried out simulations using dynamic programming techniques to elicit the impact on offloading costs and revenue generation of our proposed system. Our results suggest that combining prediction within a decision-making framework can help dramatically to reduce offloading costs and optimize revenue generation.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>The revenue of commercial airlines is primarily derived from sales of passenger tickets and cargo (freight) shipments. While most modern airlines have implemented sophisticated data-driven passenger revenue management systems, for cargo the situation is different. The air-cargo ecosystem is complex and involves several players including shippers, freight forwarders, airline-and end-customers. Overall, there are five fundamental differences between passenger and cargo revenue management <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>[4] <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>:</p><p>(1) In the case of passenger revenue, the unit of sale is an airline seat, which is static. However, in the case of cargo, there is substantial variability in both volume and weight of cargo shipments. Furthermore, the revenue from a cargo shipment often depends on the nature of the cargo. For example, perishable and non-perishable shipments generate different marginal revenues. This makes the unit of sale in cargo highly dynamic.</p><p>(2) A large chunk of air cargo capacity is pre-booked by freight forwarders who tend to overbook and release capacity closer to the date of departure. The ecosystem of air-cargo management is such that there is no penalty for overbooking. Additionally, some portion of cargo space is also reserved for mail and passenger baggage. Thus, the effective capacity available for cargo is called the "free sale", which can vary up to departure day.</p><p>(3) For cargo shipments what matters is the source and destination. How the cargo is routed from source to destination is less of a bkvol [Booked volume] rcsvol [Received volume] <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: The x-axis is booked volume (bkvol). The y-axis is received vol (rcsvol). For confidentiality reason, the axis range is obfuscated.</p><p>concern as long as it reaches on time. Rerouting though has ancillary cost as the shipment has to be stored in a warehouse. (4) A unique aspect of the air-cargo ecosystem is that there is often a substantial discrepancy between the space booked by a shipping agent (in terms of volume and weight) for a particular item and the actual quantity that arrives on or just before the departure day. Furthermore, it is a convention in the business that airlines will not charge for the discrepancy, which makes it very difficult for airlines to manage their perishable capacity. This creates an inefficiency in the market where agents tend to book excess capacity. Therefore, airlines tend to overbook flights under the assumption that the quantity that will arrive will be less than what was booked. Overbooking often leads to offloading, which has cost in terms of storage and rerouting. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(5)</ref> It is well known that cargo capacity is often volume-constrained, i.e., the aircraft will reach volume capacity before it reaches weight capacity. However, this makes things even harder because the volume measurements are less accurate than the weight ones. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> illustrates this fact.</p><p>Due to these major differences, air-cargo business requires not only to accurately predict the quantity (weight and volume) of an item that will be tendered but also to make decisions on whether to accept or reject a booking for a certain flight. This will enable the airline to greatly increase the efficiency of capacity utilization. However, prediction and decision-making in an air-cargo setting is non-trivial because of three main reasons. First, the quality of cargo booking data varies a lot. Shippers often send information using text messages, emails, spreadsheets, voice calls, or even intermediate their bookings through freight forwarders. Second, there are no good features for predicting the final quantity that will be received. Employees working in the cargo revenue teams use their intuition to decide whether to accept a shipment for a flight or to reroute through another flight. Third, offloading and rerouting cargo incur high costs in terms of storage and rerouting, which somehow constraints the decision-making.</p><p>We present the AI-CARGO system that deals with the above challenges. Although the use of formal decision-making is well established in the revenue management community <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, AI-CARGO is the first work that puts all pieces together to provide a complete pipeline for the air-cargo revenue management problem: given an incoming booking it (i) identifies if there might exist a substantial difference between the booked volume and the one that might be tendered, (ii) predicts the volume that will be tendered, and (iii) considers such a volume prediction to make an acceptance/rejection suggestion. AI-CARGO is currently deployed in production in a large airline company 1 . In particular, after surveying related work in Section 2, we make the following contributions in Section 3:</p><p>(1) We introduce a unique data cleaning module using the concept of disguised missing values (DMVs). The detection of DMVs significantly improves the overall quality of the prediction. (Section 3.1) (2) We propose to use Gradient Boosting Machines (GBMs) to build a volume prediction model that reduces the bias and the variance at the flight level. Our model takes into account whether a booking might contain a DMV or not to increase the quality of the prediction. (Section 3.2) (3) We model air-cargo revenue management as a prediction-driven sequential and stochastic optimization problem, where the state (total volume) is realized at departure time. This model tightly integrates the above prediction model in order to make more reliable decisions. (Section 3.3) (4) We evaluate the AI-CARGO using both synthetic and real data taken from the airline company. We demonstrate that our prediction-based decision-making technique helps the airline company to increase the total revenue and decrease the offloading cost. (Section 4)</p><p>We conclude this paper with a discussion, some lessons learned from the project, and future work in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORK</head><p>To the best of our knowledge AI-CARGO is the first known cargo revenue management system which combines machine learning and mathematical optimization. We overview related work in these subareas.</p><p>The discipline of Revenue Management (RM) is an advanced and well developed topic within the Operations Research (OR) community. It has roots in the airline industry and has now expanded in other areas, including hotels and tourism <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The initial focus in the airline industry was primarily on passenger RM, in particular how to price passenger seats in order to maximize revenue <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. A strand of relevant work that has appeared in the data mining literature is the problem of determining overbooking rate, forecasting the number of no-shows per flight, i.e., the percentage of bookings <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> We omit the company name for confidentiality reasons. that were made but did not show up by departure time <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13]</ref>. Noshows are a common problem in air-cargo too and several works have proposed solutions <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17]</ref>.</p><p>While RM for passenger seats is now a well developed area, the same is not true for cargo management. The first research overview of issues surrounding air cargo revenue management were introduced in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. Since then the research literature has seen a steady growth with works including <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>. Our work closely follows the decision making paradigm introduced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> for modeling both volume and weight aspects of bookings in air-cargo RM. Our innovation is that we integrate machine learning prediction into the decision making process.</p><p>Decision making with machine learning can also fall under the umbrella of reinforcement learning (RL) <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. However, much of the focus in RL is on model-free approaches and on using function approximation for overcoming the curse of dimensionality phenomenon that is ubiquitous in sequential learning paradigms <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22]</ref>.</p><p>The air cargo data that airlines collect is replete with errors because of the nature of the business. Shippers coordinate with freight forwarders and airlines using various means including email, phone calls, SMS and this increases the possibility of data errors. Data cleaning, data curation and preparation is a very developed area within the database community <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref> and there is tremendous potential to put these techniques into practice in the air cargo industry. In order to integrate fine-grained predictive modeling we had to resort to various data cleaning approaches. A particular data quality problem we dealt with is Disguised Missing Values (DMVs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19]</ref>, where users instead of providing a NaN for unknown values use arbitrary yet valid data values. The difference in our case is that DMVs are contextualized and conditioned, i.e., we only want to measure the impact of DMVs on the prediction of the final received volume.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">PROPOSED SYSTEM: AI-CARGO</head><p>AI-CARGO has three components as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: the (i) Disguised Missing Value (DMV) Detector, (ii) Cargo Predictor, and (iii) Decision-Maker. Given an incoming booking, the DMV Detector checks whether the booking has a DMV or not by consulting a directory of possible DMVs. Then, the Cargo Predictor gets as input the booking from the DMV Detector (i.e., the booking with a DMV indicator), extracts the relevant features from the booking (including the DMV indicator), and predicts the volume expected to be tendered by the customer. At the end of the pipeline, the Decision-Maker gets the incoming booking with the predicted volume that will be tendered and takes a decision whether to accept or not the booking via a stochastic dynamic program. We detail each of these steps in the following three sections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Detecting DMVs</head><p>The unique nature of the entire air-cargo ecosystem results in several practices that make bookings' values, e.g., booked volume (bkvol), not very reliable. For instance, customers send booking information via SMSs, emails, text files, or even phone calls, which also causes a natural lag between the time a customer creates the booking and the time the booking is actually reflected in the central cargo system.  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: The AI-CARGO system consists of three modules: (i) a disguised missing value detector, a prediction component to estimate rcsvol and a decision-making rule to decide which bookings to accept in order to maximize expected revenue.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Disguised Missing Value Detector Cargo Predictor Decision-Maker</head><p>An important observation we made is that customers often send arbitrary but fixed values as proxies for NaN. That is, when a customer first books an item the exact volume (or weight) that will be delivered is often not known. However, instead of setting bkvol to NaN, customers will often choose a fixed but arbitrary number, which will have no bearing on the received volume rcsvol. In the data cleaning literature, these proxy values are often called Disguised Missing Values (DMVs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19]</ref>. For example, consider a set of six bookings whose bkvol was 10.23 and rcsvol were all different: 5.1, 2.8, 13.3, 26.4, 26.4, and 2.8. Unless other features can explain the diverse range of values taken by rcsvol, 10.23 is very likely to be a DMV.</p><p>Detection of DMVs is important as they can have a substantial impact on the prediction model. To see how a DMV can effect prediction, consider the case of a linear regression model in a single dimension. Suppose a linear model y = wx is learnt from examples</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(x i , y i ) n i=1 . Then, it is well known that w = n i=1 x i y i n i=1 x 2 i</formula><p>Now suppose x dmv and a associated set of values {y 1 , y 2 , . . . , y m } are added to the training set. Let w new be the new updated parameter, which will be:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">w new = n i=1 x i y i + x dmv m j=1 y j n i=1 x 2 i + mx 2 dmv = w + x dmv m j=1 y j n i =1 x 2 i 1 + mx 2 dmv n i =1 x 2 i</formula><p>Depending upon the value of m i y j , the model might or might not be impacted by x dmv . For instance, if m j=1 y j = mwx dmv , then substituting in the above equation shows that w new = w and the DMV has no impact on the model. However, if 1 m i= y j deviates significantly from the straight line y = wx, the impact of x dmv can clearly be large.</p><p>We thus use the mean distance and entropy information to compute two features for each bkvol in order to detect DMVs. For each distinct bkvol, denoted as u i , let V i = {v i,1 , . . . , v i,n i } be the set of rcsvols that appear in the data. Then, we define д 1 to quantify how much the average of rcsvols deviates from the associated bkvol. Formally,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">д 1 (u i ) = 1 n i n i k =1 v i,k − u i 2</formula><p>Then we redefine a second feature д 2 to capture the entropy of the set V i . The higher the entropy the more likely that u i is a DMV. We normalize the entropy score in order to upperbound it at one. If V i consists of K distinct elements, then let V i,k be the the k-th bucket</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">of V i and define p k = |V i,k | |V i | .</formula><p>We thus define д 2 as</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">д 2 (u i ) = − K k =1 p k log p k log n i</formula><p>When д 1 and д 2 are above some threshold it means that the bkvol is a DMV. Using features д 1 and д 2 , we offline create the DMVs directory illustrated in the left-bottom part of <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. In more detail, from our historical booking data, we map every frequent 2 distinct value into a two-dimensional feature space and visually browse the space to set a cutoff threshold. We then denote every bkvol value that crosses the threshold as DMV and put it into a DMVs directory. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref> shows an example of the two-dimensional DMV space, where the x-axis is д 1 and the y-axis is д 2 , and highlights several known examples of DMVs, confirmed by domain experts. Our goal is to let the algorithm learn that if a booking contains a bkvol that   is likely to be a DMV, the, it should deemphasizes the bkvol in the prediction of rcsvol. This approach also makes it easier to handle DMVs in a production environment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Predicting Cargo Volume</head><p>Given an incoming booking with its DMV flag, AI-CARGO proceeds to predict rcsvol (i.e., the received volume by departure time) for the given booking, as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. To do so we need to offline build a model using historical data as illustrated in the middle-bottom of <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. We thus need to (i) decide on the features and (ii) decide on the algorithm to use. Predicting rcsvol is quite challenging as the bkvol is usually quite different from rcsvol. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> illustrates this difficulty. The vertical lines provide a clear indication that we need other features besides bkvol to have any chance of accurately predicting rcsvol. We thus experimented with extracting different feature combinations until we settled on a set that provides a good compromise between model complexity and accuracy. More formally, given a sample of bookings, we formed a feature set X and mapped each booking i as an element x i ∈ X and the rcsvol as y i ∈ R + . The prediction task then becomes a regression problem, where we have to learn a function f θ : X → R + <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5</ref> shows the set of features we use, which were the most important ones, for predicting rcsvol:</p><p>• Days until departure (DAYS): The most important feature by far is the number of days between the booking time and the departure time. Bookings closer to the departure time tend to be more accurate. In fact, bookings that are timestamped several days before departure day tend to show a clear pattern of overbooking from the customer side (and hence of using DMVs). It is natural for shippers to overbook as in the air-cargo business there is no penalty for that. • Booked weight (BKWT): Contrary to bkvol, which usually tends to be a DMV, bkwt is a valuable information. This is because shipping agents have a much more accurate information of bkwt as they have access to high quality weighing machines. Indeed, instruments for accurately measuring volume are not that widespread <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">21]</ref>. Thus, being easier to measure, bkwt is on average more precise.</p><p>• Number of pieces (PIECES): A shipment may consist of a number of equal units. Diagonal lines in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> suggest that bookings frequently differ from the tendered shipments in the number of pieces rather than in their volume. Thus, knowing the number of pieces is useful in predicting possible outcomes at receiving time. For example, if two pieces where booked for a bkvol of 12m 3 , with volume for each piece of 6m <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3</ref> , it is unlikely that a single piece will be split and the rcsvol will become 4m 3 . It is in fact much more likely that it may become 6m 3 , 18m 3 , or 24m 3 . • Booked volume (BKVOL): We observed that, despite of DMVs, the booked volume, bkvol, is still an important feature for predicting rcsvol. This is because when bkvol is not a DMV, it tends to be precise. • Shipment code (SHC): This is a set of codes to instruct how the shipment must be handled, e.g., live animals or perishables. This feature ended up being important as it specifies over (or complements the) the product type explained here below. We encode the shipment code feature as a binary vector with one element for each shipment code (one-hot encoding). • Product type (PRODUCT): We observed that the patterns in rcsvol vary with different product type. In theory product type should be a highly informative feature, but we observed that the distribution of product types is skewed. • DMV Flag (DMV): Because DMVs are frequent and must be dealt within a production environment, we decided not to remove DMV data from the training set. At the same time, giving their negative impact in the prediction, it is important to know if a booking has a DMV for bkvol. For this reason, we provide a flag, which is obtained by the DMV Detector based on historical data. • Destination (DEST): We also consider the destination as a feature, even if the destination alone is a weak predictor for rcsvol. This is because in conjunction with product type it becomes possible to elicit subtypes within products and thus reduce the variance. • Origin (ORIG): The origin airport of the shipment. This feature allows capturing the average behavior of booking agents from each location.</p><p>We also experimented with using both random forests (RFs) and gradient boosting machines (GBMs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> for building the model. GBMs are ensemble methods and are known to perform well "out of the box". They can also easily handle a mixture of datatypes including numeric and categorical data. Recall that for a prediction problem the error can be decomposed into a sum of bias and variance <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. On the one hand, RFs reduce the error by reducing variance as they combine independently generated deep trees on bootstrapped samples. GBMs, on the other hand, reduce the bias by building shallow trees in a sequential manner, where each subsequent tree is trained by using the dependent variable as the residuals of the previous one. In our case, even though we trained the model to make predictions at the booking level, we were primarily interested in making flight level predictions, which are an aggregation of booking level predictions. Therefore, while GBM predictions fluctuate more and individual predictions are further from the actual value, the differences cancel each other out at the flight level, that is, the aggregation of bookings at the flight level will automatically result in variance reduction. This has been confirmed by evaluating both models for booking level and flight level prediction. On the booking level, the variance in GBM predictions is more than 5 times higher than RF predictions. However, at the flight level, the mean absolute error of RF is 87.1% higher than the GBM error. For these reasons, in our production deployment we have used GBMs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Decision Making</head><p>Once a booking is DMV-tagged and its bkvol is predicted, the Decision-Maker creates an acceptance/rejection suggestion for the given booking. Before digging in how it does so, let us first state what the problem of decision making in the context of airline cargo booking is. For any flight, capacity is a perishable quantity, i.e., once the flight takes-off the capacity is lost. Therefore, an airline wants to accept bookings that will maximize revenue. The problem can be seen as a generalization of the classic Knapsack problem with two caveats: (i) cargo bookings appear over time and the exact volume (weight) of the shipment becomes available only at departure time. We, thus, model this problem as a stochastic dynamic program <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>. We start by defining a state vector x = (x 1 , . . . , x m ). Each x i is the number of items of type i assigned to a flight. A type is a pre-defined category, like fresh food or pharma. The state x evolves with time t. We define the value function V F (x, t) as the expected revenue from the flight given that at time t the flight is in state x. We label departure day as time t = 0 and the booking horizon extends up to time t = T . Thus, time flows backwards. We model a single flight whose volume capacity k v 3 is fixed and known. We also discretize time and in each time bin t the probability of an item i being received for a booking is p i,t . We assume that at each time step only one shipment can arrive for booking. We define p 0,t as 1 − m i=1 p(i, t) as the probability that no booking will show up in time period t. In practice, when an agent books an item of type i, it is accompanied by a booked volume bkvol i . When the item finally arrives for shipment the received volume is rcsvol i . The revenue received from the item i is R(rcsvol i ), where R() is typically an increasing and concave function of volume. Recall that during booking time the airline only knows bkvol i and not rcsvol i . Thus, it is common to make a decision about whether to accept or reject a booking based on the average volume of type i,v i .</p><p>We can now define the value function V F (x, t) as a recursive function (Bellman's Equation) in order to maximize the overall expected revenue <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">V F (x, t) = m i=1 p i,t max{R(v i ) + V F (x + e i , t − 1), V F (x, t − 1)} + p 0,t V F ((x, t − 1)), t = 1, 2, . . . ,T V F (x, 0) = −h v m i=1 x ivi − k v +</formula><p>where [a] + = max{a, 0}. We now explain the above recursive equation. When the state is x at a given time t then V F (x, t) is the expected revenue over the full time horizon of the booking. At time step t, the probability of a shipment of type i arriving is p i,t . If the booking is accepted then the state will transition to x + e i , where e i is the one-hot binary vector with a 1 at the i-th location. By accepting the booking, the expected revenue will be R(v i ). However, the booking of item i will only be accepted if the revenue</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">R(v i ) + V F (x + e i , t − 1)</formula><p>is greater than not accepting the booking and transitioning one step towards departure while staying in the same state, i.e., V F (x, t −1). At time t = 0 and in state x, the V F (x, 0) captures the cost of off-loading, which is proportional (h v ) to the total expected volume i x ivi minus the capacity k v . For example, if the expected volume is 100 units and the capacity k v is 50, then the off-loading cost is −50h v . Having defined the value function V F (x, t), the decision rule (D1V) at each time step t, which determines whether to accept or reject an incoming shipment of type i is given as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">D1V : R(v i ) + V F (x + e i , t − 1) &gt; V F (x, t − 1)</formula><p>However, we can integrate prediction in the decision-making by modifying the decision rule. For example, suppose our predictive function is f θ (as defined in Section 3.2 4 ), i.e., given a booked volume bkvol i of type i, f θ (bkvol i ) is the predicted received volume (rcsvol i ). We, then, have a new decision rule (D2V) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">D2V : R(f θ (bkvol i )) + V F (x + e i , t − 1) &gt; V F (x, t − 1)</formula><p>The Curse of Dimensionality: It is worth noting that the construction of V F (x, t) suffers from the well-known curse of dimensionality of dynamic programming <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>. For example, suppose there are m items and the number of time periods is T . Then, the size of the state space is exponential in m 5 . An approximate solution to escape the exponential blow-up is to use aggregate x = i x ivi . This makes the state space one-dimensional scalar-valued, instead of vector-valued, of maximum size. This state space is bounded by M × T , where M is the maximum possible volume booked for any type. The construction of V F (x, t) becomes considerably simplified and the decision rule D2V then becomes D2S:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">D2S : R(f θ (bkvol i )) + V F (x + f θ (bkvol i ), t − 1) &gt; V F (x, t − 1)</formula><p>Illustrative Example 1: To illustrate how dynamic programming is used to form the V F function, we will work through a simple scenario shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref>. We assume there are two shipment types: type1 and type2. Both types can arrive for a booking with a probability of 0.4 in any time step and the probability that no shipment will arrive for any <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4</ref> We have overloaded the f θ signature to emphasize the role of bkvol 5 It is S (T , m), Stirling number of second kind booking is 0.2. The revenue for type1 is 1 and for type2 is 2, while the volume for both types is fixed at 1 unit. Recall that time is labeled in a reverse order, i.e., departure time is 0 and booking horizon extends up to time t = 4. To compute the value function V F , we proceed backwards for each state x. Now the state is a twodimensional vector x = (x 1 , x 2 ), where x 1 and x 2 are the number of bookings of type1 and type2 respectively. However, we collapse</p><p>x into x = x 1v1 + x 2v2 = x 1 + x 2 as we have assume that the volume booked has a value of 1. The different values of x are shown as rows in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 6</ref>. We first have to populate the first column of <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">For example, V F (0, 0) = − max(0 − k v , 0) = 0 as k v = 2 and V F (3, 0) = − max(3 − 2, 0) = −1.</formula><p>As an example, we compute V F (1, 2).</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">V F (1, 2) =0.4 max(1 + V F (2, 1), V F (1, 1)) + 0.4 * max(2 + V F (2, 1), V F (1, 1) + 0.2 * V F (1, 1) =0.4 * (1 + 0.4) + 0.4 * (2 + 0.4) + 0.2 * 1.2 =1.76 ≈ 1.8</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">RESULTS</head><p>We first evaluate our proposed AI-CARGO system in terms of revenue and costs. We then show an in-depth analysis of our techniques. Note that the prediction module of AI-CARGO has been deployed in a large international airline company 6 and the results reported are from the production environment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Dataset</head><p>We obtained a real dataset spanning two years (June 2016-August 2018) of booking records from the cargo IT team of the airline company. Each booking record consists of several attributes including, booking date, origin, destination, agent, booking volume (bkvol), product type, received date, departure datetime, and received vol (rcsvol). We use this dataset to detect the DMVs and build the ML model for predicting rcsvol using all other attributes. As we do not have real information on the revenue and offload costs, we create simulated data as proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> to evaluate our decision making approach. To create the simulations from the real dataset, we compute the probabilities of the product types from the real dataset: For each type i, we compute</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">p i = # bookings with product i # total bookings</formula><p>The related probabilities of the ten most frequent product types are shown in the top <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>. We observe that the product type frequencies are skewed, with the most frequent product type with  For the sake of simplicity and to replicate the same formulation as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, we compute a single probability for 6 different intervals of time steps, resulting in 10 time steps per interval. For each interval we take the average of the 10 single time steps that belong to this interval. The results are shown in the bottom <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>. Given p i the probability of an incoming type i at any time, and p t the probability of getting any type of booking at time t, the probability of getting a booking of product type i at time t is p i,t = p i p t .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">AI-CARGO Revenue Analysis</head><p>We first evaluate our proposed AI-CARGO system in terms of revenue benefits and offload costs. Using the data described above we simulate the whole AI-CARGO system pipeline including data cleaning, prediction, and decision-making as follows. First, we compute the V F (x, t) table by using the entire dataset and taking the average booking volume for each time step. Then, we consider two different test cases in order to evaluate the power of our system by combing predictive modeling with decision making:</p><p>(1) BKD to RCS: no prediction is made. The decision to whether accept or reject an incoming booking by applying DS2 is based on the reported bkvol, i.e., f θ (bv i ) = bv i . Final offloading cost is then calculated based on the rcsvol.</p><p>(2) PRED to RCS: The received booking is processed for DMV identification and the resulting feature vector is used to output a prediction f θ (bv i ) using our prediction model. The decision to accept or reject an incoming shipment using D2S is based on this predicted volume.</p><p>At each time step we draw bookings from the dataset following the probabilities of <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref> and apply the decision rule D2S. <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> shows the results on eleven different flight capacities k v and ten thousand flights each, for a total of 220 thousand flights.</p><p>The left-hand side graph of <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> clearly shows that for various capacity constraints (k v ) the offloading cost is lower almost by a factor of ten and with a much lower standard deviation. This suggests that using predictions instead of booked volume (bkvol) not only reduces the offloading cost but adds substantial amount of certainty into the whole air cargo booking process. In the right-hand side graph of <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>, we show the final revenue, i.e., after subtracting the offloading costs, for various flight capacity constraints. We observe that the revenue increases when using a predicted booked volume, albeit slightly, indicating that the decision function selected better-value shipments during the booking time horizon. Still the standard deviation of the revenue is lower when using the predictions. Note that, the way the decision making process is designed, excess overbooking incurs negative penalty (i.e., offloading), while underbooking results to zero penalty (i.e., V F (x, 0) is zero when the total volume is less than the flight capacity). It is thus more beneficial to reduce the risk of offloading by using a predictive model that overpredicts leading to less shipments getting accepted. This is a design choice that is driven by business objectives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">In-depth analysis</head><p>We now evaluate the main two components of our system independently: the predictive model and the decision making process. Predictive model: We first evaluate our predictor module. For our evaluation, we use 3-fold cross-validation on the full real dataset of two years cargo bookings. We make a prediction on each single booking and we evaluate the aggregated flight leg predicted volume vs. the flight-leg received volume. For this reason, we implemented cross-validation so that all the bookings from the same flight leg are kept in the same split. Based on grid-search results, we set the XGBoost regressor with 0.9 subsample ratio of columns for each split, 300 estimators, a maximum tree depth of 20 and a learning rate of 0.05. All other parameters are set as default.  We use the mean relative absolute error on our predictive model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">e = 1 N N 1 |r csvol i −f θ (bkvol i ) | r csvol i</formula><p>. The average error on the entire historical data is 7.8%. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 8</ref> shows that the prediction error is under 5% in almost half of the flights, while it is under 10% for the 74.8% of the flights. Similar results are shown in the table at the top right of the figure. We observe that by using the predictive model instead of the actual booked volume values we have a greater number of flights that have a small error. It is also noteworthy that our prediction error is lower for higher capacity flights, where it has the biggest impact. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 3</ref> shows the benefits of the prediction on the shipment level for the 10 most frequent product types. Specifically, it shows the decrease in percentage of the prediction error (predicted rcsvol vs. actual rcsvol) from the booking error (original booked volume vs. actual rcsvol). The predicted volume has decreased the error considerably for 9 out of the 10 product types. The increase in error for product type9 is on a very rare product type and, thus, there are not enough data to train the model. However, as it is rare it does not influence the total flight-leg predicted volume. Decision Making: We now evaluate our decision making module in isolation from the prediction module. This means that in this experiment we do not use predictions but the decision is made based on the mean valuev i and offloading is determined based on the random number generated by a lognormal distribution, which leads to rule D1S :</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">R(v i ) + V F (x +v i , t − 1) &gt; V F (x, t − 1)</formula><p>. We evaluate D1S by comparing it with a first-come first-served (FCFS) policy. In the FCFS policy, every incoming booking is accepted until the capacity runs out. FCFS is a greedy strategy in the sense that it will accept immediate revenue instead of waiting for a potential booking from which more revenue can be made. In an ideal setting, if the booking value was equal to the received value, FCFS will not incur any offloading costs. However, since the two values are rarely the same, the natural advantage of FCFS is not realized and the experiments bear that out. Note We compare the D1S and the FCFS strategy on the simulated data set from <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Using the mean volume µ k for each product k of the 24 categories and the related probability distributions, we recreate synthetic data for 10 thousand different simulations and run the two different policies. Mean value is used as booked volume, while the received volume is drawn from a lognormal distribution with mean equal to the booked volume and variance (θ µ k ) 2 . Results in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 4</ref> show how D1S has a benefit not only for the expected revenue but also the final one, after the offloading cost is deducted. As the variance increases, offloading increases and revenue decreases which suggests that our predictive approach has potential in better handling the booking decision making process, as we showed in the previous section.   <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> provides the last 16 steps in the booking horizon for one of the flight simulation. In particular, it shows how in practice the decision rule D1S keeps overbooking if the revenue rate is advantageous, while rejecting the less profitable shipments once the capacity is reached. This leads to the accumulation of offloading cost with the ultimate goal of maximizing the revenue.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DISCUSSION AND FUTURE WORK</head><p>In this paper we have described the components of AI-CARGO, an intelligent and data-driven air-cargo revenue management system. AI-CARGO was developed in conjunction with a large commercial airliner over a two year period. We summarize some of our lessons learned from the project and suggest directions for future work.</p><p>The project started as a classical data science project with the stated objective of predicting the received weight (rcswt) and received volume (rcsvol) of air-cargo bookings. We later narrowed it to predicting rcsvol as it turned out that most flights are volume constrained, i.e., they run out of volume space before weight capacity. However, overtime, we realized that prediction per-se cannot be carried out in isolation. We have to analyze the upstream sources of data and understand how the data was being generated. Closer analysis led us to conclude that the use of disguised missing values (DMVs) was prolific in the air-cargo ecosystem and a solution was required to detect DMVs and obviate their impact on the prediction task. We also had to get a better understanding of how the outcome of the prediction task will be consumed by end users for decision making. This led us to formulate the prediction-driven revenue optimization problem. Our general conclusion is that in order to make real and tangible impact, data science techniques have to be situated and combined with an overall objective. For future work we plan to extend the AI-CARGO system so that it can be used by shippers and freight-forwarders and not just the RM teams within an airline.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>6</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>DMVs identified by the DMV score method</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :Figure 5 :</head><label>45</label><figDesc>sv ol = bk vo l Received volume (rcsvol) rc sv o l = 2 · b k v o l r c s v o l = 3 · b k v o l rc sv o l = 1 .5 · b kv o l rc s v o l = 2 .5 · b k v o l Booked volume (bkvol) Values of bkvol and related rcsvol in shipments from historical data for a given range of bkvol. Circled in green are vertical patterns that are evidently disguised missing values. Features importance. For categorical features, such as product, the value of the category with the maximum importance is shown.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>The Value Function (VF) corresponding to Example 1. Each cell corresponds to the revenue that will be accrued starting from state x at time t. Note the cell values are computed using backward induction as time is going backwards.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Time period 1 Figure 7 :</head><label>17</label><figDesc>Offloading cost and the revenue generated for varying levels of capacity k v a probability of 0.856. Then, we split the booking horizon into 60 equal time steps and we compute the probability of a booking arriving at time step t as p t = # shipments at time t # shipments in dataset</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Prediction error for flight legs in test splits. Each data point is a flight leg. Below each dotted line are all the flights with an error below the respective percentage.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Last 16 time steps in the booking horizon of one flight simulation, showing current cargo load and decision for the two policies.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Historical Booking Data DMVs Directorybooking accept or reject Booking Sources ONLINE OFFLINE Decision Table</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>bki,</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>bki</cell><cell>bki, dmv</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>pred. vol.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>isDMV( )</cell><cell>true/false</cell><cell>bki[ ]</cell><cell>predicted volume</cell><cell>getVFval ( )</cell><cell>VF value</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ML</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Model</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">entropy &gt; Te</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mean_distance &gt; Td</cell><cell>train( )</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>build( )</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">compute( )</cell><cell cols="2">Revenue and Volume Statistics</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Sample cargo characteristics</figDesc><table><row><cell>type1 type2</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The top table shows the probabilities (p i ) of making a booking for a product type i. The bottom table shows the probabilities (p t ) of a booking arriving in a time period t.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="11">Product type Type1 Type2 Type3 Type4 Type5 Type6 Type7 Type8 Type9 Type10</cell></row><row><cell>p i</cell><cell>0.856</cell><cell>0.042</cell><cell>0.036</cell><cell>0.035</cell><cell>0.012</cell><cell>0.007</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>0.003</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.002</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Average error decrease for each product type, at booking level, in production environment.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Product type % of booking</cell><cell>% error decrease from bkvol</cell></row><row><cell>Type1</cell><cell>73.3%</cell><cell>-33.4%</cell></row><row><cell>Type2</cell><cell>10.1%</cell><cell>-38.3%</cell></row><row><cell>Type3</cell><cell>3.7%</cell><cell>-61.9%</cell></row><row><cell>Type4</cell><cell>3.5%</cell><cell>-66.9%</cell></row><row><cell>Type5</cell><cell>3.1%</cell><cell>-34.1%</cell></row><row><cell>Type6</cell><cell>2.7%</cell><cell>-7.2%</cell></row><row><cell>Type7</cell><cell>1.4%</cell><cell>-43.9%</cell></row><row><cell>Type8</cell><cell>0.8%</cell><cell>-96.6%</cell></row><row><cell>Type9</cell><cell>0.7%</cell><cell>+25.8%</cell></row><row><cell>Type10</cell><cell>0.1%</cell><cell>-30.7%</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>The average over 10,000 flight simulations for expected revenue and final revenue after offloading for the two strategies with varying θ . Advantage in revenue for D1S is kept after the offloading cost are applied.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Expected revenue Revenue after offloading</cell></row><row><cell>θ</cell><cell>D1S</cell><cell>FCFS</cell><cell>D1S</cell><cell>FCFS</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">0.8 2927.87</cell><cell>2548.95</cell><cell>2584.28</cell><cell>2541.32</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">1.0 2927.87</cell><cell>2548.95</cell><cell>2553.74</cell><cell>2517.23</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">We used a threshold of 0.01%.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">For non-cargo flights k v varies depending upon passenger load.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">Note again that we cannot convey the name for confidentiality reasons.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single-leg air-cargo revenue management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kannapha</forename><surname>Amaruchkul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>William</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diwakar</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="469" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New freight dimensions: For shippers, finding the real cost of a shipment shouldn?t be a matter of weight and see</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Beidermand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Air Cargo World</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic programming and optimal control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dimitri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitri</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bertsekas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitri</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bertsekas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitri</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bertsekas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bertsekas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Athena scientific Belmont</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Air cargo revenue management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thijs</forename><surname>Boonekamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gromicho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Dullaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Radstaak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Amsterdam</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Vrije Universiteit</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Unpublished masters thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revenue management of air cargo service in theory and practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Budiarto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H P</forename><surname>Putro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pradono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Yudoko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IOP Conference Series: Earth and Environmental Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">158</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">XGBoost: A Scalable Tree Boosting System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tianqi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Guestrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2939672.2939785</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2939672.2939785" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22Nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD &apos;16)</title>
		<meeting>the 22Nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD &apos;16)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="785" to="794" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An overview of research on revenue management: current issues and future research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wen-Chyuan Chiang</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojing</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Revenue Management (IJRM)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Duplicate record detection: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ahmed K Elmagarmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Panagiotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vassilios S</forename><surname>Ipeirotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Verykios</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on knowledge and data engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cleaning Disguised Missing Data: A Heuristic Approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Hua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Pei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD &apos;07</title>
		<meeting>the 13th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD &apos;07</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="950" to="958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Data Mining Techniques to Improve Forecast Accuracy in Airline Business</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Hueglin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesco</forename><surname>Vannotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD &apos;01</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD &apos;01</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="442" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Air cargo revenue management: Characteristics and complexities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Raja</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kasilingam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Operational Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regret in overbooking and fare-class allocation for single leg</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yingjie</forename><surname>Lan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ball</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Itir Z Karaesmen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Manufacturing &amp; Service Operations Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="194" to="208" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Passengerbased Predictive Modeling of Airline No-show Rates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">June</forename><surname>Se</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacques</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cherrier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 9th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="397" to="406" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revenue Management: Research Overview and Prospects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Mcgill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Garrett</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Ryzin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transportation Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="256" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Problem of Disguised Missing Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ronald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pearson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGKDD Explor. Newsl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="92" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Air cargo revenue and capacity management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreea</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<publisher>Ph.D. Dissertation. Georgia Institute of Technology</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating Air-Cargo Overbooking Based on a Discrete Show-Up-Rate Distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreea</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pinar</forename><surname>Keskinocak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellis</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><surname>Ladue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raja</forename><surname>Kasilingam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interfaces</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="258" />
			<date type="published" when="2006-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Approximate Dynamic Programming: Solving the curses of dimensionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Warren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Powell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">703</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FAHES: A Robust Disguised Missing Values Detector</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ahmed</forename><surname>Abdulhakim A Qahtan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raul</forename><forename type="middle">Castro</forename><surname>Elmagarmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mourad</forename><surname>Fernandez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nan</forename><surname>Ouzzani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery &amp; Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 24th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery &amp; Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2100" to="2109" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Potter&apos;s wheel: An interactive data cleaning system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vijayshankar</forename><surname>Raman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Joseph M Hellerstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">VLDB</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="390" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implementation of cargo revenue management at KLM</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Slager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kapteijins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Revenue Pricing Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>n. d.. n. d.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reinforcement learning: An introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Richard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>MIT press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Tibshirani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Elements of Statistical Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
