<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /nfs/home/kabenamualus/Research/task-dataset-metric-extraction/../grobid-0.6.0/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Beat the AI: Investigating Adversarial Human Annotation for Reading Comprehension</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Bartolo</surname></persName>
							<email>m.bartolo@cs.ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alastair</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
							<email>a.roberts@cs.ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Welbl</surname></persName>
							<email>j.welbl@cs.ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Riedel</surname></persName>
							<email>s.riedel@cs.ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pontus</forename><surname>Stenetorp</surname></persName>
							<email>p.stenetorp@cs.ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Beat the AI: Investigating Adversarial Human Annotation for Reading Comprehension</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.0" ident="GROBID-SDO" when="2021-06-25T15:52+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid-sdo"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Innovations in annotation methodology have been a catalyst for Reading Comprehension (RC) datasets and models. One recent trend to challenge current RC models is to involve a model in the annotation process: humans create questions adversarially, such that the model fails to answer them correctly. In this work we investigate this annotation methodology and apply it in three different settings, collecting a total of 36,000 samples with progressively stronger models in the annotation loop. This allows us to explore questions such as the reproducibility of the adversarial effect, transfer from data collected with varying model-in-the-loop strengths, and generalisation to data collected without a model. We find that training on adversarially collected samples leads to strong generalisation to non-adversarially collected datasets, yet with progressive performance deterioration with increasingly stronger models-inthe-loop. Furthermore, we find that stronger models can still learn from datasets collected with substantially weaker models-inthe-loop. When trained on data collected with a BiDAF model in the loop, RoBERTa achieves 39.9F 1 on questions that it cannot answer when trained on SQuAD -only marginally lower than when trained on data collected using RoBERTa itself (41.0F 1 ).</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Data collection is a fundamental prerequisite for Machine Learning-based approaches to Natural Language Processing <ref type="bibr">(NLP)</ref>. Innovations in data acquisition methodology, such as crowdsourcing, have led to major breakthroughs in scalability and preceded the "deep learning revolution", for which they can arguably be seen as co-responsible <ref type="bibr">(Deng et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bowman et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Rajpurkar</ref>  Model-in-the-loop Strength</p><p>Using boiling water to produce mechanical motion goes back over 2000 years, but early devices were not practical. The Spanish inventor Jerónimo de Ayanz y Beaumont obtained the first patent for a steam engine in 1606. In 1698 Thomas Savery patented a steam pump that used <ref type="bibr">[…]</ref>. Thomas Newcomen's atmospheric engine was the first commercial true steam engine using a piston, and was used in 1712 for pumping in a mine. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Human annotation with a model in the loop, showing: i) the "Beat the AI" annotation setting where only questions that the model does not answer correctly are accepted, and ii) questions generated this way, with a progressively stronger model in the annotation loop. <ref type="bibr">et al., 2016)</ref>. Annotation approaches include expert annotation, for example, relying on trained linguists <ref type="bibr">(Marcus et al., 1993)</ref>, crowd-sourcing by non-experts <ref type="bibr">(Snow et al., 2008)</ref>, distant supervision <ref type="bibr">(Mintz et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Joshi et al., 2017)</ref>, and leveraging document structure <ref type="bibr">(Hermann et al., 2015)</ref>. The concrete data collection paradigm chosen dictates the degree of scalability, annotation cost, precise task structure (often arising as a compromise of the above) and difficulty, domain coverage, as well as resulting dataset biases and model blind spots <ref type="bibr">(Jia and Liang, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Schwartz et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Gururangan et al., 2018)</ref>. A recently emerging trend in NLP dataset creation is the use of a model-in-the-loop when composing samples: A contemporary model is used either as a filter or directly during annotation, to identify samples wrongly predicted by the model. Examples of this method are realised in Build It Break It, The Language Edition <ref type="bibr">(Ettinger et al., 2017)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">HotpotQA (Yang et al., 2018a)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">SWAG (Zellers et al., 2018)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">Mechanical Turker Descent (Yang et al., 2018b)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">DROP (Dua et al., 2019)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">CODAH (Chen et al., 2019)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">Quoref (Dasigi et al., 2019)</ref>, and Adversar-ialNLI <ref type="bibr">(Nie et al., 2019)</ref>. 1 This approach probes model robustness and ensures that the resulting datasets pose a challenge to current models, which drives research to tackle new sets of problems.</p><p>We study this approach in the context of RC, and investigate its robustness in the face of continuously progressing models -do adversarially constructed datasets quickly become outdated in their usefulness as models grow stronger?</p><p>Based on models trained on the widely used SQuAD dataset, and following the same annotation protocol, we investigate the annotation setup where an annotator has to compose questions for which the model predicts the wrong answer. As a result, only samples that the model fails to predict correctly are retained in the dataset -see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> for an example.</p><p>We apply this annotation strategy with three distinct models in the loop, resulting in datasets with 12,000 samples each. We then study the reproducibility of the adversarial effect when retraining the models with the same data, as well as the generalisation ability of models trained using datasets produced with and without a model adversary. Models can, to a considerable degree, learn to generalise to more challenging questions, based on training sets collected with both stronger and also weaker models in the loop. Compared to training on SQuAD, training on adversarially composed questions leads to a similar degree of generalisation to non-adversarially written questions, both for SQuAD and NaturalQuestions <ref type="bibr">(Kwiatkowski et al., 2019)</ref>. It furthermore leads to general improvements across the model-in-the-loop datasets we collect, as well as improvements of more than 20.0F 1 for both BERT and RoBERTa on an extractive subset of DROP <ref type="bibr">(Dua et al., 2019)</ref>, another adversarially composed dataset. When conducting a systematic analysis of the concrete ques- <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The idea was alluded to at least as early as <ref type="bibr">Richardson et al. (2013)</ref>, but it has only recently seen wider adoption. tions different models fail to answer correctly, as well as non-adversarially composed questions, we see that the nature of the resulting questions changes: Questions composed with a model in the loop are overall more diverse, use more paraphrasing, multi-hop inference, comparisons, and background knowledge, and are generally less easily answered by matching an explicit statement that states the required information literally. Given our observations, we believe a model-in-the-loop approach to annotation shows promise and should be considered when creating future RC datasets.</p><p>To summarise, our contributions are as follows: First, an investigation into the model-in-the-loop approach to RC data collection based on three progressively stronger models, together with an empirical performance comparison when trained on datasets constructed with adversaries of different strength. Second, a comparative investigation into the nature of questions composed to be unsolvable by a sequence of progressively stronger models. Third, a study of the reproducibility of the adversarial effect and the generalisation ability of models trained in various settings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Constructing Challenging Datasets Recent efforts in dataset construction have driven considerable progress in RC, yet datasets are structurally diverse and annotation methodologies vary. With its large size and combination of freeform questions with answers as extracted spans, SQuAD1.1 <ref type="bibr">(Rajpurkar et al., 2016)</ref> has become an established benchmark that has inspired the construction of a series of similarly structured datasets. However, mounting evidence suggests that models can achieve strong generalisation performance merely by relying on superficial cuessuch as lexical overlap, term frequencies, or entity type matching <ref type="bibr">(Chen et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Weissenborn et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Sugawara et al., 2018)</ref>. It has thus become an increasingly important consideration to construct datasets that RC models find challenging, and for which natural language understanding is a requisite for generalisation. Attempts to achieve this non-trivial aim have typically revolved around extensions to the SQuAD dataset annotation methodology. They include unanswerable questions <ref type="bibr">(Trischler et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Rajpurkar et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Reddy et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Choi et al., 2018)</ref>, adding the option of " <ref type="bibr">Yes" or "No" answers (Dua et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kwiatkowski et al., 2019)</ref>, questions requiring reasoning over multiple sentences or documents <ref type="bibr">(Welbl et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Yang et al., 2018a)</ref>, questions requiring rule interpretation or context awareness <ref type="bibr">(Saeidi et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Choi et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Reddy et al., 2019)</ref>, limiting annotator passage exposure by sourcing questions first <ref type="bibr">(Kwiatkowski et al., 2019</ref>), controlling answer types by including options for dates, numbers, or spans from the question <ref type="bibr">(Dua et al., 2019)</ref>, as well as questions with free form answers <ref type="bibr">(Nguyen et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kočiský et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Reddy et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Adversarial Annotation One recently adopted approach to constructing challenging datasets involves the use of an adversarial model to select examples that it does not perform well on, an approach which superficially is akin to active learning <ref type="bibr">(Lewis and Gale, 1994)</ref>. Here, we make a distinction between two sub-categories of adversarial annotation: i) adversarial filtering, where the adversarial model is applied offline in a separate stage of the process, usually after data generation; examples include SWAG <ref type="bibr">(Zellers et al., 2018)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">ReCoRD (Zhang et al., 2018)</ref> We are primarily interested in the latter category, as this feedback loop creates an environment where the annotator can probe the model directly to explore its weaknesses and formulate targeted adversarial attacks. Although <ref type="bibr">Dua et al. (2019)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Dasigi et al. (2019)</ref> make use of adversarial annotations for RC, both annotation setups limit the reach of the model-in-the-loop: In DROP, primarily due to the imposition of specific answer types, and in Quoref by focusing on co-reference, which is already a known RC model weakness.</p><p>In contrast, we investigate a scenario where annotators interact with a model in its original task setting -annotators must thus explore a range of natural adversarial attacks, as opposed to filtering out "easy" samples during the annotation process. 3. F1 score between ah and am is calculated; if the F1 score is greater than a threshold (40%), the human loses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4(b). Human loses.</head><p>The process is restarted (same p). 4(a). Human wins. The human-sourced adversarial example (p, q, ah) is collected. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Overview of the annotation process to collect adversarially written questions from humans using a model in the loop.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Annotation Methodology</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Annotation Protocol</head><p>The data annotation protocol is based on SQuAD1.1, with a model in the loop, and the additional instruction that questions should only have one answer in the passage, which directly mirrors the setting in which these models were trained.</p><p>Formally, provided with a passage p, a human annotator generates a question q and selects a (human) answer a h by highlighting the corresponding span in the passage. The input (p, q) is then given to the model, which returns a predicted (model) answer a m . To compare the two, a word-overlap F 1 score between a h and a m is computed; a score above a threshold of 40% is considered a "win" for the model. 2 This process is repeated until the human "wins"; <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> gives a schematic overview of the process. All successful (p, q, a h ) triples, that is, those which the model is unable to answer correctly, are then retained for further validation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Annotation Details</head><p>Models in the Annotation Loop We begin by training three different models, which are used as adversaries during data annotation. As a seed dataset for training the models we select the widely used SQuAD1.1 <ref type="bibr">(Rajpurkar et al., 2016)</ref> dataset, a large-scale resource for which a variety of mature and well-performing models are readily available. Furthermore, unlike cloze-based datasets, SQuAD is robust to passage/questiononly adversarial attacks (Kaushik and Lipton, 2018). We will compare dataset annotation with a series of three progressively stronger models as adversary in the loop, namely BiDAF <ref type="bibr">(Seo et al., 2017)</ref>, BERT <ref type="bibr">LARGE (Devlin et al., 2019)</ref>, and RoBERTa <ref type="bibr">LARGE (Liu et al., 2019b)</ref>. Each of these will serve as a model adversary in a separate annotation experiment and result in three distinct datasets; we will refer to these as D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa respectively. Examples from the validation set of each are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 1</ref>. We rely on the AllenNLP (Gardner et al., 2018) and Transformers (Wolf et al., 2019) model implementations, and our models achieve EM/F 1 scores of 65.5%/77.5%, 82.7%/90.3% and 86.9%/93.6% for BiDAF, BERT, and RoBERTa respectively on the SQuAD1.1 validation set, consistent with results reported in other work.</p><p>Our choice of models reflects both the transition from LSTM-based to pre-trained transformerbased models, as well as a graduation among the latter; we investigate how this is reflected in datasets collected with each of these different models in the annotation loop. For each of the models we collect 10,000 training, 1,000 validation, and 1,000 test examples. Dataset sizes are motivated by the data efficiency of transformerbased pretrained models <ref type="bibr">(Devlin et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Liu et al., 2019b)</ref>, which has improved the viability of smaller-scale data collection efforts for investigative and analysis purposes.</p><p>To ensure the experimental integrity provided by reporting all results on a held-out test set, we split the existing SQuAD1.1 validation set in half (stratified by document title) as the official test set is not publicly available. We maintain passage consistency across the training, validation and test sets of all datasets to enable like-for-like comparisons. Lastly, we use the majority vote answer as ground truth for SQuAD1.1 to ensure that all our datasets have one valid answer per question, enabling us to fairly draw direct comparisons. For clarity, we will hereafter refer to this modified version of SQuAD1.1 as D SQuAD .</p><p>Crowdsourcing We use custom-designed Human Intelligence Tasks (HITs) served through Amazon Mechanical Turk (AMT) for all annotation efforts. Workers are required to be based in Canada, the UK, or the US, have a HIT Approval Rate greater than 98%, and have previously completed at least 1,000 HITs successfully. We experiment with and without the AMT Master requirement and find no substantial difference in quality, but observe a throughput reduction of nearly 90%. We pay USD 2.00 for every question generation HIT, during which workers are required to com-BiDAF Passage: [. . . ] the United Methodist Church has placed great emphasis on the importance of education. As such, the United Methodist Church established and is affiliated with around one hundred colleges [. . . ] of Methodist-related Schools, Colleges, and Universities. The church operates three hundred sixty schools and institutions overseas. Question: The United Methodist Church has how many schools internationally?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BiDAF</head><p>Passage: In a purely capitalist mode of production (i.e. where professional and labor organizations cannot limit the number of workers) the workers wages will not be controlled by these organizations, or by the employer, but rather by the market. Wages work in the same way as prices for any other good.  pose up to five questions that "beat" the model in the loop (cf. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>). The mean HIT completion times for BiDAF, BERT, and RoBERTa are 551.8s, 722.4s, and 686.4s. Furthermore we find that human workers are able to generate questions that successfully "beat" the model in the loop 59.4% of the time for BiDAF, 47.1% for BERT, and 44.0% for RoBERTa. These metrics broadly reflect the relative strength of the models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Quality Control</head><p>Training and Qualification We provide a twopart worker training interface in order to i) famil-iarise workers with the process, and ii) conduct a first screening based on worker outputs. The interface familiarises workers with formulating questions, and answering them through span selection.</p><p>Workers are asked to generate questions for two given answers, to highlight answers for two given questions, to generate one full question-answer pair, and finally to complete a question generation HIT with BiDAF as the model in the loop. Each worker's output is then reviewed manually (by the authors); those who pass the screening are added to the pool of qualified annotators.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Manual Worker Validation</head><p>In the second annotation stage, qualified workers produce data for the "Beat the AI" question generation task. A sample of every worker's HITs is manually reviewed based on their total number of completed tasks n, determined by 5·log 10 (n)+1 , chosen for convenience. This is done after every annotation batch; if workers fall below an 80% success threshold at any point, their qualification is revoked and their work is discarded in its entirety.</p><p>Question Answerability As the models used in the annotation task become stronger, the resulting questions tend to become more complex. However, this also means that it becomes more challenging to disentangle measures of dataset quality from inherent question difficulty. As such, we use the condition of human answerability for an annotated question-answer pair as follows: It is answerable if at least one of three additional nonexpert human validators can provide an answer matching the original. We conduct answerability checks on both the validation and test sets, and achieve answerability scores of 87.95%, 85.41%, and 82.63% for D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa . We discard all questions deemed unanswerable from the validation and test sets, and further discard all data from any workers with less than half of their questions considered answerable. It should be emphasised that the main purpose of this process is to create a level playing field for comparison across datasets constructed for different model adversaries, and can inevitably result in valid questions being discarded. The total cost for training and qualification, dataset construction, and validation is approximately USD 27,000.</p><p>Human Performance We select a randomly chosen validator's answer to each question and compute Exact Match (EM) and word overlap F 1 scores with the original to calculate non-expert human performance; <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 2</ref> shows the result. We observe a clear trend: the stronger the model in the loop used to construct the dataset, the harder the resulting questions become for humans. <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 3</ref> provides general details on the number of passages and question-answer pairs used in the different dataset splits. The average number of words in questions and answers, as well as the average longest n-gram overlap between passage and question are given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 4</ref>.   We can again observe two clear trends: From weaker towards stronger models used in the annotation loop, the average length of answers increases, and the largest n-gram overlap drops from 3 to 2 tokens. That is, on average there is a trigram overlap between the passage and question for D SQuAD , but only a bigram overlap for D RoBERTa <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 4</ref>). 3 This is in line with prior observations on lexical overlap as a predictive cue in SQuAD <ref type="bibr">(Weissenborn et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Min et al., 2018)</ref>; questions with less overlap are harder to answer for any of the three models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Dataset Statistics</head><p>We furthermore analyse question types based on the question wh-word. We find that -in contrast to D SQuAD -the datasets collected with a model in the annotation loop have fewer when, how and in questions, and more which, where and why questions, as well as questions in the other category, which indicates increased question diversity. In terms of answer types, we observe more common noun and verb phrase clauses than in D SQuAD , as well as fewer dates, names, and numeric answers. This reflects on the strong answer-type matching capabilities of contemporary RC models. The training and validation sets used in this analysis (D BiDAF , D BERT and D RoBERTa ) will be publicly released.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Consistency of the Model in the Loop</head><p>We begin with an experiment regarding the consistency of the adversarial nature of the models in the annotation loop. Our annotation pipeline is designed to reject all samples where the model correctly predicts the answer. How reproducible is this when retraining the model with the same training data? To measure this, we evaluate the performance of instances of BiDAF, BERT, and RoBERTa, which only differ from the model used during annotation in their random initialisation and order of mini-batch samples during training.</p><p>These results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">Table 5</ref>. First, we observe -as expected given our annotation constraints -that model performance is 0.0EM on datasets created with the same respective model in the annotation loop. We observe however that retrained models do not reliably perform as poorly on those samples. For example, BERT reaches 19.7EM, whereas the original model used during annotation provides no correct  <ref type="table" target="#tab_11">Table 5</ref>: Consistency of the adversarial effect (or lack thereof) when retraining the models in the loop on the same data again, but with different random seeds. We report the mean and standard deviation (subscript) over 10 re-initialisation runs. answer with 0.0EM. This demonstrates that random model components can substantially affect the adversarial annotation process. The evaluation furthermore serves as a baseline for subsequent model evaluations: This much of the performance range can be learnt merely by retraining the same model. A possible takeaway for employing the model-in-the-loop annotation strategy in the future is to rely on ensembles of adversaries and reduce the dependency on one particular model instantiation, as investigated by <ref type="bibr">Grefenstette et al. (2018)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Adversarial Generalisation</head><p>A potential problem with the focus on challenging questions is that they might be very distinct from one another, leading to difficulties in learning to generalise to and from them. We conduct a series of experiments in which we train on D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa , and observe how well models can learn to generalise to the respective test portions of these datasets. <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 6</ref> shows the results, and there is a multitude of observations.</p><p>First, one clear trend we observe across all training data setups is a negative performance progression when evaluated against datasets constructed with a stronger model in the loop. This trend holds true for all but the BiDAF model, in each of the training configurations, and for each of the evaluation datasets. For example, RoBERTa trained on D RoBERTa achieves 72.1, 57.1, 49.5, and 41.0F 1 when evaluated on D SQuAD , D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa respectively.</p><p>Second, we observe that the BiDAF model is not able to generalise well to datasets constructed with a model in the loop, independent of its training setup. In particular it is unable to learn from D BiDAF , thus failing to overcome some of its own  In contrast, BERT and RoBERTa are able to partially overcome their blind spots through training on data collected with a model in the loop, and to a degree that far exceeds what would be expected from random retraining (cf. Third, we observe similar performance degradation patterns for both BERT and RoBERTa on D SQuAD when trained on data collected with increasingly stronger models in the loop. For example, RoBERTa evaluated on D SQuAD achieves 82.8, 80.0, 75.1, and 72.1F 1 when trained on D SQuAD(10K) , D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa respectively. This may indicate a gradual shift in the distributions of composed questions as the model in the loop gets stronger.</p><p>These observations suggest an encouraging takeaway for the model-in-the-loop annotation paradigm: Even though a particular model might be chosen as an adversary in the annotation loop, which at some point falls behind more recent stateof-the-art models, these future models can still benefit from data collected with the weaker model, and also generalise better to samples composed with the stronger model in the loop.</p><p>We further show experimental results for the same models and training datasets, but now including SQuAD as additional training data in Table 7. In this training setup we generally see improved generalisation to D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa . Interestingly, the relative differences between D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa as training sets used in conjunction with SQuAD are much diminished, and especially D RoBERTa as  <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>: Training models on SQuAD, as well as SQuAD combined with different adversarially created datasets. We report the mean and standard deviation (subscript) over 10 runs with different random seeds.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Evaluation (Test) Dataset Model Training Dataset D SQuAD D BiDAF D BERT D RoBERTa EM F 1 EM F 1 EM F 1 EM F 1 D<label>SQuAD</label></formula><p>(part of) the training set now generalises substantially better. We see that BERT and RoBERTa both show consistent performance gains with the addition of the original SQuAD1.1 training data, but unlike in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 6</ref>, this comes without any noticeable decline in performance on D SQuAD , suggesting that the adversarially constructed datasets expose inherent model weaknesses, as investigated by <ref type="bibr">Liu et al. (2019a)</ref>.</p><p>Furthermore, RoBERTa achieves the strongest results on the adversarially collected evaluation sets, in particular when trained on D SQuAD + D RoBERTa . This stands in contrast to the results in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 6</ref>, where training on D BiDAF in several cases led to better generalisation than training on D RoBERTa . A possible explanation is that training on D RoBERTa leads to a larger degree of overfitting to specific adversarial examples in D RoBERTa than training on D BiDAF , and that the inclusion of a large number of standard SQuAD training samples can mitigate this effect.</p><p>Results for the models trained on all the datasets combined (D SQuAD , D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa ) are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_13">Table 8</ref>. These further support the previous observations and provide additional performance gains where, for example, RoBERTa achieves F 1 scores of 86.9 on D SQuAD , 74.1 on D BiDAF , 65.1 on D BERT , and 52.7 on D RoBERTa , surpassing the best previous performance on all adversarial datasets.</p><p>Finally, we identify a risk of datasets constructed with weaker models in the loop becoming outdated.</p><p>For example, RoBERTa achieves 58.2EM/73.2F 1 on D BiDAF , in contrast to 0.0EM/5.5F 1 for BiDAF -which is not far from the non-expert human performance of 62.6EM/78.5F 1 (cf. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 2</ref>).</p><p>It is also interesting to note that, even when training on all the combined data (cf <ref type="table" target="#tab_13">. Table 8)</ref>, BERT outperforms RoBERTa on D RoBERTa and vice versa, suggesting that there may exist weaknesses inherent to each model class.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Generalisation to Non-Adversarial Data</head><p>Compared to standard annotation, the model-inthe-loop approach generally results in new question distributions. Consequently, models trained on adversarially composed questions might not be able to generalise to standard ("easy") questions, thus limiting the practical usefulness of the resulting data. To what extent do models trained on model-in-the-loop questions generalise differently to standard ("easy") questions, compared to models trained on standard ("easy") questions?  To measure this we further train each of our three models on either D BiDAF , D BERT , or D RoBERTa and test on D SQuAD , with results in the D SQuAD columns of <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 6</ref>. For comparison, the models are also trained on 10,000 SQuAD1.1 samples (referred to as D SQuAD(10K) ) chosen from the same passages as the adversarial datasets, thus eliminating size and paragraph choice as potential confounding factors. The models are tuned for EM on the held-out D SQuAD validation set. Note that, although performance values on the majority vote D SQuAD dataset are lower than on the original, for the reasons described earlier, this enables direct comparisons across all datasets.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Evaluation (Test) Dataset Model D SQuAD D BiDAF D BERT D RoBERTa EM F 1 EM F 1 EM F 1 EM F 1<label>BiDAF</label></formula><p>Remarkably, neither BERT nor RoBERTa show substantial drops when trained on D BiDAF compared to training on SQuAD data (−2.1F 1 , and −2.8F 1 ): Training these models on a dataset with a weaker model in the loop still leads to strong generalisation even to data from the original SQuAD distribution, which all models in the loop are trained on. BiDAF, on the other hand, fails to learn such information from the adversarially collected data, and drops &gt;30F 1 for each of the new training sets, compared to training on SQuAD.</p><p>We also observe a gradual decrease in generalisation to SQuAD when training on D BiDAF towards training on D RoBERTa . This suggests that the stronger the model, the more dissimilar the resulting data distribution becomes from the original SQuAD distribution. We later find further support for this explanation in a qualitative analysis (Section 5). It may however also be due to a limitation of BERT and RoBERTa -similar to BiDAF -in learning from a data distribution designed to beat these models; an even stronger model might learn more from, for example, D RoBERTa .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Generalisation to DROP and NaturalQuestions</head><p>Finally, we investigate to what extent models can transfer skills learned on the datasets created with a model in the loop to two recently introduced datasets: DROP (Dua et al., 2019), and Natu-ralQuestions <ref type="bibr">(Kwiatkowski et al., 2019)</ref>. In this experiment we select the subsets of DROP and NaturalQuestions that align with the structural constraints of SQuAD to ensure a like-for-like analysis. Specifically, we only consider questions in DROP where the answer is a span in the passage and where there is only one candidate answer. For NaturalQuestions, we consider all nontabular long answers as passages, remove HTML tags and use the short answer as the extracted span. We apply this filtering on the validation sets for both datasets. Next we split them, stratifying by document (as we did for D SQuAD ), which results in 1409/1418 validation and test set examples for DROP, and 964/982 for NaturalQuestions, respectively. We denote these datasets as D DROP and D NQ for clarity and distinction from their unfiltered versions. We consider the same models and training datasets as before, but tune on the respective validation sets of D DROP and D NQ . <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 6</ref> shows the results of these experiments in the respective D DROP and D NQ columns.</p><p>First, we observe clear generalisation improvements towards D DROP across all models compared to training on D SQuAD(10K) when training on any of D BiDAF , D BERT , or D RoBERTa . That is, including a model in the loop for the training dataset leads to improved transfer towards D DROP . Note that DROP also makes use of a BiDAF model in the loop during annotation; these results are in line with our prior observations when testing the same setups on D BiDAF , D BERT and D RoBERTa , compared to training on D SQuAD(10K) .   Second, we observe overall strong transfer results towards D NQ , with up to 69.8F 1 for a BERT model trained on D BiDAF . Note that this result is similar to, and even slightly improves over model training with SQuAD data of the same size. That is, relative to training on SQuAD data, training on adversarially collected data D BiDAF does not impede generalisation to the D NQ dataset, which was created without a model in the annotation loop. We then however see a similar negative performance progression as observed before when testing on D SQuAD : the stronger the model in the annotation loop of the training dataset, the lower the test accuracy on test data from a data distribution composed without a model in the loop.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Qualitative Analysis</head><p>Having applied the general model-in-the-loop methodology on models of varying strength, we next perform a qualitative comparison of the nature of the resulting questions. As reference points we also include the original SQuAD questions, as well as DROP and NaturalQuestions in this comparison: These datasets are both constructed to overcome limitations in SQuAD and have subsets sufficiently similar to SQuAD to make an analysis possible. Specifically, we seek to understand the qualitative differences in terms of reading comprehension challenges posed by the questions in each of these datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Comprehension Requirements</head><p>There exists a variety of prior work that seeks to understand the types of knowledge, comprehension skills or types of reasoning required to answer questions based on text <ref type="bibr">(Rajpurkar et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Clark et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Sugawara et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dua et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr">Dasigi et al., 2019)</ref>; we are however unaware of any commonly accepted formalism. We take inspiration from these but develop our own taxonomy of comprehension requirements which suits the datasets analysed. Our taxonomy contains 13 labels, most of which are commonly used in other work. However, the following three deserve additional clarification: i) explicit -for which the answer is stated nearly wordfor-word in the passage as it is in the question, ii) filtering -a set of answers is narrowed down to select one by some particular distinguishing feature, and iii) implicit -the answer builds on information implied by the passage and does not otherwise require any of the other types of reasoning.</p><p>We annotate questions with labels from this catalogue in a manner that is not mutually exclusive, and neither fully comprehensive; the development of such a catalogue is itself very challenging. Instead, we focus on capturing the most salient characteristics of each given question, and assign it up to three of the labels in our catalogue. In total, we analyse 100 samples from the validation set of each of the datasets; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref> shows the results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Observations</head><p>An initial observation is that the majority (57%) of answers to SQuAD questions are stated explicitly, without comprehension requirements beyond the literal level. This number decreases substantially for any of the model-in-the-loop datasets derived from SQuAD (e.g., 8% for D BiDAF ) and also D DROP , yet 42% of questions in D NQ share this property. In contrast to SQuAD, the modelin-the-loop questions generally tend to involve more paraphrasing. They also require more external knowledge, and multi-hop inference (beyond co-reference resolution) with an increasing trend for stronger models used in the annotation loop. Model-in-the-loop questions further fan out into a variety of small, but non-negligible proportions of more specific types of inference required for comprehension, for example, spatial or temporal inference (both going beyond explicitly stated spatial or temporal information) -SQuAD questions rarely require these at all. Some of these more particular inference types are common features of the other two datasets, in particular comparative questions for DROP (60%) and to a small extent also NaturalQuestions. Interestingly, D BiDAF possesses the largest number of comparison questions (11%) among our model-in-the-loop datasets, whereas D BERT and D RoBERTa only possess 1% and 3%, respectively. This offers an explanation for our previous observation in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 6</ref>, where BERT and RoBERTa perform better on D DROP when trained on D BiDAF rather than on D BERT or D RoBERTa . It is likely that BiDAF as a model in the loop is worse than BERT and RoBERTa at comparative questions, as evidenced by the results in <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 6</ref> with BiDAF reaching 8.6F 1 , BERT reaching 28.9F 1 , and RoBERTa reaching 39.4F 1 on D DROP (when trained on D SQuAD(10K) ).</p><p>The distribution of NaturalQuestions contains elements of both the SQuAD and D BiDAF distributions, which offers a potential explanation for the strong performance on D NQ of models trained on D SQuAD(10K) and D BiDAF . Finally, the gradually shifting distribution away from both SQuAD and NaturalQuestions as the model-in-the-loop strength increases reflects our prior observations on the decreasing performance on SQuAD and NaturalQuestions of models trained on datasets with progressively stronger models in the loop.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussion and Conclusions</head><p>We have investigated an RC annotation paradigm that requires a model in the loop to be "beaten" by an annotator. Applying this approach with progressively stronger models in the loop (BiDAF, BERT, and RoBERTa), we produced three separate datasets. Using these datasets, we investigated several questions regarding the annotation paradigm, in particular whether such datasets grow outdated as stronger models emerge, and their generalisation to standard (non-adversarially collected) questions. We found that stronger models can still learn from data collected with a weak adversary in the loop, and their generalisation im-proves even on datasets collected with a stronger adversary. Models trained on data collected with a model in the loop further generalise well to nonadversarially collected data, both on SQuAD and on NaturalQuestions, yet we observe a gradual deterioration in performance with progressively stronger adversaries.</p><p>We see our work as a contribution towards the emerging paradigm of model-in-the-loop annotation. While this paper has focused on RC, with SQuAD as the original dataset used to train model adversaries, we see no reason in principle why findings would not be similar for other tasks using the same annotation paradigm, when crowdsourcing challenging samples with a model in the loop. We would expect the insights and benefits conveyed by model-in-the-loop annotation to be the greatest on mature datasets where models exceed human performance: Here the resulting data provides a magnifying glass on model performance, focused in particular on samples which models struggle on. On the other hand, applying the method to datasets where performance has not yet plateaued would likely result in a more similar distribution to the original data, which is challenging to models a priori. We hope that the series of experiments on replicability, observations on transfer between datasets collected using models of different strength, as well as our findings regarding generalisation to non-adversarially collected data, can support and inform future research and annotation efforts using this paradigm.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Additional Dataset Statistics</head><p>Question statistics In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 7</ref> we analyse question lengths across SQuAD1.1 and compare them to questions constructed with different models in the annotation loop. While the mean of the distributions is similar, there is more question length variability when using a model in the loop. We also perform analysis of question types by whword as described earlier (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). This is in further detail displayed using sunburst plots of the first three question tokens for D SQuAD (cf. <ref type="figure">Figure 11)</ref>, D BiDAF (cf. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 13</ref>), D BERT (cf. <ref type="figure">Figure 12)</ref> and D RoBERTa (cf. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 14)</ref>. We observe a general trend towards more diverse questions with increasing model-in-the-loop strength. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 9</ref> allows for further analysis of answer lengths across datasets. We observe that answers for all datasets constructed with a model in the loop tend to be longer than in SQuAD. There is furthermore a trend of increas-    ing answer length and variability with increasing model-in-the-loop strength. We show an analysis of answer types in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 8</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Answer statistics</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B Annotation Interface Details</head><p>We have three key steps in the dataset construction process: i) training and qualification, ii) "Beat the AI" annotation and iii) answer validation.</p><p>Training and Qualification This is a combined training and qualification task; a screenshot of the interface is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 15</ref>. The first step involves a set of five assignments requiring the worker to demonstrate an ability to generate questions and indicate answers by highlighting the corresponding spans in the passage. Once complete, the worker is shown a sample "Beat the AI" HIT for a pre-determined passage which helps facilitate manual validation. In earlier experiments, these two steps were presented as separate interfaces, however, this created a bottleneck between the two layers of qualification and slowed down annotation considerably. In total, 1,386 workers completed this task with 752 being assigned the qualification.</p><p>"Beat the AI Annotation" The "Beat the AI" question generation HIT presents workers with a randomly selected passage from SQuAD1.1, about which workers are expected to generate questions and provide answers. This data is sent to the corresponding model-in-the-loop API running on AWS infrastructure and primarily consisting of a load balancer and a t2.xlarge EC2 instance with the T2/T3 Unlimited setting enabled to allow high sustained CPU performance during annotation runs. The model API returns a prediction which is scored against the worker's answer to determine whether the worker has successfully managed to "beat" the model. Only questions which the model fails to answer are considered valid; a screenshot for this interface is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 16</ref>. Workers are tasked to ideally submit at least three valid questions, however fewer are also accepted -in particular for very short passages. A sample of each worker's HITs is manually validated; those who do not satisfy the question quality requirements have their qualification revoked and all their annotated data discarded. This was the case for 99 workers. Worker validation distributions are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Figure 10</ref>.</p><p>Answer Validation The answer validation interface (cf. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 17)</ref> is used to validate the answerability of the validation and test sets for each dif-ferent model used in the annotation loop. Every previously collected question generation HIT from these dataset parts, which had not been discarded during manual validation, is submitted to at least 3 distinct annotators. Workers are shown the passage and previously generated questions and are asked to highlight the answer in the passage. In a post-processing step, only questions with at least 1 valid matching answer out of 3 are finally retained.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C Catalogue of Comprehension Requirements</head><p>We give a description for each of the items in our catalogue of comprehension requirements in Table 9, accompanied with an example for illustration. These are the labels used for the qualitative analysis performed in Section 5.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 15</ref>: Training and qualification interface. Workers are first expected to familiarise themselves with the interface and them complete a sample "Beat the AI" task for validation. <ref type="figure">Figure 16</ref>: "Beat the AI" question generation interface. Human annotators are tasked with asking questions about a provided passage which the model in the loop fails to answer correctly. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 17</ref>: Answer validation interface. Workers are expected to provide answers to questions generated in the "Beat the AI" task. The additional answers are used to determine question answerability and non-expert human performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Type</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description</head><p>Passage Question</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Explicit</head><p>Answer stated nearly word-for-word in the passage as it is in the question.</p><p>Sayyid Abul Ala Maududi was an important early twentieth-century figure in the Islamic revival in India <ref type="bibr">[. . . ]</ref> Who was an important early figure in the Islamic revival in India? Paraphrasing Question paraphrases parts of the passage, generally relying on contextspecific synonyms.</p><p>Seamans' establishment of an ad-hoc committee <ref type="bibr">[. . . ]</ref> Who created the adhoc committee?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>External Knowledge</head><p>The question cannot be answered without access to sources of knowledge beyond the passage.</p><p>[. . . ] the 1988 film noir thriller Stormy Monday, directed by Mike Figgis and starring Tommy Lee Jones, Melanie Griffith, Sting and Sean Bean.</p><p>Which musician was featured in the film Stormy Monday?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Coreference</head><p>Requires resolution of a relationship between two distinct words referring to the same entity. Into what family did the artist who represented the Art Deco style marry? Comparative Requires a comparison between two or more attributes (e.g., smaller than, last)</p><p>The previous chairs were Rajendra <ref type="bibr">K. Pachauri, elected in May 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr">Robert Watson in 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr">and Bert Bolin in 1988</ref>.</p><p>Who was elected earlier, Robert Watson or Bert Bolin? Numeric Any numeric reasoning (e.g., some form of calculation is required to arrive at the correct answer).</p><p>[. . . ] it has been estimated that Africans will make up at least 30% of the delegates at the 2012 General Conference, and it is also possible that 40% of the delegates will be from outside <ref type="bibr">[. . . ]</ref> From which continent is it estimated that members will make up nearly a third of participants in 2012? Negation</p><p>Requires interpreting a single or multiple negations.</p><p>Subordinate to the General Conference are the jurisdictional and central conferences which also meet every four years.</p><p>What is not in charge?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Filtering</head><p>Narrowing down a set of answers to select one by some particular distinguishing feature.</p><p>[. . . ] was engaged with Johannes Bugenhagen, Justus Jonas, Johannes Apel, Philipp Melanchthon and Lucas Cranach the Elder and his wife as witnesses <ref type="bibr">[. . . ]</ref> Whose partner could testify to the couple's agreement to marry?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Temporal</head><p>Requires an understanding of time and change, and related aspects. Goes beyond directly stated answers to When questions or external knowledge.</p><p>In 2010 the Amazon rainforest experienced another severe drought, in some ways more extreme than the 2005 drought.</p><p>What occurred in 2005 and then again five years later?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spatial</head><p>Requires an understanding of the concept of space, location, or proximity. Goes beyond finding directly stated answers to Where questions. What could not keep the Augsburg confession from being signed? <ref type="table">Table 9</ref>: Comprehension requirement definitions and examples from adversarial model-in-the-loop annotated RC datasets. Note that these types are not mutually exclusive. The annotated answer is highlighted in yellow.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, HotpotQA (Yang et al., 2018a), and HellaSWAG (Zellers et al., 2019); ii) model-in-the-loop adversarial annotation, where the annotator can directly interact with the adversary during the annotation process and uses the feedback to further inform the generation process; examples include CODAH (Chen et al., 2019), Quoref (Dasigi et al., 2019), DROP (Dua et al., 2019), FEVER2.0 (Thorne et al., 2019), Ad-versarialNLI (Nie et al., 2019), as well as work by Dinan et al. (2019), Kaushik et al. (2020), and Wallace et al. (2019) for the Quizbowl task.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>"Beat the AI" question generation interface. Human annotators are tasked with asking questions about a provided passage which the model in the loop fails to answer correctly.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Distribution of longest n-gram overlap between passage and question for different datasets. µ: mean; σ: standard deviation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>D</head><label></label><figDesc>SQuAD + D BERT 73.8 0.2 86.7 0.2 55.4 1.0 70.1 0.9 48.9 1.0 59.0 1.2 32.9 1.3 43.7 1.4 D SQuAD + D RoBERTa 73.5 0.3 86.5 0.2 55.9 0.7 70.6 0.7 49.1 1.2 59.5 1.2 34.7 1.0 45.9 1.2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Comparison of comprehension types for the questions in different datasets. The label types are neither mutually exclusive nor comprehensive. Values above columns indicate excess of the axis range.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 6: Analysis of question types across datasets.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Question length distribution across datasets.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Analysis of answer types across datasets.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Answer length distribution across datasets.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Worker distribution, together with the number of manually validated QA pairs per worker.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Validation set examples of questions collected using different RC models (BiDAF, BERT, and RoBERTa) in the annotation loop. The answer to the question is highlighted in the passage.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Non-expert human performance results for a randomly-selected validator per question.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>#Passages</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>#QAs</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Resource</cell><cell>Train Dev</cell><cell>Test</cell><cell>Train</cell><cell>Dev</cell><cell>Test</cell></row><row><cell>DSQuAD</cell><cell cols="5">18,891 971 1,096 87,599 5,278 5,292</cell></row><row><cell>DBiDAF</cell><cell>2,523 278</cell><cell cols="4">277 10,000 1,000 1,000</cell></row><row><cell>DBERT</cell><cell>2,444 283</cell><cell cols="4">292 10,000 1,000 1,000</cell></row><row><cell>DRoBERTa</cell><cell>2,552 341</cell><cell cols="4">333 10,000 1,000 1,000</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>Number of passages and question-answer pairs for each data resource.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>Average number of words per question and answer, and average longest n-gram overlap between passage and question.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>SQuAD(10K) 40.9 0.6 54.3 0.6 7.1 0.6 15.7 0.6 5.6 0.3 13.5 0.4 5.7 0.4 13.5 0.4 3.8 0.4 8.6 0.6 25.1 1.1 38.7 0.7 BiDAF DBiDAF 11.5 0.4 20.9 0.4 5.3 0.4 11.6 0.5 7.1 0.4 14.8 0.6 6.8 0.5 13.5 0.6 6.5 0.5 12.4 0.4 15.7 1.1 28.7 0.8 DBERT 10.8 0.3 19.8 0.4 7.2 0.5 14.4 0.6 6.9 0.3 14.5 0.4 8.1 0.4 15.0 0.6 7.8 0.9 14.5 0.9 16.5 0.6 28.3 0.9</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Evaluation (Test) Dataset</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>Trained On</cell><cell cols="2">DSQuAD</cell><cell cols="2">DBiDAF</cell><cell cols="2">DBERT</cell><cell cols="2">DRoBERTa</cell><cell cols="2">DDROP</cell><cell>DNQ</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>EM</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>EM</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>EM</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>EM</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>EM</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>EM</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>D DRoBERTa</cell><cell cols="11">10.7 0.2 20.2 0.3 6.3 0.7 13.5 0.8 9.4 0.6 17.0 0.6 8.9 0.9 16.0 0.8 15.3 0.8 22.9 0.8 13.4 0.9 27.1 1.2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="12">D SQuAD(10K) 69.4 0.5 82.7 0.4 35.1 1.9 49.3 2.2 15.6 2.0 27.3 2.1 11.9 1.5 23.0 1.4 18.9 2.3 28.9 3.2 52.9 1.0 68.2 1.0</cell></row><row><cell>BERT</cell><cell>DBiDAF</cell><cell cols="11">66.5 0.7 80.6 0.6 46.2 1.2 61.1 1.2 37.8 1.4 48.8 1.5 30.6 0.8 42.5 0.6 41.1 2.3 50.6 2.0 54.2 1.2 69.8 0.9</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>DBERT</cell><cell cols="11">61.2 1.8 75.7 1.6 42.9 1.9 57.5 1.8 37.4 2.1 47.9 2.0 29.3 2.1 40.0 2.3 39.4 2.2 47.6 2.2 49.9 2.3 65.7 2.3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>DRoBERTa</cell><cell cols="11">57.0 1.7 71.7 1.8 37.0 2.3 52.0 2.5 34.8 1.5 45.9 2.0 30.5 2.2 41.2 2.2 39.0 3.1 47.4 2.8 45.8 2.4 62.4 2.5</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="12">D SQuAD(10K) 68.6 0.5 82.8 0.3 37.7 1.1 53.8 1.1 20.8 1.2 34.0 1.0 11.0 0.8 22.1 0.9 25.0 2.2 39.4 2.4 43.9 3.8 62.8 3.1</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">RoBERTa DBiDAF</cell><cell cols="11">64.8 0.7 80.0 0.4 48.0 1.2 64.3 1.1 40.0 1.5 51.5 1.3 29.0 1.9 39.9 1.8 44.5 2.1 55.4 1.9 48.4 1.1 66.9 0.8</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>DBERT</cell><cell cols="11">59.5 1.0 75.1 0.9 45.4 1.5 60.7 1.5 38.4 1.8 49.8 1.7 28.2 1.5 38.8 1.5 42.2 2.3 52.6 2.0 45.8 1.1 63.6 1.1</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>DRoBERTa</cell><cell cols="11">56.2 0.7 72.1 0.7 41.4 0.8 57.1 0.8 38.4 1.1 49.5 0.9 30.2 1.3 41.0 1.2 41.2 0.9 51.2 0.8 43.6 1.1 61.6 0.9</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Training models on various datasets, each with 10,000 samples, and measuring their generalisation to different evaluation datasets. Results underlined indicate the best result per model. We report the mean and standard deviation (subscript) over 10 runs with different random seeds. blind spots through adversarial training. Irrespective of the training dataset, BiDAF consistently performs poorly on the adversarially collected evaluation datasets, and we also note a substantial performance drop when trained on D BiDAF , D</figDesc><table /><note>BERT , or D RoBERTa and evaluated on D SQuAD .</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head>Table 5 )</head><label>5</label><figDesc>. For example, BERT reaches 47.9F 1 when trained and evaluated on D BERT , while RoBERTa trained on D RoBERTa reaches 41.0F 1 on D RoBERTa , both considerably better than random retraining, or when training on the non-adversarially collected D SQuAD(10K) showing gains of 20.6F 1 for BERT and 18.9F 1 for RoBERTa. These observations suggest that there exists learnable structure among harder questions that can be picked up by some of the models, yet not all, as BiDAF fails to achieve this. The fact that even BERT can learn to generalise to D RoBERTa , but not BiDAF to D BERT suggests the existence of an inherent limitation to what BiDAF can learn from these new samples, compared to BERT and RoBERTa.More generally, we observe that training on D S , where S is a stronger RC model, helps generalise to D W , where W is a weaker model, for example, training on D RoBERTa and testing on D BERT . On the other hand, training on D W also leads to generalisation towards D S . For example, RoBERTa trained on 10,000 SQuAD samples reaches 22.1F 1 on D RoBERTa (D S ), whereas training RoBERTa on D BiDAF and D BERT (D W ) bumps this number to 39.9F 1 and 38.8F 1 , respectively.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Training models on SQuAD combined with all the adversarially created datasets D BiDAF , D BERT , and D RoBERTa . We report the mean and standard deviation (subscript) over 10 runs with different random seeds.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>large annotated corpus for learning natural language inference. In Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, pages 632-642, Lisbon, Portugal. Association for Computational Linguistics.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Edward Grefenstette, Robert Stanforth, Bren-documents. In Proceedings of the 56th Annual 2019. The FEVER2.0 shared task. In Pro-</cell><cell>hierarchical image database. In 2009 IEEE benchmarks. In Proceedings of the 2018 Con-Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Kiela, and Jason Weston. 2018b. Mastering the</cell></row><row><cell>dan O'Donoghue, Jonathan Uesato, Grzegorz Meeting of the Association for Computational ceedings of the Second Workshop on Fact Ex-</cell><cell>Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern ference on Empirical Methods in Natural Lan-Language Processing, pages 193-203, Seattle, dungeon: Grounded language learning by me-</cell></row><row><cell>Swirszcz, and Pushmeet Kohli. 2018. Strength Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers), pages traction and VERification (FEVER), pages 1-6,</cell><cell>Recognition (CVPR), volume 00, pages 248-guage Processing, pages 5010-5015, Brussels, Washington, USA. Association for Computa-chanical turker descent. In International Con-</cell></row><row><cell>in numbers: Trading-off robustness and com-1725-1735, Melbourne, Australia. Association Hong Kong, China. Association for Computa-</cell><cell>255. Belgium. Association for Computational Lin-tional Linguistics. ference on Learning Representations.</cell></row><row><cell>putation via adversarially-trained ensembles. for Computational Linguistics. tional Linguistics. CoRR, abs/1811.09300. Mike Mintz, Steven Bills, Rion Snow, and Daniel Adam Trischler, Tong Wang, Xingdi Yuan, Justin</cell><cell>Jacob Devlin, Ming-Wei Chang, Kenton Lee, and Kristina Toutanova. 2019. BERT: Pre-training guistics. Marzieh Saeidi, Max Bartolo, Patrick Lewis, Rowan Zellers, Yonatan Bisk, Roy Schwartz, and Tomáš Kočiský, Jonathan Schwarz, Phil Blun-Sameer Singh, Tim Rocktäschel, Mike Sheldon, Yejin Choi. 2018. SWAG: A large-scale adver-</cell></row><row><cell>Danqi Chen, Jason Bolton, and Christopher D. Suchin Gururangan, Swabha Swayamdipta, Omer Jurafsky. 2009. Distant supervision for rela-Harris, Alessandro Sordoni, Philip Bachman,</cell><cell>of deep bidirectional transformers for language som, Chris Dyer, Karl Moritz Hermann, Gá-Guillaume Bouchard, and Sebastian Riedel. sarial dataset for grounded commonsense infer-</cell></row><row><cell>Manning. 2016. A thorough examination of Levy, Roy Schwartz, Samuel Bowman, and tion extraction without labeled data. In Pro-and Kaheer Suleman. 2017. NewsQA: A ma-</cell><cell>understanding. In Proceedings of the 2019 bor Melis, and Edward Grefenstette. 2018. The 2018. Interpretation of natural language rules ence. In Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on</cell></row><row><cell>the CNN/Daily Mail reading comprehension Noah A. Smith. 2018. Annotation artifacts in ceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th An-chine comprehension dataset. In Proceedings of</cell><cell>Conference of the North American Chapter NarrativeQA reading comprehension challenge. in conversational machine reading. In Pro-Empirical Methods in Natural Language Pro-</cell></row><row><cell>task. In Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meet-natural language inference data. In Proceed-nual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th Interna-the 2nd Workshop on Representation Learning</cell><cell>of the Association for Computational Linguis-Transactions of the Association for Computa-ceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empiri-cessing, pages 93-104, Brussels, Belgium. As-</cell></row><row><cell>ing of the Association for Computational Lin-ings of the 2018 Conference of the North Amer-tional Joint Conference on Natural Language for NLP, pages 191-200, Vancouver, Canada.</cell><cell>tics: Human Language Technologies, Volume tional Linguistics, 6:317-328. cal Methods in Natural Language Processing, sociation for Computational Linguistics.</cell></row><row><cell>guistics (Volume 1: Long Papers), pages 2358-2367, Berlin, Germany. Association for Com-putational Linguistics. Michael Chen, Mike D'Arcy, Alisa Liu, Jared Fer-nandez, and Doug Downey. 2019. CODAH: An adversarially-authored question answering dataset for common sense. In Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Evaluating Vector Space Representations for NLP, pages 63-69, Min-neapolis, USA. Association for Computational Linguistics. Eunsol Choi, He He, Mohit Iyyer, Mark Yatskar, Wen-tau Yih, Yejin Choi, Percy Liang, and Luke Zettlemoyer. 2018. QuAC: Question an-swering in context. In Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, pages 2174-2184, Brus-sels, Belgium. Association for Computational Linguistics. Peter Clark, Isaac Cowhey, Oren Etzioni, Tushar Khot, Ashish Sabharwal, Carissa Schoenick, and Oyvind Tafjord. 2018. Think you have solved question answering? Try ARC, the AI2 reasoning challenge. CoRR, abs/1803.05457. Pradeep Dasigi, Nelson F. Liu, Ana Maraso-vić, Noah A. Smith, and Matt Gardner. 2019. Quoref: A reading comprehension dataset with questions requiring coreferential reason-ing. In Proceedings of the 2019 Confer-ence on Empirical Methods in Natural Lan-guage Processing and the 9th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Pro-cessing (EMNLP-IJCNLP), pages 5925-5932, Hong Kong, China. Association for Computa-tional Linguistics. ican Chapter of the Association for Computa-tional Linguistics: Human Language Technolo-gies, Volume 2 (Short Papers), pages 107-112, Association for Computational Linguistics. Processing of the AFNLP, pages 1003-1011, Suntec, Singapore. Association for Computa-Eric Wallace, Pedro Rodriguez, Shi Feng, Ikuya tional Linguistics. Yamada, and Jordan Boyd-Graber. 2019. Trick New Orleans, Louisiana. Association for Com-Tri Nguyen, Mir Rosenberg, Xia Song, Jian-me if you can: Human-in-the-loop generation putational Linguistics. feng Gao, Saurabh Tiwary, Rangan Majumder, of adversarial examples for question answering. on Learning Representations. Divyansh Kaushik and Zachary C. Lipton. 2018. and Erin Renshaw. 2013. MCTest: A challenge tional Linguistics. Matthew Richardson, Christopher J.C. Burges, Brussels, Belgium. Association for Computa-augmented data. In International Conference 266. ural Language Processing, pages 2369-2380, makes a difference with counterfactually-ciation for Computational Linguistics, 7:249-2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Nat-Robin Jia and Percy Liang. 2017. Adversarial ex-amples for evaluating reading comprehension systems. In Proceedings of the 2017 Confer-ence on Empirical Methods in Natural Lan-guage Processing, pages 2021-2031, Copen-hagen, Denmark. Association for Computa-tional Linguistics. Mandar Joshi, Eunsol Choi, Daniel Weld, and Luke Zettlemoyer. 2017. TriviaQA: A large scale distantly supervised challenge dataset for pers), pages 1601-1611, Vancouver, Canada. Association for Computational Linguistics. Divyansh Kaushik, Eduard Hovy, and Zachary Lipton. 2020. Learning the difference that ing, pages 2383-2392, Austin, Texas. Associa-tion for Computational Linguistics. Siva Reddy, Danqi Chen, and Christopher D. Man-ning. 2019. CoQA: A conversational question answering challenge. Transactions of the Asso-hop question answering. In Proceedings of the potQA: A dataset for diverse, explainable multi-and Christopher D. Manning. 2018a. Hot-Bengio, William Cohen, Ruslan Salakhutdinov, Zhilin Yang, Peng Qi, Saizheng Zhang, Yoshua Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Pa-pirical Methods in Natural Language Process-abs/1910.03771. 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for In Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Em-the-art Natural Language Processing. ArXiv, reading comprehension. In Proceedings of the Pranav Rajpurkar, Robin Jia, and Percy Liang. 2018. Know what you don't know: Unan-Association for Computational Linguistics. Pranav Rajpurkar, Jian Zhang, Konstantin Lopy-rev, and Percy Liang. 2016. SQuAD: 100,000+ questions for machine comprehension of text. 2019. HuggingFace's Transformers: State-of-Louf, Morgan Funtowicz, and Jamie Brew. thony Moi, Pierric Cistac, Tim Rault, Rémi Julien Chaumond, Clement Delangue, An-Thomas Wolf, Lysandre Debut, Victor Sanh, Papers), pages 784-789, Melbourne, Australia. tional Linguistics, 6:287-302. for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Transactions of the Association for Computa-of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association hop reading comprehension across documents. swerable questions for SQuAD. In Proceedings Riedel. 2018. Constructing datasets for multi-Johannes Welbl, Pontus Stenetorp, and Sebastian and Li Deng. 2016. MS MARCO: A human Transactions of the Association for Computa-Karl Moritz Hermann, Tomas Kocisky, Edward generated MAchine Reading COmprehension tional Linguistics, 7:387-401. Grefenstette, Lasse Espeholt, Will Kay, Mustafa Suleyman, and Phil Blunsom. 2015. Teach-ing machines to read and comprehend. In C. Cortes, N. D. Lawrence, D. D. Lee, M. Sugiyama, and R. Garnett, editors, Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 28, pages 1693-1701. Curran Associates, Inc. dataset. arXiv preprint arXiv:1611.09268. Yixin Nie, Adina Williams, Emily Dinan, Mohit Bansal, Jason Weston, and Douwe Kiela. 2019. Adversarial NLI: A new benchmark for natural language understanding. arXiv preprint arXiv: 1910.14599. Dirk Weissenborn, Georg Wiese, and Laura Seiffe. 2017. Making neural QA as simple as possible but not simpler. In Proceedings of the 21st Con-ference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL 2017), pages 271-280, Van-couver, Canada. Association for Computational Linguistics.</cell><cell>1 (Long and Short Papers), pages 4171-4186, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Association for Com-putational Linguistics. Emily Dinan, Samuel Humeau, Bharath Chin-Tom Kwiatkowski, Jennimaria Palomaki, Olivia Redfield, Michael Collins, Ankur Parikh, Chris Alberti, Danielle Epstein, Illia Polosukhin, Ja-pages 2087-2097, Brussels, Belgium. Associa-Rowan Zellers, Ari Holtzman, Yonatan Bisk, Ali tion for Computational Linguistics. Farhadi, and Yejin Choi. 2019. HellaSwag: Roy Schwartz, Maarten Sap, Ioannis Konstas, Can a machine really finish your sentence? In cob Devlin, Kenton Lee, Kristina Toutanova, Leila Zilles, Yejin Choi, and Noah A. Smith. Proceedings of the 57th Annual Meeting of Llion Jones, Matthew Kelcey, Ming-Wei 2017. The effect of different writing tasks on the Association for Computational Linguistics, tagunta, and Jason Weston. 2019. Build it break it fix it for dialogue safety: Robust-ness from adversarial human attack. In Pro-ceedings of the 2019 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and the 9th International Joint Conference on Nat-ural Language Processing (EMNLP-IJCNLP), pages 4537-4546, Hong Kong, China. Associa-tion for Computational Linguistics. Gabriel Stanovsky, Sameer Singh, and Matt Gardner. 2019. DROP: A reading compre-hension benchmark requiring discrete reason-ing over paragraphs. In Proceedings of the 2019 Conference of the North American Chap-ter of the Association for Computational Lin-guistics: Human Language Technologies, Vol-ume 1 (Long and Short Papers), pages 2368-2378, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Association for Computational Linguistics. Allyson Ettinger, Sudha Rao, Hal Daumé III, and Emily M. Bender. 2017. Towards linguistically generalizable NLP systems: A workshop and shared task. CoRR, abs/1711.01505. Matt Gardner, Joel Grus, Mark Neumann, Oyvind Tafjord, Pradeep Dasigi, Nelson F. Liu, Proceedings of Workshop for NLP Open Source Software (NLP-OSS), pages 1-6, Melbourne, 19(2):313-330. Sewon Min, Victor Zhong, Richard Socher, and hension datasets. CoRR, abs/1911.09241. marking capacity of machine reading compre-tic natural language processing platform. In Penn Treebank. Computational Linguistics, and Akiko Aizawa. 2019. Assessing the bench-Zettlemoyer. 2018. AllenNLP: A deep seman-a large annotated corpus of English: The Saku Sugawara, Pontus Stenetorp, Kentaro Inui, Matthew Peters, Michael Schmitz, and Luke Stoyanov. 2019b. RoBERTa: A robustly op-timized BERT pretraining approach. CoRR, abs/1907.11692. Mitchell P. Marcus, Beatrice Santorini, and Mary Ann Marcinkiewicz. 1993. Building tion for Computational Linguistics. pages 4208-4219, Brussels, Belgium. Associa-cal Methods in Natural Language Processing, ceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empiri-ing comprehension questions easier? In Pro-Mike Lewis, Luke Zettlemoyer, and Veselin and Akiko Aizawa. 2018. What makes read-Du, Mandar Joshi, Danqi Chen, Omer Levy, Saku Sugawara, Kentaro Inui, Satoshi Sekine, Nelson F. Liu, Roy Schwartz, and Noah A. Smith. 2019a. Inoculation by fine-tuning: A method for analyzing challenge datasets. In Proceed-ings of the 2019 Conference of the North Amer-ican Chapter of the Association for Computa-tional Linguistics: Human Language Technolo-gies, Volume 1 (Long and Short Papers), pages 2171-2179, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Associa-tion for Computational Linguistics. Yinhan Liu, Myle Ott, Naman Goyal, Jingfei tional Linguistics. Honolulu, Hawaii. Association for Computa-Natural Language Processing, pages 254-263, the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in for natural language tasks. In Proceedings of is it good? evaluating non-expert annotations and Andrew Ng. 2008. Cheap and fast -but Rion Snow, Brendan O'Connor, Daniel Jurafsky, resentations (ICLR). The International Conference on Learning Rep-Dheeru Dua, Yizhong Wang, Pradeep Dasigi, Chang, Andrew M. Dai, Jakob Uszkoreit, Quoc linguistic style: A case study of the ROC story pages 4791-4800, Florence, Italy. Association Le, and Slav Petrov. 2019. Natural Questions: cloze task. In Proceedings of the 21st Con-for Computational Linguistics. A benchmark for question answering research. Transactions of the Association for Computa-tional Linguistics, 7:453-466. David D. Lewis and William A. Gale. 1994. A sequential algorithm for training text classifiers. In SIGIR, pages 3-12. ACM/Springer. ference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL 2017), pages 15-25, Van-couver, Canada. Association for Computational Linguistics. Minjoon Seo, Aniruddha Kembhavi, Ali Farhadi, and Hannaneh Hajishirzi. 2017. Bidirectional attention flow for machine comprehension. In Sheng Zhang, Xiaodong Liu, Jingjing Liu, Jianfeng Gao, Kevin Duh, and Benjamin Van Durme. 2018. ReCoRD: Bridging the gap between human and machine common-sense reading comprehension. arXiv preprint arXiv:1810.12885.</cell></row><row><cell>Jia Deng, R. Socher, Li Fei-Fei, Wei Dong, Kai Li, How much reading does reading comprehen-dataset for the open-domain machine compre-Zhilin Yang, Saizheng Zhang, Jack Urbanek, Will</cell><cell>Australia. Association for Computational Lin-Caiming Xiong. 2018. Efficient and robust James Thorne, Andreas Vlachos, Oana Cocarascu,</cell></row><row><cell>and Li-Jia Li. 2009. ImageNet: A large-scale sion require? a critical investigation of popular hension of text. In Proceedings of the 2013 Feng, Alexander Miller, Arthur Szlam, Douwe</cell><cell>guistics. question answering from minimal context over Christos Christodoulopoulos, and Arpit Mittal.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_18"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Tamara de Lempicka was a famous artist born in Warsaw.[. . . ]  Better than anyone else she represented the Art Deco style in painting and art[. . . ]    </figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Through what cre-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ations did Lempicka</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>express a kind of art</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>popular after WWI?</cell></row><row><cell>Multi-Hop</cell><cell>Requires more than one step of infer-</cell><cell>[. . . ] and in 1916 married a Polish</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ence, often across multiple sentences.</cell><cell>lawyer Tadeusz Lempicki. Better than</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>anyone else she represented the Art Deco</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>style in painting and art [. . . ]</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. . . ] frequently evoked by particular events in his life and the unfolding Reformation. This behavior started with his learning of the execution of Johann Esch and Heinrich Voes, the first individuals to be martyred by the Roman Catholic Church for Lutheran views [. . . ] Despite the disagreements on the Eucharist, the Marburg Colloquy paved the way for the signing in 1530 of the Augsburg Confession, and for the [. . . ]</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Warsaw lies in east-central Poland about</cell><cell>Is Warsaw closer to the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>300 km (190 mi) from the Carpathian</cell><cell>Baltic Sea or Berlin,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Mountains and about 260 km (160 mi)</cell><cell>Germany?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>from the Baltic Sea, 523 km (325 mi)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>east of Berlin, Germany.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Inductive</cell><cell>A particular case is addressed in the</cell><cell>How did the Roman</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>passage but inferring the answer re-</cell><cell>Catholic Church deal</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>quires generalisation to a broader cat-</cell><cell>with non-believers?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>egory.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Implicit</cell><cell>Builds on information implied in the</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>passage and does not otherwise re-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>quire any of the above types of rea-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>soning.</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>[</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">This threshold is set after initial experiments to not be overly restrictive given acceptable answer spans, e.g., a human answer of "New York" vs. model answer "New York City" would still lead to a model "win".</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Note that the original SQuAD1.1 dataset can be considered a limit case of the adversarial annotation framework, in which the model in the loop always predicts the wrong answer, thus every question is accepted.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors would like to thank Christopher Potts for his detailed and constructive feedback, and our reviewers. This work was supported by the European Union's Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme under grant agreement No. 875160 and the UK Defence Science and Technology Laboratory (Dstl) and Engineering and Physical Research Council (EPSRC) under grant EP/R018693/1 as a part of the collaboration between US DOD, UK MOD, and UK EPSRC under the Multidisciplinary University Research Initiative (MURI).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Samuel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabor</forename><surname>Bowman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Angeli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/D15-1075</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
